<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>Uncategorized on RaidAdvice.com</title>
		<link>www.raidadvice.com/tags/uncategorized/</link>
		<description>Recent content in Uncategorized on RaidAdvice.com</description>
		<generator>Hugo 0.72.0 -- gohugo.io</generator>
		<language>en-us</language>
		<lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Aug 2020 21:15:57 +0000</lastBuildDate>
		<atom:link href="www.raidadvice.com/tags/uncategorized/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		<item>
			<title>2020 Update</title>
			<link>www.raidadvice.com/2020-update/</link>
			<pubDate>Sun, 16 Aug 2020 21:15:57 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">www.raidadvice.com/2020-update/</guid>
			<description>&lt;p&gt;Hello there! Sorry to anyone who was a loyal reader and noticed I abruptly stopped updating the site a few years back. My dad was sick, got much sicker, and then passed away, and during that time period I quit Warcraft and blogging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I still play games now, in August of 2020 that&amp;rsquo;s mostly Fortnite (with some Fall Guys).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Players don&amp;rsquo;t seem too optimistic about Shadowlands. If it&amp;rsquo;s great I might come back to raiding. However, I avoided coming back for BfA raiding, and that now seems like it was a good move. Unless raider feedback about Shadowlands improves, I&amp;rsquo;ll probably stay away for Shadowlands as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I spent a day moving the site from Wordpress on Digital Ocean to a static site (I chose Hugo, but there are &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.staticgen.com/&#34;&gt;tons of options&lt;/a&gt;), which is why things look different now. The site is now hosted on &lt;a href=&#34;https://pages.github.com/&#34;&gt;Github Pages&lt;/a&gt;. I am glad to reduce my costs from $130/year to $10/year for a site I haven&amp;rsquo;t been updating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I haven&amp;rsquo;t gone through the effort of enabling comments, which is a bit tricky with static sites. If you want to say hi, or want to comment on this or another post, send me a twitter DM at &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/RaphanW&#34;&gt;RaphanW&lt;/a&gt; or an e-mail (address available in the &lt;a href=&#34;www.raidadvice.com/about/&#34;&gt;About Page&lt;/a&gt;). If you want it to be a public comment, just send me a link to the post you want me to add it to.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Mythic Antorus: Tips for Ranged DPS Part One</title>
			<link>www.raidadvice.com/mythic-antorus-tips-for-ranged-dps-part-one/</link>
			<pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 07:55:06 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">www.raidadvice.com/mythic-antorus-tips-for-ranged-dps-part-one/</guid>
			<description>&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;about-what-is-this&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About: What is this?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I am writing just a few sentences outlining the things I thought were most important to focus on as a ranged DPS.&lt;/strong&gt; My guild downed the first 6 bosses in week one of mythic, with me playing Balance Druid. We have also had some good progression on the 7th. This guide comes from that experience. This guide assumes you have completed the bosses in heroic and will not cover heroic mechanics. This guide will not mention abilities that are the primary responsibility of tanks, healers, or melee classes. The dungeon journal is a great resource if you want to read about what every single mechanic does.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;garothi-worldbreaker&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Garothi Worldbreaker&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This fight is &lt;strong&gt;barely different from Heroic&lt;/strong&gt;. Follow your guild’s strategy for moving out with Decimation. We had the range stack and all move together once it was empowered, which seemed to work fine. On progression, don’t be afraid to use DPS-loss defensive abilities when soaking Annihilation, especially in the empowered phase. There is no meaningful DPS check on the boss. My warcraftlogs percentage parse was around 30 on our first (one-shot) kill and around 95 on our second kill. I didn’t get better at DPS a week later, I just realized the boss was super easy for our guild, and I stopped going overboard with bear form and frenzied regeneration. Do I regret that? Not at all, we one-shot the boss and DPS parses are for one-shot farm content only.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;felhounds-of-sargeras&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Felhounds of Sargeras&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unlike Heroic, tanks may have to keep the bosses farther away from each other, and you will stack near the boss based on the debuff you get, rather than standing in the middle. As such, &lt;strong&gt;bring a mostly-single-target build&lt;/strong&gt; for progression. This is another fight will little relevant DPS check; &lt;strong&gt;focus on movement&lt;/strong&gt;. Move with your group at orange to avoid placing puddles all over the room, then spread out to avoid cleaving each other with Erupting Flames. The nasty bit is when mechanics overlap, where you need to all be stacked but then spread immediately. None of the mechanics are that hard, just pay attention to when they are coming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;antoran-high-command&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Antoran High Command&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“&lt;strong&gt;Watch your feet&lt;/strong&gt;,” and don’t trigger mines when the party has a few stacks of the debuff already. Make sure to focus down the bats so they don’t eject raiders from the pods. &lt;strong&gt;Sustained AOE is very important here&lt;/strong&gt;; it was the fight so far that I felt balance druid was the most uniquely valuable for. The adds on the ground are high priority, especially second phase when the pod is no longer debuffing them. Make sure you are in the Fel-Shield Emitter second phase to avoid taking excess damage, but move out as soon as the burst damage is over to avoid stacking whirlwinds from the adds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;portal-keeper-hasabel&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Portal Keeper Hasabel&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interrupts and creature control spells are very important for the imps&lt;/strong&gt;, especially when half the party goes up into the portals to down the minibosses. Make sure to save resources for burst AOE damage on the ads if you are not in the portal groups. We went from wiping to killing the boss when everyone started focusing more on these two things. Balance Druids and Elemental Shaman should almost surely stay on the platform, as their AOE damage is strong and their single target burst is weak. DPS matters a bit here, as her damage starts to ramp up near the end of the fight in a very-soft-enrage type mechanic. Focus on a build that has good single target but can also cleave off the boss onto the imps when they spawn. Last but not least, watch your feet. Dying to Felstorm Barrage is easy to avoid so long as you don’t let your mind wander. Move immediately if the green line spawns under you - the blast comes quicker than you think.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;eonar-the-life-binder&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Eonar the Life Binder&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The portal group is new and interesting. Make sure everyone knows what is going on to avoid unnecessary wipes: Four groups of four people (1 healer and 3 dps) will be assigned to go up into the ship. &lt;strong&gt;Make sure everyone in the group gets to the portal before it spawns and hop in immediately&lt;/strong&gt;. It spawns near Eonar’s pool. Have an interrupt rotation, and make sure everyone is assigned to a debuff and clicks it up in the Paraxis before the timer runs out. This rest of this boss comes down more to guild strategy than what you can do as an individual. We split up into two groups and chased the spawn points, with a few DPS and a healer assigned to chase down the bats. Near the end, tons of mobs will spawn; focus groups one-by-one, as once you kill enough mobs you win. You won’t kill all the mobs on the map. As Balance druid I went full AOE build here. Most ranged will likely want to do that as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;imonar-the-soul-hunter&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Imonar the Soul Hunter&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This fight is purely single target, of course. We used lust on the third platform, which seems to be an uncommon strategy. More common is lust on the first platform. I’d like to have tried using it on the first platform, as figuring out Balance Druid cooldown usage with third-platform lust continues to be a struggle for me. A lot of the tricky part of this fight is tanks/healers figuring out how to clear the path during the four platform transitions. We cleared one half of the platform every time, which seemed to work well. DPS without the Empowered Pulse Grenade debuff need to cluster around 10 yards behind the tank. The DPS with Pulse Grenade and at least one healer need to follow behind, spread out single-file. If you do NOT have Pulse Grenade, make sure to keep moving once you cross the bridge. It is YOUR fault, not the fault of the dps behind you, if they hit you with pulse grenade, if you stop moving once you are off the bridge. The first, third, and fifth platforms are a lot like heroic. The &lt;strong&gt;second platform&lt;/strong&gt;, everyone without pulse grenade should stack. Move out near the ship targeting you with Charged Blast. &lt;strong&gt;DO NOT BE LAZY AND HAVE THE BEAM CUT ACROSS THE PLATFORM “BARELY MISSING” PEOPLE, MOVE OUT TOWARDS THE SHIP&lt;/strong&gt;. Someone will move at the last second and you will hit them. Everyone else should move as a group once Shrapnel Blast goes off, leaving a small line of bombs that your raid will never need to explode. The fourth platform, range should be loose, similar to the first platform, except keep the front and back of the platform where the ships spawn clear. Like in the second phase, move to the ships with Charged Blast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;kingaroth&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kin’garoth&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This fight is all about burst single-target DPS on the adds during intermissions&lt;/strong&gt;. Spec for single target and go to town on the add you are assigned to. Other than that, the mechanics for ranged DPS aren’t that complicated and are similar to the trash adds before the boss. The rolling bombs move clockwise; &lt;strong&gt;keep your camera facing right&lt;/strong&gt; to make sure you avoid them. In the later intermissions of the fight, make extra sure you are not standing in the green swirls, as the damage they do ramps up over the course of the fight. This, combined with tanks needing to explode the rolling bombs, can easily kill you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s all for now. I plan to come back with Part Two once we are further along in progression. Best of luck until then!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Halfway Through Antorus</title>
			<link>www.raidadvice.com/halfway-through-antorus/</link>
			<pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2017 04:13:27 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">www.raidadvice.com/halfway-through-antorus/</guid>
			<description>&lt;p&gt;Hey there. I&amp;rsquo;m still around, moderating &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/competitivewow&#34;&gt;/r/competitivewow&lt;/a&gt; and playing in my guild &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wowprogress.com/guild/us/stormrage/Storm&#34;&gt;Storm&lt;/a&gt;. I just haven&amp;rsquo;t had anything I felt compelled to blog about. Blizzcon was great. There was a fun panel with Day9 and several Warcraft content creators about how to effectively be a content creator, and a top suggestion was having a consistent release schedule. I&amp;rsquo;ve thought about getting into something like that on the blog. Maybe consistently releasing something on Tuesdays. We&amp;rsquo;ll see. I day-raided day one of a mythic release for the first time ever, and in the first week my (normally raiding only 7 hours per week) guild cleared half the bosses in the raid on mythic. That was exciting, but it leaves me wondering what we are going to be doing for the next X months until Battle for Azeroth is released. Method already has cleared the full raid, and on social media indicated that the first 9 bosses are of similar difficulty. The seven I have seen so far does little to dispel that notion. I like this raid&amp;rsquo;s design a bunch more than Tomb of Sargeras, but I don&amp;rsquo;t like how quickly we are looking to get through it. How has Antorus been going for you so far?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Blizzcon 2017</title>
			<link>www.raidadvice.com/blizzcon-2017/</link>
			<pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2017 01:42:10 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">www.raidadvice.com/blizzcon-2017/</guid>
			<description>&lt;p&gt;I am heading to Blizzcon 2017! This will be my first Blizzcon- the first time I will visit Los Angeles/Anaheim as well. Aside from &amp;ldquo;go to Disneyland!&amp;rdquo; any tips for the visit? If you read this blog because we are online friends and you are going, be sure to reach out so we can say hi there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;comments&#34;&gt;Comments:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://coffeecakesandcrits.wordpress.com/&#34; title=&#34;wrathofkublakhan@yahoo.com&#34;&gt;wrathsome&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Oct 4, 2017&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What fun! When it comes to Los Angeles, it is all about time and money. In general, I&amp;rsquo;d suggest that you simply enjoy Blizzcon; that should be the most fun for you. And, yeah, Disneyland is right there and is one of my favorite spots in the world. Should you have the &amp;ldquo;time and money&amp;rdquo; to go up to LA and see Griffith Park or visit the beach in Santa Monica; those would be memories that you&amp;rsquo;d have for life. Even driving (I hate to say, the traffic is notorious) through Los Angeles makes an impression because it IS so crowded and at a hair-raising 80 miles-an-hour, you will see iconic sights that you will recognize from many movies and television shows. Maybe spend a day at Universal? Really, anything can be fun with friends, even visiting a Wax Museum or seeing the stars on the sidewalk on Hollywood Blvd.
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;heading-1&#34;&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://coffeecakesandcrits.wordpress.com/&#34; title=&#34;wrathofkublakhan@yahoo.com&#34;&gt;wrathsome&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Dec 1, 2017&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well? Was it fun?
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;heading-2&#34;&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;%22raphanwow@gmail.com%22&#34;&gt;Raphael&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Dec 3, 2017&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a blast! Meeting people who I had only met online was the best part.
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;heading-3&#34;&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://coffeecakesandcrits.wordpress.com/&#34; title=&#34;wrathofkublakhan@yahoo.com&#34;&gt;wrathsome&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Dec 2, 2017&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;awesomesauce!
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Mythic Kil&#39;Jaeden Takeaways after 100 Pulls</title>
			<link>www.raidadvice.com/mythic-kiljaeden-takeaways-after-100-pulls/</link>
			<pubDate>Fri, 13 Oct 2017 03:40:35 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">www.raidadvice.com/mythic-kiljaeden-takeaways-after-100-pulls/</guid>
			<description>&lt;p&gt;A few nights into progression on the last boss in Tomb of Sargeras, here are my thoughts. If you are progressing on it or about to start, these are the things I wish we had all been clearer on beforehand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;red-orbs&#34;&gt;Red Orbs:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Change viewing settings to low particle density to dodge red orbs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dodge red orbs, seriously; dps to boss during that time is not super important compared to making sure you don&amp;rsquo;t die.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stutterstep the red orbs so you don&amp;rsquo;t die when placing them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;purple-orbs&#34;&gt;Purple Orbs:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you die to being knocked off by purple orb, it&amp;rsquo;s usually your fault. Don&amp;rsquo;t soak Armageddon far from center if you don&amp;rsquo;t have blink/similar to avoid dying if the purple orb is in an &amp;ldquo;unlucky&amp;rdquo; place.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you aren&amp;rsquo;t sure where to stand, stand on the shot caller (a tank in our raid) when purple orbs incoming. Either they did it right, or lots of people got knocked off and it&amp;rsquo;s a disaster anyways.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;dps&#34;&gt;DPS:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t be lazy, switch to priority targets especially the tank ad. It&amp;rsquo;s easy to see if you are scumbagging this on logs&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Mythic Maiden of Vigilance Phase One Quick Thoughts</title>
			<link>www.raidadvice.com/mythic-maiden-of-vigilance-phase-one-quick-thoughts/</link>
			<pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2017 16:28:37 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">www.raidadvice.com/mythic-maiden-of-vigilance-phase-one-quick-thoughts/</guid>
			<description>&lt;p&gt;Hey all. I&amp;rsquo;m still around, I&amp;rsquo;ve just been quite busy this summer and posting/making updates has been on the back-burner. I&amp;rsquo;ve gotten your comments &amp;amp; e-mails: I will try to get to updating the class guides &amp;amp; mythic+ pages, but no promises! As my guild works on Maiden of Vigilance, I have some quick thoughts on phase one of the boss that I explained in an imgur image. Maybe it will be of some use to you: &lt;a href=&#34;https://imgur.com/hNUitpv&#34;&gt;https://imgur.com/hNUitpv&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Boss is the Red X. Tanks below the X with backs to hole. Default positions during phase one should be with your group near the &amp;ldquo;1.&amp;rdquo; Try to drop the circles near &amp;ldquo;1&amp;rdquo; and move towards &amp;ldquo;2&amp;rdquo; so the other color can soak your circles without colliding with you. Reset to &amp;ldquo;1&amp;rdquo; once circles are soaked. Ranged stay mostly behind blue line melee stay mostly in front. Ranged and Melee avoid colliding, especially when dropping bombs in center hole. Ranged make sure to give melee enough room, stay behind the blue line!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If your guild puts Fel right and Light left then flip things as appropriate, obviously. The video I reference is &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZIsDI3I_a9k&#34;&gt;this one&lt;/a&gt; in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/maiden-of-vigilance-tomb-of-sargeras-raid-strategy-guide&#34;&gt;Wowhead Guide&lt;/a&gt;. I hope you all are enjoying 7.3 and making good progress in Tomb of Sargeras!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Preparing for Tomb of Sargeras</title>
			<link>www.raidadvice.com/preparing-for-tomb-of-sargeras/</link>
			<pubDate>Tue, 20 Jun 2017 03:22:56 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">www.raidadvice.com/preparing-for-tomb-of-sargeras/</guid>
			<description>&lt;p&gt;For learning the fights in Tomb of Sargeras, start with the in-game dungeon journal. Then head to some out-of-game Tomb of Sargeras specific resources. Here are some of the ones I used, in rough order from least to most-detailed:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mmo-champion.com/content/6517-World-of-Warcraft-Tomb-of-Sargeras-Minimalist-Raid-Guide&#34;&gt;MMo-Champion Minimalist Guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLvcq2yEgGseZPkpsamTqgJ2R3lQKP7yGN&#34;&gt;1-2 Minute Youtube Overviews&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1I2QbAowMgD2SEAvR9eMT5cMY9JyHZ7ehuViMjct1f5I/edit?usp=sharing&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Hardcoded Asian Guide&amp;rdquo; - Google Doc&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.icy-veins.com/wow/tomb-of-sargeras-raid&#34;&gt;Icy-Veins Written Guides&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://phoguild.enjin.com/forum/viewforum/8375219/m/39307077&#34;&gt;PhoGuild - Written Forum Post Strategies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Detailed video guides will likely become available in the next week. Several folks made some handy weakauras for Tomb, such as &lt;a href=&#34;https://wago.io/Vyfk0e9-X&#34;&gt;these&lt;/a&gt;. I also did personal preparation like &lt;a href=&#34;http://raidadvice.com/preparing-for-the-emerald-nightmare/&#34;&gt;I did for Emerald Nightmare&lt;/a&gt;. Check out that article for general preparation tips applicable to all tiers. Good luck with the raid!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Raid for Legendaries</title>
			<link>www.raidadvice.com/raid-for-legendaries/</link>
			<pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2017 03:41:37 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">www.raidadvice.com/raid-for-legendaries/</guid>
			<description>&lt;p&gt;If you don&amp;rsquo;t have all the legendaries for your main spec and want to do something about it, this post is for you. &lt;a href=&#34;http://eu.battle.net/forums/en/wow/topic/17614472761?page=2#27&#34;&gt;Bad luck protection&lt;/a&gt; exists: the more chances you have to get a legendary, the better chance you will have of getting one. Killing a raid boss is one of the highest chances as getting a legendary. You can get legendaries on a fairly consistent basis now (1-2 weeks) if you put the work in. Kill every Legion raid boss you can, on all difficulties you can, every week, with your preferred spec as your loot spec. You will bump up your bad luck protection and have dozens of chances each week to get a new orange item. With Tomb of Sargeras a few weeks out, if you start now you can likely grab another few legendaries if you clear the raids. I was stuck at six legendaries, and over six weeks, clearing normal, heroic, and mythic of Emerald Nightmare, Trial of Valor, and Normal and Heroic Nighthold, I got to ten. Several friends have had similar success and recommended this method to me. If you want legendaries, this is the best way I know how to get them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;comments&#34;&gt;Comments:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://coffeecakesandcrits.wordpress.com/&#34; title=&#34;wrathofkublakhan@yahoo.com&#34;&gt;wrathsome&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;May 3, 2017&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick question: were you farming Legendary pieces or AP?
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;heading-1&#34;&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;%22raphanwow@gmail.com%22&#34;&gt;Raphael&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Jun 4, 2017&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Artifact Power was a nice added benefit, but the main reason I was doing the raids was for legendaries. I wanted to be sure to go into Tomb with all the ones available for Balance. Nighthold is worth doing for AP if you are trying to maximize AP. AP drops are not guaranteed from Trial of Valor and Emerald Nightmare, so the primary value there is fishing for legendaries.
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Raid Management: The Magic Number</title>
			<link>www.raidadvice.com/raid-management-the-magic-number/</link>
			<pubDate>Mon, 08 May 2017 05:22:51 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">www.raidadvice.com/raid-management-the-magic-number/</guid>
			<description>&lt;p&gt;Managing the roster of raiders is one of the most difficult parts of running a mythic raiding guild in World of Warcraft. As long as a guild has enough happy raiders showing up to raid every week, the guild will live on and the group will, in all likelihood, defeat more and more bosses. If a raiding guild fails to sustain its roster, it will fade out of existence. This happens enough in Warcraft that it is colloquially referred to as a guild dying to &amp;ldquo;the roster boss.&amp;rdquo; There have been many posts written about &lt;a href=&#34;http://raidadvice.com/how-to-find-a-new-guild-a-guide-and-case-study/&#34;&gt;how to find a guild&lt;/a&gt; or recruit. But how many raiders should the guild shoot for?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-problem-why-numbers-matter&#34;&gt;The Problem: Why Numbers Matter&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Warcraft currently, a group must bring exactly 20 raiders to the highest raiding difficulty, Mythic. For lower difficulty levels, a group can bring 10-30 raiders, and the encounter will adjust to match the size of the group. For those difficulties, a raiding roster of anywhere between 15-35 (or even lower/higher) can reliably raid every night it plans to without benching many (or any) raiders. For Mythic, a roster of fewer than 20 will likely cause the guild to fail, as few prefer to raid in a group that is gimping itself by not bringing 20 guild raiders to the encounters. A roster of too much more than 20 will also not work well for the guild, as players bored of being benched too much will leave. So, the key question is how many more than 20 is &amp;ldquo;too much more?&amp;rdquo; What&amp;rsquo;s the right number for most raid teams?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;advantages-of-small-and-large-rosters&#34;&gt;Advantages of Small and Large Rosters&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Smaller rosters give a raiding group more consistency and allow the group as a whole to learn quicker. Fewer bench slots means more play time for everyone, giving everyone more experience on each boss. Small groups require fewer player swaps, so group composition is similar from night to night, requiring fewer strategy changes due to class/player composition changes. Smaller rosters also allow raid gear to be split among fewer players, minimizing the gear that is &amp;ldquo;wasted&amp;rdquo; on progression because it is equipped by a player benched for a progression fight. Larger rosters give a raiding group more durability and flexibility. A guild with 24 members can weather the storm of 3 people absent on the same night, while a guild of 22 might have to take a night off. Additionally, large rosters tolerate players leaving/quitting the game better - a roster of 24 can carry on for a week or two if 2 players leave, while looking to recruit 2 replacements. A roster of 22 is suddenly in a very shaky position if 1 person leaves for another guild and 1 person quits the game. Also, larger roster sizes give a bit more flexibility in raid composition. If an encounter is easier with more of a specific class, or more ranged, or more melee, a larger guild is more likely to be able to shift its composition to take advantage of the encounter&amp;rsquo;s weakness. Ultimately, I think most mythic guilds want as small a roster as possible to guarantee that they survive and have enough raiders on almost all raid nights. The advantages of a smaller roster are significant, and there are little disadvantages outside of &amp;ldquo;maybe having to skip raid due to absences.&amp;rdquo; Large rosters are an administrative headache, and can cause players to look for other guilds if they are spending too much raid time on the bench. Outside of world top 50 raiding, a guild essentially wants more than 20 players only to allow it to raid if people are absent and ensure long-term sustainability&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;a-mathematics-based-approach&#34;&gt;A Mathematics Based Approach&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So then, exactly how many players do we need? That number depends on your tolerance for risk (let&amp;rsquo;s quantify that as &amp;ldquo;how sure do we want to be that we have 20 to raid each night?&amp;quot;) and how high attendance you demand of your raiders. I take raiding Mythic fairly seriously, as I imagine most people raiding Mythic do. If you wanted to just spend time with friends, and not be bothered if a certain number of players fail to show up, heroic is much easier and much less administrative headache than mythic. I therefore suggest that you want to have more than &lt;strong&gt;20 players show up at least 95% of the time&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;and ideally higher&lt;/strong&gt; unless the guild has planned not to raid due to a holiday. If you can&amp;rsquo;t raid due to not enough people showing up on a non-holiday, you want it to be an extreme fluke, the kind of thing that happens once a  year. As an officer of several guilds, I also suggest that an &lt;strong&gt;average attendance of 95% is realistic&lt;/strong&gt; for mythic raiding guilds. Some players will never ever miss raid, and they will be balanced by players who miss about a night a month, which is close to 90% attendance for 2 or 3 night raid teams. I think an average 95% is reasonable, as I would be hesitant to kick an otherwise excellent raider if they missed one week every two months. Much more than that, and I would talk to them about their attendance and see if it was going to be improved going forwards. I created &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/12DvYkwJkGiMm7v_mGaKiRjbHADD7WbdbH7XifAjk9b8/&#34;&gt;this spreadsheet&lt;/a&gt; for you to estimate how often your guild will have 20+ people to raid, given two variables: the size of the raid roster and the average attendance of the raiders. Feel free to play around with it. Some takeaways:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Raid Roster Size&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Average Attendance&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;20+ Raiders how Often?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;23&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;95%&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;97.4%&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;24&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;95%&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;99.4%&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;25&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;90%&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;96.6%&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With 95% attendance, 24 raiders will allow the guild to raid over 99% of the time. 24 seems like an ideal number then, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;reality-trumps-math&#34;&gt;Reality Trumps Math&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are three kinds of lies: lies, damned lies and statistics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on the above math, 24 seems like the right number to shoot for. In practice, I think that will be a little low. There are a few factors that suggest one or two more players is prudent. First, there is attrition. Guilds that I have been a part of, even excellent ones that mostly lost players to quitting the game and almost never to other guilds, lost 1-2 players a month. Also, recruitment is easier between tiers than during a progression push, especially if a guild temporarily &amp;ldquo;falls behind&amp;rdquo; its progression target. Given this, the guild needs space on the roster for recruits and should have enough players that _after _the guild loses a member the raid roster is still in a good spot. Second, I don&amp;rsquo;t think having 20 people online to raid is the right number to shoot for. Having 22 online for raid is about ideal. This allows the raid to shift its composition slightly as required (more or fewer healers, for instance). Having an extra member or two online also allows for someone to swap in if someone is having a bad night, whether due to real life factors affecting their play or internet connection issues. To get 22 consistently with a 95% attendance rate, you need one or two more than 24 raiders. Thus, I think a raid roster size of 25-26, including all trials, is the sweet spot. This will minimize players&amp;rsquo; time on the bench while maximizing the guild&amp;rsquo;s stability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, any guild size 20 and above can work. I have been a part of very successful mythic raiding teams with 21-22 on the roster (including my current guild, &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;. By the way, thanks to the GM of Trap Run for giving me his blessing to publish this article and for discussing it with me). I cleared Mythic Archimonde in &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; in Tier 18 at around US 167, and helped manage a roster of around 30. 22 raiders feels a bit low and &amp;ldquo;dangerous;&amp;rdquo; one raider disconnecting can force the guild to stop raiding if a few others are absent. 30 raiders allowed for a weekend guild with a rather low average attendance rate and was a logistical feat to accommodate fairly; most guilds would do well to have a smaller roster size and find players who can hit higher attendance numbers. The guilds I have been in with around 25-26 raiding members felt like they were both nimble and stable, minimizing players&amp;rsquo; time on the bench while maximizing the guild&amp;rsquo;s durability. How much attendance can you demand from your raiders? How much do you value short-term consistency versus long-term stability? What is your magic number?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>To Consume or Not, That Is the Question</title>
			<link>www.raidadvice.com/to-consume-or-not-that-is-the-question/</link>
			<pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2017 06:50:39 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">www.raidadvice.com/to-consume-or-not-that-is-the-question/</guid>
			<description>&lt;p&gt;I have been enjoying my &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/item=147707/repurposed-fel-focuser&#34;&gt;Repurposed Fel Focuser&lt;/a&gt;, a reusable item that costs 7500 &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/currency=1226/nethershard&#34;&gt;Nethershards&lt;/a&gt; and provides a buff equal to a bit less than half a flask. I was running several easy Mythic+ with guild-members the other day, and one asked why I wasn&amp;rsquo;t using better consumables. I could have been using the full flask (and using &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/item=142117/potion-of-prolonged-power&#34;&gt;Potions of Prolonged Power&lt;/a&gt; on cooldown). I have over one million gold, so I could afford the 500 per hour for flask or 1000 gold per hour for potions of prolonged power - but why spend 1500 per hour when we are consistently 3-chesting the Mythic+ dungeons without me doing so? The idea is that it makes the dungeons go faster, and as a DPS, your job is to make the dungeons go faster. For any difficult or progression content, I always use the best consumables I can get my hands on. For easy farm, the &amp;ldquo;why&amp;rdquo; eluded me a bit. The more I thought about it, the more I thought my guild-member might be right, though. At current wowtoken prices, the consumables would have cost an additional 25 cents per hour, and are at least partially offset by disenchanting the gear from the runs. Even if using better consumables shaves off a minute of time per hour, it&amp;rsquo;s probably worth doing. Saving such little gold is a false economy if it makes the dungeons even slightly slower, especially with the prices being what they are relative to my gold and the price of a wowtoken. If the potions were 20,000g per hour that might be a closer call. But as is, why not use them, even on easy content? My Fel Focuser is probably best used for world quests only, or even not at all in favor of more potent flasks. When prices are low, consume away!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Feasts Are Back in Patch 7.2</title>
			<link>www.raidadvice.com/feasts-are-back-in-patch-7.2/</link>
			<pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2017 21:52:10 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">www.raidadvice.com/feasts-are-back-in-patch-7.2/</guid>
			<description>&lt;p&gt;Per the &lt;a href=&#34;https://worldofwarcraft.com/en-us/news/20629899/world-of-warcraft-7-2-the-tomb-of-sargeras-patch-notes&#34;&gt;7.2 patch notes&lt;/a&gt;, the best Legion feast (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/item=133579/lavish-suramar-feast&#34;&gt;Lavish Suramar Feast&lt;/a&gt;) grants 500 main stat (up from 200) in 7.2. This means that for most classes, feasts will be better than all other food options. Even the lesser feast (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/item=133578/hearty-feast&#34;&gt;Hearty Feast&lt;/a&gt;) will grant 400 main stat. If you cook your own food and don&amp;rsquo;t have rank 3 of the feasts, you might want to &lt;a href=&#34;http://raidadvice.com/how-to-target-specific-recipes-from-nomi/&#34;&gt;head back to Nomi&lt;/a&gt; with some materials. Make sure your raid group is ready to feast on some feasts!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>What Boss Order Should We Follow in Nighthold After Mythic Trilliax?</title>
			<link>www.raidadvice.com/what-boss-order-should-we-follow-in-nighthold-after-mythic-trilliax/</link>
			<pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2017 04:18:37 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">www.raidadvice.com/what-boss-order-should-we-follow-in-nighthold-after-mythic-trilliax/</guid>
			<description>&lt;p&gt;Now that my guild has cleared seven bosses in Mythic Nighthold, I have some perspective on what boss order you might want to pursue. What boss should you target now if you are just getting to 3/10 Mythic bosses down (with patch 7.2 right around the corner)? The options for what boss to do fourth are Spellblade Aluriel, High Botanist Tel&amp;rsquo;arn, Krosus, and Tichondrius. From easiest to hardest, I suggest Spellblade &amp;lt; Krosus = Botanist &amp;lt; Tichondrius. Why? &lt;strong&gt;Spellblade&lt;/strong&gt; was &lt;a href=&#34;https://worldofwarcraft.com/en-us/news/20478238/hotfixes-march-21&#34;&gt;heavily nerfed&lt;/a&gt; just this past week. The boss is now definitely the easiest path forward. Follow this &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IEy1JBsh5-Y&#34;&gt;video guide&lt;/a&gt; by Kelani or something similar. Our raid killed Spellblade 7th, and with the nerf, Spellblade is now &lt;em&gt;significantly&lt;/em&gt; easier than the other three options. &lt;strong&gt;Krosus&lt;/strong&gt; has a DPS check that remains tight. However, the mechanics are fairly straightforward (&lt;a href=&#34;http://raidadvice.com/krosus-guide-how-to-soak-burning-pitch/&#34;&gt;check out the RaidAdvice guide&lt;/a&gt;), and if you lack the DPS check on Krosus, you are going to have a hard time on Tichondrius. There&amp;rsquo;s an argument for doing Botanist if your guild is missing the Krosus DPS check, but overall I think Krosus is a bit easier. It also rewards Tier gear. &lt;strong&gt;Botanist&lt;/strong&gt; is mechanically demanding and can be a frustrating fight. The hard part is getting down phase three, which comes after 6-8 fairly easy minutes of phase one and phase two. DPS is not a big issues on Botanist, and you may want to call for raiders to stop or slow DPS at certain points to ensure a smooth transition between the phases. &lt;strong&gt;Miniguide on Botanist&lt;/strong&gt;: We did the  Naturalist &amp;gt; Arcanist &amp;gt; Solarist kill order. In phase three, we soaked the first set of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/spell=218809/call-of-night&#34;&gt;Call of Night&lt;/a&gt; debuffs, then had the 2nd and 3rd set suicide by running into &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/spell=219235/toxic-spores&#34;&gt;Toxic Spores&lt;/a&gt; as soon as they got the debuff. Every ranged should be prepared to run alongside someone who gets the 2nd or 3rd debuff set to minimize ticking damage on the raid while they suicide, and healers should save big cooldowns in case ticking damage gets through. It&amp;rsquo;s key to avoid deaths to silly mistakes in phase one and phase two so you can resurrect key players who suicide in phase three. &lt;strong&gt;Tichondrius&lt;/strong&gt; is now the hardest of the bunch, in my opinion. It&amp;rsquo;s close, and you could argue for doing Tichondrius after Spellblade. But while Krosus has a hard DPS check and Botanist requires mechanical precision, Tichondrius demands a bit of both from your raid. Blizzard did a great job with this balance of these bosses! Until the Spellblade nerfs, any of these four bosses was a viable fourth option. Giving meaningful choice to the raid in terms of boss order is cool. It allows guilds to pick a boss that might be more suited to their strengths (for example, Botanist for mechanically-oriented guilds or Krosus for guilds with top-notch DPS). Our raid killed Krosus &amp;gt; Tichondrius &amp;gt; Botanist &amp;gt; Spellblade. Since we knew we had the DPS check for Krosus, having killed it fourth like many other guilds did, we decided to do Tichondrius over Botanist since the mechanics on Botanist are a bit trickier. Ultimately, I think that Tichondrius ended up being harder to kill. It was a close decision on whether to do Botanist or Spellblade next (before the Spellblade nerf). Usually you can &lt;a href=&#34;http://raidadvice.com/use-wowprogress-to-pick-your-battles/&#34;&gt;follow wowprogress kill totals&lt;/a&gt; and just do the boss most people have killed and do fine. The kill counts right now line up with my recommended order, except that Spellblade still has fewer than Krosus, probably because the Spellblade nerf was so recent. Check out &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/CompetitiveWoW/comments/60bytv/spell_blade_or_tich/&#34;&gt;this reddit thread&lt;/a&gt; that discusses this topic. _The &amp;ldquo;correct&amp;rdquo; order might change based on subsequent patches - this is the order I recommend right at this moment. _&lt;em&gt;I intentionally do not address the question of &amp;ldquo;Are there issues in my guild if we are just now getting to 3/10M, and what do we do about them?&amp;rdquo; I am only addressing boss order in this post.&lt;/em&gt; Good luck with your progression!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;comments&#34;&gt;Comments:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://zisforzeirah.wordpress.com&#34; title=&#34;zeirah123@gmail.com&#34;&gt;Zeirah&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Apr 3, 2017&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your order is really interesting and shows that each group definitely can tackle the raid in varying ways. Our mythic progression after Trill was Bot - Krosus - Spell and Tich. And tbh I found Tich the most straightforward/easier of them all especially if you hold the brands rather than pop them. It makes one mechanic almost neglible to deal with.
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Mythic Plus Keystones Next Week in 7.2</title>
			<link>www.raidadvice.com/mythic-plus-keystones-next-week-in-7.2/</link>
			<pubDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2017 19:19:28 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">www.raidadvice.com/mythic-plus-keystones-next-week-in-7.2/</guid>
			<description>&lt;p&gt;Patch 7.2 is coming this week (worry not, the new raid is still months out). If you routinely do a 15 keystone each week, you may want to do an 18 this week. Why? Starting with 7.2, each level will get more difficult, and a 10+ generates the maximum reward (of a 905 in your weekly cache). More significantly to this post, for this week only, if you do an 18 you will get a 10 in your bags next week. See this blue post for more information: &lt;a href=&#34;https://us.battle.net/forums/en/wow/topic/20753795211#1&#34;&gt;https://us.battle.net/forums/en/wow/topic/20753795211#1&lt;/a&gt;. Key you get next week based on highest key completed this week:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mythic 2-8: level 2 Keystone Mythic 9-10: level 3 Mythic 11: level 4 Mythic 12: level 5 Mythic 13-14: level 6 Mythic 15: level 7 (each difficulty level above 15 increases next week’s Keystone level by 1)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or, if you want to run lots of mythic plus next week for AP, consider doing only a level 10 this week, as that will generate the (maximum) 905 gear reward next week and you will start with a 3-level key you can run many times:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To put it more directly: completing a Keystone dungeon of difficulty 10 or higher this week will result in a reward with a minimum item level of 905 in your next weekly chest, which is the current maximum reward in Patch 7.2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A tidbit for next week: Do the intro quest in the Broken Isles first thing, it leads to getting Artifact Knowledge 26 instantly, which increases AP gains by something like 400% over level 25. Only after doing that should you open your weekly cache (which rewards Artifact Power now) (EDIT 2017-3-27: &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/WarcraftDevs/status/846418523337371648&#34;&gt;the weekly cache will not reward AP the first week of 7.2&lt;/a&gt;), do world quests, dungeons, etc. Do you know of any more things like this to do this weekend to be prepared for 7.2?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;comments&#34;&gt;Comments:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;%22raphanwow@gmail.com%22&#34;&gt;Raphael&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Mar 6, 2017&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MadSeason has a great video about what to do on day one of the patch: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kGrDdKAqugg&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kGrDdKAqugg&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Mastery for Restoration Druid Raids in 7.1.5</title>
			<link>www.raidadvice.com/mastery-for-restoration-druid-raids-in-7.1.5/</link>
			<pubDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2017 03:52:24 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">www.raidadvice.com/mastery-for-restoration-druid-raids-in-7.1.5/</guid>
			<description>&lt;p&gt;Maybe &lt;a href=&#34;https://coffeecakesandcrits.wordpress.com/2017/02/14/the-druid-detective/&#34;&gt;gearing for mastery in raids&lt;/a&gt; is not so crazy for Restoration Druids for challenging progression content. In progression, players are often at low health. With the Cultivation talent, a Rejuvenation on a party member at low health is already 2 out of 3 of the HOTs for Restoration Druid mastery. Add in a Wild Growth, Spring Blossoms, Cenarion Ward, or Lifebloom, and you are getting full mastery benefit. A few Restoration druids I have talked to are using a Mastery heavy build on at least some fights. I don&amp;rsquo;t have all the answers here, but it is something at least worth thinking about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;comments&#34;&gt;Comments:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;%22dendronwayo@gmail.com%22&#34;&gt;Dedrophile of Sen&amp;rsquo;Jin&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Mar 4, 2017&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If your raid has healers who coordinate, mastery is the way to go, it gives you a boost where you need it most, low health players or tanks. If you are &amp;ldquo;competing&amp;rdquo; for healing on meters, haste becomes much more meaningful on charts, but doesn&amp;rsquo;t necessarily mean your performance was better, especially on long fights where stacking haste can easily lead to mana issues. If you are just spread healing with no real coordination, crit becomes the best way to get a boost off your HoT spam. It really depends on your team and your healing style. I believe that healing charts don&amp;rsquo;t matter if your raid survives and the boss dies. I personally use Cultivation for every progression fight, sure I may be a bit lower on charts on the &amp;ldquo;farm&amp;rdquo; bosses, but when the raid is low health, a mastery build really shines. Another benefit of a mastery focus build is that it carries over well for keystone runs.
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;heading-1&#34;&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://coffeecakesandcrits.wordpress.com/&#34; title=&#34;wrathofkublakhan@yahoo.com&#34;&gt;wrathsome&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Mar 5, 2017&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Super interesting. In a sense, there are three viable ways to go and; one could argue, that you can&amp;rsquo;t do it &amp;ldquo;wrong&amp;rdquo;. That part is very reassuring. I&amp;rsquo;ve been going Haste with a lot of hold-over in playstyle from past expansions which, kinda, have a choice of Haste or Mastery being part of the conversation and Crit over in the corner. I think that with a Haste focus that it covers the wide range of activities offered in the game. It might be fun to switch out everything for Mastery!
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Legion Guide Updates</title>
			<link>www.raidadvice.com/legion-guide-updates/</link>
			<pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2017 03:14:44 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">www.raidadvice.com/legion-guide-updates/</guid>
			<description>&lt;p&gt;This past weekend, I updated the Legion &lt;a href=&#34;http://raidadvice.com/world-of-warcraft-legion-class-guides/&#34;&gt;class guides compilation&lt;/a&gt;, adding a few new class-specific sites I have heard about in the past few months and altering the recommended guide for a few specs based on community feedback. In the past month or so I have also updated the &lt;a href=&#34;http://raidadvice.com/legion-mythic-plus-dungeons-guide/&#34;&gt;Mythic Plus Dungeons Guide&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://raidadvice.com/withered-training-preparation-tips-and-tricks/&#34;&gt;Withered Training Guide&lt;/a&gt;, and added some comments to past articles for a bit of clarification. If you found one of those valuable in the past, you might want to check them out again. If you see something that looks like it still needs updating, let me know. As with every guide, try it out in game and make sure it works for you. As much as we all might like some &lt;a href=&#34;http://raidadvice.com/khadgar-admiration/&#34;&gt;Khadgar Admiration&lt;/a&gt;, you can&amp;rsquo;t believe everything you read.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Khadgar Admiration</title>
			<link>www.raidadvice.com/khadgar-admiration/</link>
			<pubDate>Sun, 19 Feb 2017 05:59:51 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">www.raidadvice.com/khadgar-admiration/</guid>
			<description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m posting this because it seems that a surprising number of people don&amp;rsquo;t know about it. In 7.1.5, Blizzard added a repeatable quest to turn Order Hall Resources in to Khadgar in Dalaran as tribute. The more times you turn them in, the greater his admiration for you as a hero grows, and the higher base ilvl gear rewards you can get from world quests. It works very similarly to Artifact Knowledge research in your order hall. Like Artifact Knowledge (AK) increases your Artifact Power gains, Khadgar Admiration (KA) increases gains from world quests. Once you get to max KA (25/25) your world quest rewards will skyrocket, with a consistent base item level of 880/885 instead of 840/845. Just like AK, KA will have even more levels in 7.2, allowing you to further increase your world quest rewards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;comments&#34;&gt;Comments:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;%22%22&#34;&gt;Morph&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Feb 0, 2017&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How is this accessed? Is this something that has to have the suramar questline completed?
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;heading-1&#34;&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;%22raphanwow@gmail.com%22&#34;&gt;Raphael&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Feb 0, 2017&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is dry satire ;). It seems like something Blizzard would do, though, right?
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;heading-2&#34;&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;%22%22&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Feb 2, 2017&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I thought this was real, should come with a disclaimer, not April Fools Day yet.
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;heading-3&#34;&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;%22%22&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Feb 6, 2017&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OP should know I like this blog for its reliable information. This post made me think twice about trusting all the other great work on this blog.
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Krosus Guide: How to Soak Burning Pitch</title>
			<link>www.raidadvice.com/krosus-guide-how-to-soak-burning-pitch/</link>
			<pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2017 06:04:24 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">www.raidadvice.com/krosus-guide-how-to-soak-burning-pitch/</guid>
			<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/npc=101002/krosus&#34;&gt;Krosus&lt;/a&gt; is the fourth boss attempted by many guilds raiding &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/the-nighthold&#34;&gt;The Nighthold&lt;/a&gt; on Mythic difficulty. Getting a fourth boss down is the first major &amp;ldquo;wall&amp;rdquo; to progression in mythic; as of this writing, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wowprogress.com/&#34;&gt;wowprogress&lt;/a&gt; indicated that around 2400 guilds have killed three bosses, while only around 700 have killed Krosus. One of the biggest difficulties on Krosus is soaking the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/spell=205420/burning-pitch&#34;&gt;Burning Pitch&lt;/a&gt; puddles to ensure that as few as possible &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/npc=104262/burning-ember&#34;&gt;adds&lt;/a&gt; spawn. On Mythic, Krosus demands near-perfect puddle soaking. Too many adds will result in them killing raiders, and if a player dies without a battle resurrection available on Krosus, it will likely wipe the raid. If your raid is already soaking puddles perfectly, keep doing what you are doing. If not, perhaps this guide will help. This guide will outline how to soak burning pitch, as well as give a few other Krosus tips. This guide assumes a basic familiarity with the fight, and might be most appreciated by players who have wiped several times on the boss thinking that they would be fine using the same strategy they used in heroic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;burning-pitch-soaking-basics&#34;&gt;Burning Pitch Soaking Basics&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A perhaps obvious, but nonetheless key, tip to soaking is that multiple puddles that overlap may be soaked by the same player. Two puddles are generally safe to soak, and three or more may be safe with a defensive ability or cooldown. If someone else is straddling multiple puddles to soak them, you should find a different place to soak! Another key element is to leave before the puddles form so the raid team can sort out which to soak. This must be balanced with staying on boss to meet a tight DPS check. However, if everyone leaves after the puddles have appeared, the raid will likely miss puddles. A third rule of thumb is that, once someone is stationary on a puddle, assume they are staying there - you should get another puddle, not assume they will move off of it. Fourth, the back is the most important area of the room to soak. Ideally all unsoaked puddles will be near the front, in or near melee range of the boss so they can be cleaved down together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;possible-pitch-soaking-strategies&#34;&gt;Possible Pitch Soaking Strategies&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, how should raiders approach picking which puddle to soak? YOLO: You only live once, just wing it - tell players to soak as many as they can. This strategy has problems if players all go towards the same area initially; many players might try to soak the same puddle, leaving others unsoaked. This is fine if you outgear the boss on Heroic, but in Mythic is inadvisable. Zone: Assign players to zones of the bridge they must soak. This is certainly better than YOLO, but can cause issues if the burning pitch puddles are imbalanced - one zone may have none, whereas others may have more puddles than raiders. Order: Assign players numbers from 1-20, 20 taking the backmost puddle, and up from there. This is also better than YOLO, but can get muddy in the middle of the room as people become unsure how far back they need to go. I suggest a hybrid approach, combining the best of both worlds from zone-based and order-based strategies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-hybrid-soaking-strategy&#34;&gt;The Hybrid Soaking Strategy&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As shown in &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1GrVF2g6kwQNpENaM3F65j0OCPYkbzNFxQkUz0UQWLWs/&#34;&gt;this spreadsheet&lt;/a&gt;, assign all non-tanks into six zones, assigning the number 1 and 2 to the tanks and 3-20 to each other player. Players 16, 18, and 20 (mobile ranged) should look to soak in the back right of the room, while players 3, 5, and 7 (melee) should look to soak in the front left. If the puddles are unbalanced, adjust on the fly, with higher-numbered players soaking towards the back. Another way to think about this six-zone strategy is as a three-zone strategy with half the players having a preference for each side. This is perhaps best explained with some examples. The following three diagrams, just like in the spreadsheet, have the boss in the front of the room with the players in the back. The green circles are burning pitch puddles, and the numbers are suggestions as to which player from the spreadsheet should soak each puddle. [caption id=&amp;quot;attachment_495&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;quot;alignnone&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;quot;606&amp;rdquo;]&lt;img src=&#34;http://raidadvice.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/02/krosus_examples.png&#34; alt=&#34;Krosus Burning Pitch Soaking Examples&#34;&gt; Krosus Burning Pitch Soaking Examples[/caption] In the left diagram, everything went according to plan. There were three puddle groups in each of the six zones. Tanks soaked two puddles by the boss, and only a few adds spawned near the front. In the middle diagram, the puddles spawned further towards the back than anticipated. The players adjusted, again only spawning a few adds near the front of the room. Several player had to soak further back than they expected - this is normal and OK. Note that sometimes tanks cannot soak any puddles if they need to be on the boss and no puddles spawn in melee range. In the right diagram, the puddles were imbalanced towards the left. Did the players assigned to the right groups stand there and soak nothing? No, they adjusted, maintaining a preference to be on the right, but moving to left of center as needed. Even with a lopsided &amp;ldquo;unlucky&amp;rdquo; pattern, the group was able to soak every puddle, preventing any ads from spawning!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;use-your-abilities&#34;&gt;Use Your Abilities&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If adds do spawn, use your stuns and interrupts on them. The enlarged adds especially do a ton of damage. Preventing their casts is a huge bonus. Most classes have a stun and/or interrupt. Talent into them, and use them!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;late-stage-soaking&#34;&gt;Late-Stage Soaking&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When only the last quarter of the platform remains, sticking to your assigned areas to soak burning pitch is still important. Basically the whole platform will be covered in puddles, and staying disciplined and following your zone and order assignments will result in maximized soaking. Be very careful not to overlap with another soaker - you each take the damage for no benefit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;orb-schemes&#34;&gt;Orb Schemes&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the last quarter of the platform, make sure that the raid is in the very front corner, and that the person with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/spell=205348/orb-of-destruction&#34;&gt;Orb of Destruction&lt;/a&gt; is in the very back opposite corner. A few yards makes a difference: the person in the back should run into the corner to make sure they are as far back as possible, and the raiders in the front should be on the white strip and as far forward as they can get without falling off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;beam-dreams&#34;&gt;Beam Dreams&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/spell=205391&#34;&gt;Fel Beams&lt;/a&gt; always follow the same pattern. Whether they start left or right is random, but after that they alternate between right and left. After a beam finishes, immediately move to side the beam was on to ensure that you are safe for the next side. &lt;a href=&#34;https://wago.io/EJ34WlqvM&#34;&gt;This weakaura&lt;/a&gt;, with slight input from a raid leader each fight, will show which side is safe for every beam after the first. Our group placed markers down the left side of the platforms so everyone would know, even when disoriented, that left was marked and right was unmarked. The weakaura has left in green text and right in red text, so we placed the red X marker in the back right and green triangle in the back left to indicate which side was which to someone facing backwards. If you are dying to beam more than once in a raid night, you are doing something very, very wrong. You have tons of time to mentally prepare to be in the right place, and you know exactly where the beam will be coming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;heal-memes&#34;&gt;Heal Memes&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a note, at the end of the fight, the Burning Pitch/&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/spell=205875&#34;&gt;Slam&lt;/a&gt;/Orb of Destruction combination at around 5:00 is very healing intensive. Save cooldowns and personals for that stretch. Raiders should self-heal and use healing potions to make sure they don&amp;rsquo;t die. Best of luck with your kill! If you have any questions leave a comment below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;comments&#34;&gt;Comments:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://coffeecakesandcrits.wordpress.com/&#34; title=&#34;wrathofkublakhan@yahoo.com&#34;&gt;wrathsome&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Feb 5, 2017&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brilliant.
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;heading-1&#34;&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;%22raphanwow@gmail.com%22&#34;&gt;Raphael&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Feb 1, 2017&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reddit comments: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/CompetitiveWoW/comments/5uknn4/krosus&#34;&gt;https://www.reddit.com/r/CompetitiveWoW/comments/5uknn4/krosus&lt;/a&gt;_a_spreadsheet_and_guide_to_soaking_burning/
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>WOW Tokens Now Convertible to Battlenet Balance</title>
			<link>www.raidadvice.com/wow-tokens-now-convertible-to-battlenet-balance/</link>
			<pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2017 03:46:02 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">www.raidadvice.com/wow-tokens-now-convertible-to-battlenet-balance/</guid>
			<description>&lt;p&gt;New today, you can now use wowtokens to exchange them for either gametime OR battlenet balance in certain regions. Prices are going up (track prices on &lt;a href=&#34;http://wowtoken.info&#34;&gt;wowtoken.info&lt;/a&gt;). See the &lt;a href=&#34;https://worldofwarcraft.com/en-us/news/20542016&#34;&gt;official announcement&lt;/a&gt; for an &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=BCWtkTWwpXM&#34;&gt;explanatory video&lt;/a&gt; and more details.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Flap - The Number One Reason to Play Druid</title>
			<link>www.raidadvice.com/flap-the-number-one-reason-to-play-druid/</link>
			<pubDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2017 14:50:35 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">www.raidadvice.com/flap-the-number-one-reason-to-play-druid/</guid>
			<description>&lt;p&gt;If you play Balance Druid and have not heard of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/spell=164862/flap&#34;&gt;Flap&lt;/a&gt;, you are missing out. It is our version of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/spell=130/slow-fall&#34;&gt;Slow Fall&lt;/a&gt;, usable only in Moonkin Form (you can use it in other specs with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/spell=197632/balance-affinity&#34;&gt;Balance Affinity&lt;/a&gt;). You learn the spell from a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/item=136794/tome-of-the-wilds-flap&#34;&gt;Tome&lt;/a&gt; that you can pick up in Moonglade or the Dreamgrove. This makes traveling around the broken isles much more quick, and, dare I say, fun. You cannot change directions while flapping, but with good aim, you can run off a cliff on your mount, start flapping, and float gracefully (or not-so-gracefully depending on how you view fat chickens frantically flapping their arms) to your destination. I think this goes against the spirit of flap, but in patch 7.1.5, you can now use flap with glyph of the stars. You look like you are levitating, not flapping, but the effect is the same. With this macro: &lt;code&gt;#showtooltip Flap /stopcasting [mod:alt] /use [nomod:alt]Flap&lt;/code&gt; Flap gets even more powerful. You can cancel flap with alt + the key you bind flap to, then recast it before you hit the ground. Flap gets supercharged when used with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/item=139773/emerald-winds&#34;&gt;The Emerald Winds&lt;/a&gt;. With Flap and Winds, you can gain altitude slightly while flapping around, and you can change direction! Take a flight point to somewhere high, and Winds + Flap to your destination. Flap - never leave home without it. Image: &lt;a href=&#34;http://imgur.com/EawakIe&#34;&gt;Check out the Majesty of Flap + Winds&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;comments&#34;&gt;Comments:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://coffeecakesandcrits.wordpress.com/&#34; title=&#34;wrathofkublakhan@yahoo.com&#34;&gt;wrathsome&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Jan 5, 2017&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gadzooks! That is totally flap-a-licious! Plus, you can show off while waiting for a pull in a raid; to the envy of all.
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Balance Druid: My Trinket and Gear Sims Start of Nighthold</title>
			<link>www.raidadvice.com/balance-druid-my-trinket-and-gear-sims-start-of-nighthold/</link>
			<pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2017 04:10:11 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">www.raidadvice.com/balance-druid-my-trinket-and-gear-sims-start-of-nighthold/</guid>
			<description>&lt;p&gt;As a follow up to &lt;a href=&#34;http://raidadvice.com/balance-druid-my-trinket-sims-end-of-trial-of-valor/&#34;&gt;my sims at the end of 7.1&lt;/a&gt;, I &lt;a href=&#34;http://raidadvice.com/remember-to-update-simulationcraft/&#34;&gt;updated Simcraft&lt;/a&gt; and am updating my simulations as of the start of Nighthold. I simulated using my current best gear. Single target used Starlord, Incarnation, Blessing of the Ancients, and Stellar Drift, and 3-target used Force of Nature, Soul of the Forest, Shooting Stars, and Stellar Drift.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;trinkets&#34;&gt;Trinkets&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The nerfs to AOE trinkets/buffs to stat-based trinkets going into Nighthold are remarkable. My 895 &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/item=140809/whispers-in-the-dark&#34;&gt;Whispers in the Dark&lt;/a&gt; (bonus roll first week, don&amp;rsquo;t hate me) and my 860 &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/item=141482/unstable-arcanocrystal&#34;&gt;Unstable Arcanocrystal&lt;/a&gt; (I guess it&amp;rsquo;s OK to hate me a little) are my best trinkets in all situations. A 885 &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/item=140792/erratic-metronome&#34;&gt;Erratic Metronome&lt;/a&gt;, which I do not yet have, might be slightly better than the Arcanocrystal at AOE, but it&amp;rsquo;s basically a wash. Swapping to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/item=142157/arans-relaxing-ruby&#34;&gt;Aran&amp;rsquo;s Relaxing Ruby&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/item=138224/unstable-horrorslime&#34;&gt;Unstable Horrorslime&lt;/a&gt; for AOE was a short-lived experience. My trinket results overall match up well with the &lt;a href=&#34;http://raidadvice.com/balance-druid-gear-spreadsheets-for-nighthold/&#34;&gt;Balance Druid Trinket Spreadsheet&lt;/a&gt; (Whispers is still best, though not quite &lt;em&gt;as&lt;/em&gt; best since it was nerfed slightly this week).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;gear&#34;&gt;Gear&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I swapped around my rings, since AOE is a lot more prevalent in Nighthold and Haste is just bonkers on AOE fights. The buff to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/item=132444/prydaz-xavarics-magnum-opus&#34;&gt;Prydaz&lt;/a&gt; makes it simulate only 0.5% worse than &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/item=133976/cinidaria-the-symbiote&#34;&gt;Cinidaria&lt;/a&gt; at DPS, and the survivability bonus of Prydaz argues for using it on high-damage progression fights over the belt. Gebuz&amp;rsquo;s recommended pawn string &amp;ldquo;(Pawn: v1: &amp;ldquo;Balance Druid&amp;rdquo;: Intellect=1, CritRating=0.8, HasteRating=1.2, MasteryRating=1, Versatility=0.8 )&amp;rdquo; is just about right for my character. I value Mastery at 1.05 since it is simulating a bit better than intellect, and Versatility at 0.85 since it offers survivability while Critical Strike doesn&amp;rsquo;t. Either way, those stat weights are solid. For pure AOE, haste is simulating as more than twice as good as intellect. However, pure AOE with no priority target is rare in a raid setting. For large packs in dungeons, you might value haste more highly than in a raid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;comments&#34;&gt;Comments:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;%22mklueppel@me.com%22&#34;&gt;Ammer&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Jan 6, 2017&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hi, is the sheet already updated after the damage buff?
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;heading-1&#34;&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;%22raphanwow@gmail.com%22&#34;&gt;Raphael&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Jan 6, 2017&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ammer, which buff are you referring to? I don&amp;rsquo;t believe the trinket spreadhseet had been updated yet since Nighthold&amp;rsquo;s release (including after the Nighthold-AOE-trinket damage buff). It is my understanding that Arcanocrystal, Whispers, and Metronome are still top three, however.
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Balance Druid Encounter Notes for Heroic Nighthold: Talents and Trinkets</title>
			<link>www.raidadvice.com/balance-druid-encounter-notes-for-heroic-nighthold-talents-and-trinkets/</link>
			<pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2017 06:00:11 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">www.raidadvice.com/balance-druid-encounter-notes-for-heroic-nighthold-talents-and-trinkets/</guid>
			<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/document/d/1c6-_akHl_Cja-uwg20Gt8R0f12pcw4_qtVcT7LyZW4A/edit&#34;&gt;Gebuz&amp;rsquo;s Guide&lt;/a&gt;, linked from the &lt;a href=&#34;http://raidadvice.com/world-of-warcraft-legion-class-guides/&#34;&gt;Class Guides Page&lt;/a&gt;, outlines several talent combinations for Nighthold. Many more combinations are possible after patch 7.1.5, as several talent options have been buffed to be more competitive. I tried out a few things the first week, and also &lt;a href=&#34;http://raidadvice.com/learn-from-logs-picking-the-top-talents/&#34;&gt;looked at top logs&lt;/a&gt;. What follows are my plans for this week in Nighthold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;ideas&#34;&gt;Ideas&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My talents selections are in shorthand and refer to each talent&amp;rsquo;s position in the Nth row. For example, &amp;ldquo;1233112&amp;rdquo; would be a standard frequent-AOE build, with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/spell=205636/force-of-nature&#34;&gt;Force of Nature&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/spell=102280/displacer-beast&#34;&gt;Displacer Beast&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/spell=197492&#34;&gt;Restoration Affinity&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/spell=132469/typhoon&#34;&gt;Typhoon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/spell=114107/soul-of-the-forest&#34;&gt;Soul of the Forest&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/spell=202342/shooting-stars&#34;&gt;Shooting Stars&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/spell=202354/stellar-drift&#34;&gt;Stellar Drift&lt;/a&gt;. It may be easier to follow along with the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/talent-calc/druid/balance&#34;&gt;Balance Druid Talent Calculator&lt;/a&gt; open in game or in another window. I favor Stellar Drift for all fights as ads are usually high priority, and my &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/item=137092/oneths-intuition&#34;&gt;Oneth&amp;rsquo;s Intuition&lt;/a&gt; legendary gives free Starfalls to boot. I dislike Displacer Beast and try to use Wild Charge or Renewal when possible to save GCDs. If you are worried about reacting slowly or need to move far distances, Displacer Beast is the safer bet. I like Starlord with Incarnation builds and Force of Nature or Warrior of Elune with Soul of the Forest builds. Taking Starlord when you intend to be casting Starfall with most of your Astral Power seems very unintuitive to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;fight-specific-plans&#34;&gt;Fight-Specific Plans&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Skorpyron: 2332112. AOE trinkets. Sephuz. Heavy AOE fight; Force of Nature or Starlord could be justified, all three talents are close with AOE. Sephuz can be reliably proc&amp;rsquo;d on cooldown by Mass Entanglement. Chronomatic Anomaly: 1333112. ST (single target) trinkets. The ads are up enough to make AOE worth it, but my AOE trinkets require stacked ads. Trilliax: 3333232. ST trinkets. Heavy movement negates Nature&amp;rsquo;s Balance value, even on a single target fight, and Stellar Drift allows movement while casting during beam. Spelldblade Aluriel: 1333112. AOE trinkets. The multi-ad phases make AOE a priority. Tichondrius: 3333232. ST trinkets. Demon Ring for 2-set (the neck is my non-legendary BiS neck already). You can rank with Soul of the Forest and Shooting Stars on intermission, but I don&amp;rsquo;t see that as the important part of the fight. Krosus: 3231232. ST trinkets. Demon Ring for 2-set. Classic ST fight if your fellow raiders have perfect execution of mechanics. Stellar Drift is nice if people miss soaking pools and spawn adds; Nature&amp;rsquo;s Balance is likely better if few adds spawn. Botanist: 1333112. AOE Trinkets. Constant cleave fight after 75%. Star Augur: 3123232. ST trinkets. Little movement, but my legendary and the ads in the last third make Stellar Drift worth it. Elisande: 1223112. ST trinkets. Somewhat similar to Anomaly, the ads are up just enough to make AOE worth it. Gul&amp;rsquo;dan: 1223112. ST trinkets. Frequent AOE burst, but not up enough to make AOE trinkets worth it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;trinket-spoilers&#34;&gt;Trinket Spoilers&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Balance, you actually don&amp;rsquo;t want to swap out trinkets in Nighthold much, as the same trinkets tend to do well on both AOE and single target. Look for a post tomorrow to see my simulation results.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Preparing for Nighthold</title>
			<link>www.raidadvice.com/preparing-for-nighthold/</link>
			<pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2017 06:33:33 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">www.raidadvice.com/preparing-for-nighthold/</guid>
			<description>&lt;p&gt;I realized I did not make a preparing for Nighthold post like my &lt;a href=&#34;http://raidadvice.com/preparing-for-the-emerald-nightmare/&#34;&gt;Preparing for the Emerald Nightmare post&lt;/a&gt;. The reason? I didn&amp;rsquo;t have to. I actually read that prior post and followed its advice in preparing for Nighthold. Many of the links now lead to Nighthold information, and the same principles for preparation that applied then apply now. And the preparation worked out pretty well - I did well both as Balance and offhealing (considering my gear and Artifact Power) as Restoration. We cleared 9/10H during our seven hours of raid, and many of us got together and managed to down Heroic Gul&amp;rsquo;dan (after 10/10 normal) on our optional Sunday run. I am excited for Mythic progression, which for me is &amp;ldquo;the real challenge.&amp;rdquo; At some point I may rewrite that article generalizing for all raids. For now, if you are wondering what more you can do to prepare for Nighthold, check out that post. I have pre-written a few posts about Balance Druid and Nighthold that you can expect to see this coming week, if you are focused on Balance Druid preparation in particular.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;comments&#34;&gt;Comments:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://coffeecakesandcrits.wordpress.com/&#34; title=&#34;wrathofkublakhan@yahoo.com&#34;&gt;wrathsome&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Jan 6, 2017&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I see that your typical raid week is seven hours; is that three then four over two days? 3/2/2?
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;heading-1&#34;&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;%22raphanwow@gmail.com%22&#34;&gt;Raphael&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Jan 6, 2017&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My current guild, No Big Deal of Stormrage-US, raids 3.5 hours Tuesday and Wednesday night each week.
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Balance Druid Gear Spreadsheets for Nighthold</title>
			<link>www.raidadvice.com/balance-druid-gear-spreadsheets-for-nighthold/</link>
			<pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2017 05:25:38 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">www.raidadvice.com/balance-druid-gear-spreadsheets-for-nighthold/</guid>
			<description>&lt;p&gt;Unlike my &lt;a href=&#34;http://raidadvice.com/balance-druid-gear-spreadsheet-for-the-emerald-nightmare/&#34;&gt;Emerald Nightmare Balance Druid Spreadsheet&lt;/a&gt;, I did not make these two google docs. However, they are great baseline comparison tools for Balance Druid gear from the Nighthold: &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/12_FLVPAbGQTxSg42uC1N9r4wvtNF3swW7L3Z-aVHLgQ/&#34;&gt;Trinket Comparison Spreadsheet&lt;/a&gt;; &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/10r4a77VQt53vQ6YnR0NUnw0rCq0ZLBqWId7FpB0qq_E/&#34;&gt;Gear Comparison Spreadhseet&lt;/a&gt;. Both were sticky posts in the Druid Discord channel. Check out your class and spec at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://raidadvice.com/world-of-warcraft-legion-useful-discord-channels/&#34;&gt;Useful Discord Channel List&lt;/a&gt; I compiled. More and more, the class Discord channels are becoming the go-to place for up-to-the-minute information about your class. Sensibly, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/item=142157/arans-relaxing-ruby&#34;&gt;Aran&amp;rsquo;s Relaxing Ruby&lt;/a&gt; has been nerfed. It is still okay-ish for AOE, but it is no longer the best single target trinket (combined with the Nightbane chest) as it was when I &lt;a href=&#34;http://raidadvice.com/balance-druid-my-trinket-sims-end-of-trial-of-valor/&#34;&gt;simmed a few weeks ago&lt;/a&gt;. On top for single target are &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/item=140809/whispers-in-the-dark&#34;&gt;Whispers in the Dark&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/item=140792/erratic-metronome&#34;&gt;Erratic Metronome&lt;/a&gt;. I did not score the Metronome when we went 7/10H in the first night of Nighthold, but my &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/item=141482/unstable-arcanocrystal&amp;amp;bonus=3466&#34;&gt;Unstable Arcanocrystal&lt;/a&gt; and 880 &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/item=142166/ethereal-urn&#34;&gt;Ethereal Urn&lt;/a&gt; are about as good as you can get outside those two.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;comments&#34;&gt;Comments:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://coffeecakesandcrits.wordpress.com/&#34; title=&#34;wrathofkublakhan@yahoo.com&#34;&gt;wrathsome&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Jan 3, 2017&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cool. Do you use the &amp;ldquo;memekin&amp;rdquo; build that I read about over on the Restokin site? If so, how do you like it?
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;heading-1&#34;&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;%22raphanwow@gmail.com%22&#34;&gt;Raphael&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Jan 0, 2017&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use shooting stars/ stellar drift for most fights with frequent ads, about half of the dungeon. Gebuz&amp;rsquo;s balance guide (linked from my class guides) has been updated for 7.1.5 and goes over several talent variations.
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Get 20% Better at Raiding in One Simple Step</title>
			<link>www.raidadvice.com/get-20-better-at-raiding-in-one-simple-step/</link>
			<pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2017 05:50:36 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">www.raidadvice.com/get-20-better-at-raiding-in-one-simple-step/</guid>
			<description>&lt;p&gt;Whether it&amp;rsquo;s friends asking for tips on a spec, readers wondering if a guide is accurate, or people in trade chat wondering if &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/item=19019/thunderfury-blessed-blade-of-the-windseeker&#34;&gt;Thunderfury&lt;/a&gt; is their best in slot legendary, people often reach out to me and ask how they can get better at raiding. There are many complicated methods of getting better. We can analyze logs. We can eek out small gains in Simcraft. We can acquire better gear. We can practice our rotation. We can study encounters and develop strategies to overcome them. Those are all good things to do, and in past expansions, one of them might have been my top suggestion for getting better results. Not in Legion though. In Legion, this one simple tip is your best bet for improvement: Complete as many Mythic Plus Dungeons as you can. It&amp;rsquo;s a long process and is not easy, since the beginning of the end (54 traits in your primary spec) is over 200 dungeons away. But it&amp;rsquo;s very simple. And I am not being facetious here. Mythic Plus dungeons are likely the quickest, most repeatable way to acquire artifact power, and getting enough artifact power for 54 traits is guaranteed to make you 15-20% better than you were at 34 traits. Not only that, Mythic Plus may reward you with gear improvements. It lets you practice your spec as well. You can be bad at analyzing logs or understanding encounters. But no matter your skill level, you will be 15-20% better after maximizing your artifact weapon. If you get good legendary drops or titanforges, you might be even more than 20% more effective after completing the grind. Logs? Simcraft? Gear? Practice? Preparation? Nah. Just spam dungeons.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Delete your Hearthstone</title>
			<link>www.raidadvice.com/delete-your-hearthstone/</link>
			<pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2017 05:22:37 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">www.raidadvice.com/delete-your-hearthstone/</guid>
			<description>&lt;p&gt;If you don&amp;rsquo;t love special events, the recent Diablo-themed Warcraft event may have caused your eyes to glaze over. You may have missed the limited-availability &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/item=142542/tome-of-town-portal&#34;&gt;Tome of Town Portal&lt;/a&gt;. This toy is obtained easily by killing and looting 5 or so &lt;a href=&#34;http://ru.wowhead.com/npc=116041/treasure-goblin&#34;&gt;Treasure Goblins&lt;/a&gt;. They appear in various places - the easiest place to farm them is the Dalaran Underbelly, where they appear every few minutes. It shares a cooldown with and has the same functionality as a Hearthstone, but it is a toy so it doesn&amp;rsquo;t take up bag space. Move aside Hearthstone - the Tome has arrived!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;comments&#34;&gt;Comments:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://coffeecakesandcrits.wordpress.com/&#34; title=&#34;wrathofkublakhan@yahoo.com&#34;&gt;wrathsome&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Jan 5, 2017&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Woot! I need the bag space. I need the Action Bar space more, for certain sure. But if I &amp;lsquo;favorite&amp;rsquo; the toy, I can quick open my collections. With the Innkeeper&amp;rsquo;s Daughter, I could only use it on the character who did the digs &amp;ndash; I hope this Tome is account-wide!
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Balance Druid: My Trinket Sims end of Trial of Valor</title>
			<link>www.raidadvice.com/balance-druid-my-trinket-sims-end-of-trial-of-valor/</link>
			<pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2016 06:55:51 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">www.raidadvice.com/balance-druid-my-trinket-sims-end-of-trial-of-valor/</guid>
			<description>&lt;p&gt;Hey everyone. I am still around; I simply haven&amp;rsquo;t had much I wanted to post about. The game and my life have both kept me pretty busy. The &lt;a href=&#34;http://raidadvice.com/world-of-warcraft-legion-class-guides/&#34;&gt;Legion class guide compilation&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://raidadvice.com/legion-mythic-plus-dungeons-guide/&#34;&gt;Mythic+ Guide post&lt;/a&gt; are still pretty current. I plan to do a significant review of them once Nighthold comes out. In the next week or two, there are a few posts I could make: I joined a new 2-day guild (we are 2/3 Mythic ToV); I have thoughts on Restoration Druid M+ talents; I suspected Feral Affinity was great months ago, and now top Balance Druids are starting to use it in raids. I simmed my druid recently. The simulation confirmed what I had thought. Of the trinkets I currently have, the two non-raid, non-Mythic+ trinkets are my best single target trinkets. &lt;a href=&#34;http://imgur.com/ZpK2fdh&#34;&gt;Single Target Results&lt;/a&gt;; &lt;a href=&#34;http://imgur.com/H4hvZ9k&#34;&gt;Three-Target Results&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/item=142157/arans-relaxing-ruby&#34;&gt;Aran&amp;rsquo;s Relaxing Ruby&lt;/a&gt;, which drops from Karazhan, is my best trinket. When buffed by the Nightbane chest, is incredibly strong. It is an AOE trinket that is my best single target trinket. On AOE it is incredible. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/item=141482/unstable-arcanocrystal&amp;amp;bonus=3466&#34;&gt;Unstable Arcanocrystal&lt;/a&gt;, which drops from a world boss that spawns every other month or so, is my second best trinket for single target. These ilvl 860 trinkets outclass my 880 socketed &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/item=139321/swarming-plaguehive&amp;amp;bonus=1807&#34;&gt;Swarming Plaguehive&lt;/a&gt; on single target, and the Ruby is better than my 890 titanforged-socketed &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/item=138224/unstable-horrorslime&amp;amp;bonus=1807&#34;&gt;Unstable Horrorslime&lt;/a&gt; on AOE. 30 ilvls and a socket: still not as good as the ruby. As someone who is mostly motivated to play by raiding, it feels a bit odd that my best trinkets come from outside of raid. And not just outside of raid. One is RNG on top of RNG, dropping on one of three times I was able to kill and bonus roll a world boss this expansion. The other came from a boss late in Karazhan, which, while a fun dungeon, isn&amp;rsquo;t something I wanted to feel obligated to run in its entirety every week for a shot at my best trinket. And these are just the trinkets I have - an 880 titanforged haste statstick would be incredible, as would one or two 880+ titanforged trinkets from dungeons. Anyhow, I might go into more detail about Legion gearing at some point. For now, have a happy New Year&amp;rsquo;s Eve!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;comments&#34;&gt;Comments:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://coffeecakesandcrits.wordpress.com/&#34; title=&#34;wrathofkublakhan@yahoo.com&#34;&gt;wrathsome&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Dec 6, 2016&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yeah, I remember when, in WoD, you could get BiS trinkets in the mythic version of dungeons. No plus back then but we ran and ran and ran those every week trying for that lucky rolling upgrade. I agree, it feels wrong!
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Legion Mythic Plus Dungeons Guide</title>
			<link>www.raidadvice.com/legion-mythic-plus-dungeons-guide/</link>
			<pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2016 07:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">www.raidadvice.com/legion-mythic-plus-dungeons-guide/</guid>
			<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EDIT 2017-4-6: Mythic Plus has changed last week with Patch 7.2. This change includes 3 new dungeons, new affixes, and max gear reward at M+10. Aside from that, the below information is still mostly accurate.&lt;/strong&gt; (Last Revised 2017-1-21, see &lt;a href=&#34;#Changelog&#34;&gt;Changelog&lt;/a&gt; below) This guide presents my thoughts and tips on Legion&amp;rsquo;s Mythic Plus dungeons. I cover general strategy, affixes, and dungeons. This is intended to be a living document, updated with suggestions or as Blizzard adds or changes content. I have gotten the highest rewarding M+ level most every week since they were released, and have tanked, healed, and DPS&amp;rsquo;d high levels of Mythic+ on my Druid and tanked on my Paladin. My highest completed as of January 21, 2017 is M+16; I completed the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/achievement=11162/keystone-master&#34;&gt;Keystone Master&lt;/a&gt; achievement December 16, 2016 (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.twitch.tv/raphanw/v/107996645&#34;&gt;twitch video&lt;/a&gt; of Neltharion&amp;rsquo;s Lair +15, Balance Druid POV). On November 14, 2016, some friends and I completed M+13 Court of Stars, before it had been nerfed. I played a Restoration Druid (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.twitch.tv/raphanw/v/100809759&#34;&gt;twitch video of final boss kill&lt;/a&gt; after hours of wipes). This guide assumes a reasonable familiarity with Mythic+ and is targeted at players looking to improve their performance. For a basic overview of what Mythic+ dungeons are and how they work, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/mythic-keystones-and-dungeons-guide&#34;&gt;this guide on wowhead&lt;/a&gt; does well. The linked guides of each dungeon there are a good way to get a very detailed understanding of most bosses, mobs, and mechanics of each dungeon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;rewards&#34;&gt;Rewards&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mythic+ dungeons are pretty fun and a reward unto themselves, allowing you to challenge your best times and highest level completed while adding variety with new affix combinations each week. Wait, you need a reason to repeatedly run the same 9 dungeons other than enjoyment? Hmph, well then! Mythic+ dungeons are a great source of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/artifact-weapons-guide#power&#34;&gt;Artifact Power&lt;/a&gt;, especially if you complete them quickly. They have a chance to drop Legendary items each time you complete a dungeon. They reward gear that increases in iLvL the higher Mythic+ you do. They also reward a weekly chest in you class hall with a random piece of loot whose iLvL is based on the highest Mythic+ you did the previous week (at the start of patch 7.1.5, the highest base reward is iLvL 900 from doing a Mythic+15 the previous week).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;general-strategy&#34;&gt;General Strategy&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;mindset&#34;&gt;Mindset&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mythic+s are at their core a time trial. Complete the dungeon as quickly as possible with as few deaths as possible (as deaths add to the timer). As the last mob is dying from a pull, if everyone is healthy and the healer is at full mana you want to already be starting the next pull or using mounts/speed boosts to get towards it. Mythic+ is not a place for 30 seconds of AFK or debating what to do inside the dungeon. Talk about strategy beforehand; during the dungeon execute upon the strategy. It is often faster to just kill a mob/pull than spend 15 seconds discussing whether it is necessary. A very helpful addon for Mythic+ is aptly named &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mods.curse.com/addons/wow/gottagofast&#34;&gt;Gotta Go Fast&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;rdquo; It will let you know precisely how close you are to the time requirements for 2 or 3 chests and exactly what percentage of mob completion you are at.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;consumables&#34;&gt;Consumables&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Part of the going fast mindset is using consumables as appropriate. If beating the 3-chest timer for you on a dungeon is not trivial, you want to be using flasks, food, and potions. If a &lt;a href=&#34;http://wowhead.com/spell=229217/potion-of-prolonged-power&#34;&gt;Potion of Prolonged Power&lt;/a&gt; costs less than 100 gold on your server, why aren&amp;rsquo;t you drinking them on cooldown during tough Mythic+ dungeons? Healers absolutely must bring food (I recommend a mage&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/item=113509/conjured-mana-fritter&#34;&gt;Conjured Mana Fritters&lt;/a&gt; or cooking &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/item=133575/dried-mackerel-strips&#34;&gt;Dried Mackerel Strips&lt;/a&gt;) to replenish mana between pulls. Non-healers should bring food as well to eat up and restore health while healers are eating (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/item=143681/slightly-burnt-food&#34;&gt;Sightly Burnt Food&lt;/a&gt; works well for this - Nomi was trying to help you in Mythic+ all along!). Also bring &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/item=132514/auto-hammer&#34;&gt;Auto-Hammer&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/item=49040/jeeves&#34;&gt;Jeeves&lt;/a&gt; in case someone in the group needs to repair. Don&amp;rsquo;t let them hold you back by needing to hearth or continue broken - have a repair ready! Don&amp;rsquo;t hoard gold for the sake of hoarding gold - using consumables enhances your performance and experience. Use them!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;heroism&#34;&gt;Heroism&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are not a mage, shaman, or Beast Mastery hunter, bring along &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/item=142406/drums-of-the-mountain&#34;&gt;Drums of the Mountain&lt;/a&gt; so your groups have access to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/spell=32182/heroism&#34;&gt;Heroism&lt;/a&gt; no matter who else is in the group. You generally want to use heroism on the first boss of each dungeon. Use it again on the next boss where it&amp;rsquo;s off cooldown if you will get a third use, or save the second and final use for the most difficult encounter of a dungeon. On tyrannical, you may find certain bosses impossible to kill without heroism. Use a DBM break timer (/dbm break 5) and come back when herosim is ready if you wiped. Tyrannical bosses can feel like progression raiding if you do not out-gear them. I think this is fun and good; whatever your opinion of it, you may need time and patience if you want to kill every Mythic+ boss on tyrannical. As an aside, I wish that Blizzard would make the heroism debuff dissappear after a wipe once the timer has expired on a Mythic+ dungeon. Waiting 5-10 minutes between pulls for heroism on difficult encounters is a tad annoying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;team-building&#34;&gt;Team-Building&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make friends with people you run Mythic+ dungeons with and try and do more dungeons with them. Whether from your guild, friends list, or PUG, every party member is a potential long-term Mythic+ group mate. Just like raids, Mythic+s go more smoothly the more familiar the group is with each other and the strategy the group is using on a particular encounter. Also like raids, voice communication helps. If you have to start by PUGing, then by all means go for it. But hopefully over the course of playing you can find some folks to play with repeatedly. Ideally you and your buddies can get a high Mythic+ done each week to maximize your weekly reward cache.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;team-picking&#34;&gt;Team-Picking&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not all classes are created equal. AOE stuns, interrupts, and creature control are useful. AOE damage is good, as is survivability and mobility. Of course, player skill comes before class, but for near-or-equal skill levels, the following classes have an edge. Balance changes by Blizzard will change who does better or worse numbers. Also, the best class for one dungeon may be worse on another. But in terms of &lt;em&gt;class design&lt;/em&gt;, the following strike me as generally strong for Mythic+: &lt;strong&gt;Tanks:&lt;/strong&gt; Paladins - Paladins have interrupts for days, excellent damage, great survivability, and many tricks up their sleeves. Druids - Druids are &lt;em&gt;extremely&lt;/em&gt; survivable and can do very reasonable AOE DPS. Blood Death Knights - 20 yard AOE grip is extremely powerful and DKs do excellent damage. For any affix except Necrotic, DKs are great if they can survive the encounters. That can be a &amp;ldquo;big if&amp;rdquo; on hard content, however. The other thanks are usable but the above tanks - again in terms of class design - seem strongest. &lt;strong&gt;Melee DPS:&lt;/strong&gt; Rogues: They can pick the spec best suited to the dungeon, as at least two are currently viable, and they bring strong survivability and mob control. They can shroud groups past pulls you want to skip, bring sap, and have tricks of the trade for skittish. Enhancement Shamans: They have an AOE stun, bring heroism, and are designed to do great AOE damage. Windwalker Monks bring a lot of the same things Enhancement Shamans do. DPS DKs are also quite strong, with grip being useful in many situations. Really, almost every melee class is strong and viable in Mythic+. Pure melee groups can be viable depending on the dungeon. &lt;strong&gt;Ranged DPS:&lt;/strong&gt; Mages: Mages are the best ranged class to bring, and it is not close. Like Rogues, they can pick the spec best suited to the dungeon or group. Fire has great AOE DPS, and mages bring heroism, crowd control, and good survivability. Balance Druids: They can bring extremely strong sustained AOE after patch 7.1.5, which is usually great in Mythic+. **Healers: **Restoration Druids: They have nearly unlimited mobility, strong survivability, and can add significant DPS in low-healing periods. The best by a _large _margin on weeks with the Overflowing affix. Restoration Shamans: They bring very strong boss healing with several good cooldowns. Heroism, AOE stun, hex, and interrupt all add value. Most healing specs are close and can get through any level of Mythic+, but the above two are the strongest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;getting-carried&#34;&gt;Getting &amp;ldquo;Carried&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you do not have friends to run with and are not sure whether you will complete your key this week, you might as well use it in a PUG. You can create your own PUG and hope for the best, possibly hoping to find people to play with in the future. Alternatively, you can join a &amp;ldquo;carry group.&amp;rdquo; Many groups of experienced 880+ ilvl players will create groups in the group finder indicating what dungeons and M+ range they are looking to play. If you have a key that fits what they are looking to run, apply to the group and whisper them linking your key. Some of these groups will let you down, but often they will make the 3-chest timer for you key and provide an efficient dungeon experience. If your alternative is letting your M+ key expire, you may as well give it a shot. For all you know, you may hit it off with the group and run with them in the future. I have a friend who found a new guild through a Mythic+ guild carry group. If you lead a group doing the carrying, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://mods.curse.com/addons/wow/254158-keybooster&#34;&gt;Keybooster&lt;/a&gt; addon is a nice UI improvement to sort out which applicants have which key.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tips-and-tricks&#34;&gt;Tips and Tricks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rogues are sneaky! &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/spell=114018/shroud-of-concealment&#34;&gt;Shroud&lt;/a&gt; can help your group sneak past groups, and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/spell=6770/sap&#34;&gt;Sap&lt;/a&gt; can incapacitate a target, turning a group that you couldn&amp;rsquo;t all sneak past into a group you &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; all sneak past. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/item=116268/draenic-invisibility-potion&#34;&gt;Invisibility potions&lt;/a&gt; can be useful for skipping packs, either as part of a main strategy or in case you kill too many mobs earlier in the dungeon. Similarly, you can &amp;ldquo;corpse-run&amp;rdquo; through mobs you do not want to fight. To &amp;ldquo;corpse-run,&amp;rdquo; run through mobs and have the healer try to die first. Have someone battle-resurrect the healer, waiting to take the resurrection until everyone has died. The healer then group resurrects everyone, and the mobs are now behind you instead of ahead of you. This is generally worse than using an invisibility potion. &amp;ldquo;Kiting&amp;rdquo; is the process of a tank getting mobs&amp;rsquo; aggression focused on the tank then running away from the mobs out of melee range. Kiting is great on Necrotic. It can also be great generally on fortified or otherwise difficult pulls, allowing DPS to bring down ads while the tank stays alive. Night Elf healers can &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/spell=58984/shadowmeld&#34;&gt;Shadowmeld&lt;/a&gt; and start eating to replenish mana during a pull. Know where you will respawn if you release. If you are fighting the first pack below decks in Maw of Souls, you should release and spawn right there, not wait for a resurrection. Conversely, you had better not release if you die while the last mob of the last pack dies in Darkheart Thicket - you will respawn far away and waste your group&amp;rsquo;s time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;affixes&#34;&gt;Affixes&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/affix=7&#34;&gt;Bolstering&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/affix=6&#34;&gt;Raging&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/affix=8&#34;&gt;Sanguine&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/affix=5&#34;&gt;Teeming&lt;/a&gt; appear at M+ 4 and higher. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/affix=4&#34;&gt;Necrotic&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/affix=1&#34;&gt;Overflowing&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/affix=2&#34;&gt;Skittish&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/affix=3&#34;&gt;Volcanic&lt;/a&gt; appear at M+ 7 and higher. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/affix=10&#34;&gt;Fortified&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/affix=9&#34;&gt;Tyrannical&lt;/a&gt; appear at M+ 10 and higher. Several of these are easier or harder based on group composition; it pays to have many friends of different classes and/or who can play multiple specs. More affixes are coming; Blizzcon 2016 revealed &amp;ldquo;Bursting,&amp;rdquo; an affix that causes mobs to explode and place a stacking damage over time effect on players (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mmo-champion.com/threads/2107128-What-do-you-think-of-the-new-affix-shown-in-Blizzcon&#34;&gt;MMO-Champion thread discussing it&lt;/a&gt;). The affixes appear in a semirandom combination; &lt;a href=&#34;http://image.prntscr.com/image/baab6e39bd2b4b82bb3089489b9b06d8.png&#34;&gt;this chart&lt;/a&gt; shows predictions of what combination of affixes will come based on observations from beta and other regions: &lt;img src=&#34;http://image.prntscr.com/image/baab6e39bd2b4b82bb3089489b9b06d8.png&#34; alt=&#34;Chart of Affixes by Week&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;bolstering&#34;&gt;Bolstering&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/affix=7&#34;&gt;Bolstering&lt;/a&gt; -&amp;ldquo;When any non-boss enemy dies, its death cry empowers nearby allies, increasing their maximum health and damage by 20%.&amp;rdquo; &lt;strong&gt;Strategy:&lt;/strong&gt; AOE down all mobs so they all die at the same time. Make sure not to kill weaker mobs while leaving stronger mobs at high health.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;raging&#34;&gt;Raging&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/affix=6&#34;&gt;Raging&lt;/a&gt; - &amp;ldquo;Non-boss enemies enrage at 30% health remaining, dealing 100% increased damage until defeated.&amp;rdquo; **Strategy: **Ideally bring AOE stuns and stun the mobs as they reach 20%. At higher levels of M+, if you cannot kill all mobs while stunned below 20%, single target down mobs so only one or two mobs enrage at a time. Single target stun enraged mobs as necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;sanguine&#34;&gt;Sanguine&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/affix=8&#34;&gt;Sanguine&lt;/a&gt; - &amp;ldquo;When slain, non-boss enemies leave behind a lingering pool of ichor that heals their allies and damages players.&amp;rdquo; &lt;strong&gt;Strategy:&lt;/strong&gt; Tanks should steadily kite mobs so that remaining mobs do not stand on sanguine pools. Classes that can knock back or pull ads should bring those abilities to get stubborn stationary mobs out of sanguine. Death Knight &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/spell=49576/death-grip&#34;&gt;Grip&lt;/a&gt;, Druid &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/spell=132469/typhoon&#34;&gt;Typhoon&lt;/a&gt;, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;teeming&#34;&gt;Teeming&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/affix=5&#34;&gt;Teeming&lt;/a&gt; - &amp;ldquo;Additional non-boss enemies are present throughout the dungeon.&amp;rdquo; &lt;strong&gt;Strategy:&lt;/strong&gt; This affix will force players to change pull routes they are accustomed to, as more mobs will be necessary to achieve 100% completion rate. Some dungeons will now spawn a group of 3-4 hard-hitting mobs instead of 1-2, turning a manageable pull into one that is very difficult without creature control. Spells like &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/spell=51514/hex&#34;&gt;Hex&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/spell=118/polymorph&#34;&gt;Polymorph&lt;/a&gt; are your friends here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;necrotic&#34;&gt;Necrotic&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/affix=4&#34;&gt;Necrotic&lt;/a&gt; - &amp;ldquo;All enemies&amp;rsquo; melee attacks apply a stacking blight that inflicts damage over time and reduces healing received.&amp;rdquo; &lt;strong&gt;Strategy:&lt;/strong&gt; The stack keeps growing indefinitely until the player is not hit for several seconds and the stack falls off. As with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/affix=6&#34;&gt;Raging&lt;/a&gt;, AOE stuns are a big help. A tank ideally wants to kite away from mobs to let Necrotic fall off during big pulls. Some tanks have a much easier time of this than others. Blood Death Knights in particular complain about Necrotic. If kiting is not proving effective, pull smaller groups than normal or use creature control to minimize stacks on the tank.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;overflowing&#34;&gt;Overflowing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/affix=1&#34;&gt;Overflowing&lt;/a&gt; - &amp;ldquo;Healing in excess of a target&amp;rsquo;s maximum health is instead converted to a heal absorption effect.&amp;rdquo; &lt;strong&gt;Strategy:&lt;/strong&gt; This varies based on the healer. For Restoration Druids, this is a very easy affix. Heal over time spells like &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/spell=774/rejuvenation&#34;&gt;Rejuvenation&lt;/a&gt; will tick once on a full party member, creating an absorption shield, then tick again and remove the shield. The affix can practically be ignored. Classes with mostly big, direct heals struggle with overflowing. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/spell=633/lay-on-hands&#34;&gt;Lay on Hands&lt;/a&gt; is particularly problematic if used without care.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;skittish&#34;&gt;Skittish&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/affix=2&#34;&gt;Skittish&lt;/a&gt; - &amp;ldquo;Enemies pay far less attention to threat generated by tanks.&amp;rdquo; &lt;strong&gt;Strategy:&lt;/strong&gt; This depends on how well the tank can keep aggro. Tanks with high damage like Paladins and Demon Hunters have a bit of a better time. Warrios in particular struggle. Hunters using &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/spell=34477/misdirection&#34;&gt;Misdirection&lt;/a&gt; or Rogues using &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/spell=57934/tricks-of-the-trade&#34;&gt;Tricks of the Trade&lt;/a&gt; helps. AOE stuns also help - noticing a pattern?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;volcanic&#34;&gt;Volcanic&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/affix=3&#34;&gt;Volcanic&lt;/a&gt; - &amp;ldquo;While in combat, enemies periodically cause gouts of flame to erupt beneath the feet of distant players.&amp;rdquo; &lt;strong&gt;Strategy:&lt;/strong&gt; If you see a volcano spawning under you, stop what you are doing and move. It&amp;rsquo;s simple to say, but it can be difficult to execute, and it can be very hard for certain casters and healers to be effective with lots of additional movement. Every mob will periodically cause a volcano to spawn on players at range from it (or a random player if no player is at range). This means that if a single mob is attacking a &amp;ldquo;ranged&amp;rdquo; player, the melee and tanks are eligible to have volcanoes spawned under them. Ranged classes with many instant casts deal with this much more easily. Beast Mastery Hunters in particular have an easy time dealing with Volcanic. Certain dungeons have mobs that are more resistant to being grouped up, making Volcanic on melee more frequent and worrisome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;fortified&#34;&gt;Fortified&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/affix=10&#34;&gt;Fortified&lt;/a&gt; - &amp;ldquo;Non-boss enemies have 20% more health and inflict up to 40% increased damage.&amp;rdquo; &lt;strong&gt;Strategy:&lt;/strong&gt; I will cover this more on a per dungeon basis. Generally you need to pull smaller packs and use stuns and creature control better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tyrannical&#34;&gt;Tyrannical&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/affix=9&#34;&gt;Tyrannical&lt;/a&gt; - &amp;ldquo;Boss enemies have 40% more health and inflict up to 20% increased damage.&amp;rdquo; &lt;strong&gt;Strategy:&lt;/strong&gt; I will cover this on a per-boss basis. This makes some dungeons much harder. As of January 21, 2017, the final bosses of Court of Stars, Eye of Azshara, and Blackrock Hold are among the most difficult.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;dungeons&#34;&gt;Dungeons&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This guide assumes that you have done the dungeons and are looking to improve. It points out a few ways to improve on each dungeon rather than explain every single mechanic. On each dungeon you need to interrupt important casts (like fears or heals), stun mobs when they enrage, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;black-rock-hold&#34;&gt;Black Rock Hold&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This dungeon is pretty straightforward, albeit challenging. There are not many pulls to avoid, and you generally do not want to pull additional mobs off the main path. The main groups to avoid are the first packs of the dungeon, which can get dangerous if not interrupted. Use a speed boost and invisibility pot and go to the right, and you can get all the way to the first boss. On the gauntlet area with bats, the bats do not aggro unless DPSed. Focus on killing the demons. Using an invisibility potion on the stairs before the last boss can save time if you have somehow met the mob count. &lt;strong&gt;Fortified:&lt;/strong&gt; The packs leading up to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/npc=98696/illysanna-ravencrest&#34;&gt;Illysanna&lt;/a&gt; can be line-of-sight pulled behind pillars to group them up more easily. You may want to use some cooldowns or creature control on these packs. &lt;strong&gt;Tyrannical:&lt;/strong&gt; I try to avoid difficult levels of BRH on tyrannical. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/npc=94923/lord-kurtalos-ravencrest#encounter&#34;&gt;Lord Ravencrest&lt;/a&gt; casts &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/spell=202019/shadow-bolt-volley&#34;&gt;Shadow Bolt Volley&lt;/a&gt;, which on tyrannical can one-shot players without damage reduction cooldowns available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;court-of-stars&#34;&gt;Court of Stars&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Study &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/court-of-stars-dungeon-strategy-guide#class-profession-and-race-perks&#34;&gt;this wowhead map&lt;/a&gt;. Know at least the buffs you can trigger and ideally all buffs available so you can ask your party members if they have X profession to trigger Y buff. Seriously, go study the map right now. Throughout, kill all sentries before they activate a beacon. Interrupt Construct casts of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/spell=209413/suppress&#34;&gt;Suppress&lt;/a&gt;. Jump through the water to avoid the construct on the first bridge. Pull the mobs close to the water, and hug the right building. Don&amp;rsquo;t worry about disabling all the towers before &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/npc=104215&#34;&gt;Gerdo&lt;/a&gt;; even on Tyrannical, you should be able to kill the boss before the ads arrive. If you cannot, you are in for a rude awakening on the last boss. In the buffs area before the second boss, pull the patrolling imps before you pull other mobs and have the imps run into you. Avoid pulling extra &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/npc=104278&#34;&gt;Felbound Enforcers&lt;/a&gt; if you were able to distract one of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/npc=104217&#34;&gt;Talixae&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s guardians with the buff items. The damaging ability from Enforcers can be line-of-sighted around pillars as it casts to avoid all damage. This dungeon is won or lost in two places, generally. First, getting the buff items and guardians quickly. Second, in playing the &amp;ldquo;identify-the-demon&amp;rdquo; game before the third boss. Protection paladins should have a glowing shield near the right mob after all the gossip clues are gathered, and demon hunters should be able to see the right mob as well. After the miniboss, someone should start running to quickly click the final boss door. Once you learn how the dungeon works, it is pretty quick and easy at low Mythic+ levels. &lt;strong&gt;Fortified:&lt;/strong&gt; The enforcers and guardians are all strong as mini-bosses. Constructs hit rather hard as well. &lt;strong&gt;Tyrannical:&lt;/strong&gt; Having killed Melandrus on M+13 (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.twitch.tv/raphanw/v/100809759&#34;&gt;twitch video of the kill&lt;/a&gt;), I suspect most other dungeons are an easier path on Tyrannical weeks. Even with the nerf before patch 7.1.5, he can be a bit tricky. The boss&amp;rsquo;s soft-enrage gets more punishing with Tyrannical, and your DPS will need 300-400k dps, depending on the M+ level, to kill the boss before the unhealable 9/10th round of AOE damage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;darkheart-thicket&#34;&gt;Darkheart Thicket&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Early, you can go to the left and go through a keyhole to skip some mobs. Don&amp;rsquo;t do that. Instead, climb a rock to the left of the keyhole and skip even more mobs. If you have Sap or a similar effect, sap the dancing centaur to avoid the 5-mob pack after &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/npc=96512/archdruid-glaidalis&#34;&gt;Glaidalis&lt;/a&gt;. You can hex or roots it when it stops dancing as well if your group stays for to the right to avoid aggroing it. Skip the second big red dude before &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/npc=99200/dresaron&#34;&gt;Dresaron&lt;/a&gt;. If you get 100% mob completion before the last pack in the dungeon, you can corpse-run or invisibility potion through it. If you have not pulled any extra packs, though, you may need that pack for completion %. &lt;strong&gt;Fortified:&lt;/strong&gt; You need some creature control for the last packs in the dungeon. Double bear packs may need some cooldowns. &lt;strong&gt;Tyrannical:&lt;/strong&gt; Not too bad on tyrannical if your group is geared enough for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;eye-of-azshara&#34;&gt;Eye of Azshara&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many groups go to the left at the start to avoid mobs, then need additional mobs near the end of the dungeon. On easy affixes, I prefer going straight along the path to the first poss to minimize mobs later, as these mobs are packed tightly together and, if your group can interrupt, are not very challenging. After the first boss, kill the first &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/npc=97171/hatecoil-arcanist&#34;&gt;Hatecoil Arcanist&lt;/a&gt; on the path. Then turn off the path and go to the right, go across the water, skip all the trash, and pull the Arcanist to the left of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/npc=91789/lady-hatecoil&#34;&gt;Lady Hatecoil&lt;/a&gt;. Some groups like to kill the next boss before Hatecoil, but I prefer killing her first as the extra running wastes time. Kill at least 3 packs of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/npc=91793/seaspray-crab&#34;&gt;crabs&lt;/a&gt;, 3 &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/npc=91792/stormwake-hydra&#34;&gt;Stormwake Hydras&lt;/a&gt;, and 4 Mak&amp;rsquo;ranas before pulling &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/npc=91808/serpentrix&#34;&gt;Serpentrix&lt;/a&gt;. If your group has rotational AOE or can&amp;rsquo;t help themselves from pulling &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/npc=91787&#34;&gt;seagulls&lt;/a&gt;, you may wish to clear them as well. Pull 3-4 groups of crabs to the left and AOE them all down together to make up mob count, or plan on pulling extra giblins or murlocs later. Skip the giant at the start of the cave, but get both the murloc and giblin pack. Skip all the way to the two final giants. They should get you to 100%. If not, the murlocs to the left should do it. You can get the last 2% you need from the snail to the right of the 2nd-to-last boss if you have ranged. They can often kill it &amp;ldquo;for free&amp;rdquo; with DoT spells while your group focuses on the last boss. &lt;strong&gt;Fortified:&lt;/strong&gt; You may want to use heroism on the final two giants rather than on the last boss. &lt;strong&gt;Tyrannical:&lt;/strong&gt; The last boss is tough on Tyrannical. If the first boss feels difficult, consider whether your group has what it takes to do the last boss. There are easier dungeons on Tyrannical for sure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;halls-of-valor&#34;&gt;Halls of Valor&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the first boss, you can line-of-sight the patrols and mobs near the door outside of the building. This is recommended as it makes accidentally pulling a patrol much less likely. Go left to Hyrja and heroism on her, then go right to Fenryr. Depending on your gear and the Mythic+ level, you can do two or three rounds on the left side of Hyrja and possibly skip the right side all together. You only need to kill one mob (a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/npc=96611/angerhoof-bull&#34;&gt;Bull&lt;/a&gt;) before taking Fenryr from 100% to 60%. With sap you could skip it if you do not need it for completion percentage. You should only need to kill one pack of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/npc=96608&#34;&gt;Wolves&lt;/a&gt; before pulling Fenryr; just be careful to not pull an additional pack while fighting Fenryr. If you pull all the patrols as mentioned above, you do not need more mobs here for completion %. After Fenryr, you can use beer to sap the four mobs in the middle of the building and pull the two by the door into the area before the bridge. Once they are near dead, if you have DOTs on them, you can run up the bridge and they will follow. If you need to, finish them off in the final room before engaging the four kings there. I prefer using heroism on Skovald rather than Odyn. &lt;strong&gt;Fortified:&lt;/strong&gt; An even better reason not to pull extra animals near Fenryr. &lt;strong&gt;Tyrannical:&lt;/strong&gt; The bosses are hard but doable on Tyrannical. If you are confident your group can dodge orbs of light, consider using heroism on Fenryr instead of Hyrja, and possibly going to Fenryr first if you are going for a 3-chest clear&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;maw-of-souls&#34;&gt;Maw of Souls&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everyone&amp;rsquo;s favorite quick 3-boss dungeon. It&amp;rsquo;s one of the easiest, even at high levels. It is easy, short, and equally rewarding as the other dungeons? No wonder carry groups prefer Maw of Souls keys. The start of this dungeon is where you can really get ahead. With a low enough M+ and/or high enough gear, you can pull every single mob outside into the first boss and AOE them down while cleaving off the boss with heroism up. Make sure the tank is comfortable with having aggro before starting heroism and DPS. Go slower as needed, but get every single mob outside. Below decks, I like pulling the pack in the dead end to the right rather than more packs above decks. Above decks, pull two large mobs on both sides, then pull both packs at the end. Make sure not to miss interrupting fears or heals. &lt;strong&gt;Fortified:&lt;/strong&gt; Forget pulling everything into the first boss. You likely don&amp;rsquo;t want a second mariner below decks either since your healer will need to use cooldowns on the first one. Some patrolling dogs or additional mobs above decks can make up the %. Heroism on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/npc=99307/skjal&#34;&gt;Skjal&lt;/a&gt;, not Helya! &lt;strong&gt;Tyrannical:&lt;/strong&gt; Brave groups will still pull everything outside into the first boss. Consider using heroism on phase one of Helya to keep ahead of the tentacles; phase two is an endurance check with no enrage mechanic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;neltharions-lair&#34;&gt;Neltharion&amp;rsquo;s Lair&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pull everything at the start except &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/npc=91000/vileshard-hulk&#34;&gt;Vileshard Hulk&lt;/a&gt; in a big a pack as possible. Go left into the river then pull the three mobs right before the waterfall, killing them before jumping down. The healer should jump down early to star the dialog and restore their mana. At the base of the next waterfall, pull the two mobs to the right and have ranged DOT up and kill the drum. Once the drum dies, you may pull the drummer; without his drum he is a vanilla mob. Pull mobs on the right and the patrol before the drummer. Do not pull this drummer. Pelters sometimes stop throwing rocks if the tank gets aggro then kites them far away. This can be very useful for fortified or teeming groups of pelters. Pull the 2-pelter group, then the Hulk +1 group. Go up the ramp towards Ularogg, and pull every mob up there (not the one down in the cave to the right). After Ularogg, if you have 64%, walk by the snail race group (hug the wall closely; have a rogue sap for some breathing room) and the basilisks in the water. If you don&amp;rsquo;t, pull some of the basilisks to get you to 64% before engaging the first mobs in the worm area. Downstairs, you should need everything but the three mob group to the right. Unless you are feeling confident, Polymorph the mobs next to the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/npc=102295/emberhusk-dominator&#34;&gt;Scorpions&lt;/a&gt; and do the Scorpions one at a time. As far as I am concerned, Neltharion&amp;rsquo;s Lair is the second easiest dungeon after Maw of Souls. **Fortified: **Stun and use creature control on pelters; try not to fight more than one at a time. Use Grips or &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/spell=102793/ursols-vortex&#34;&gt;Ursol&amp;rsquo;s Vortex&lt;/a&gt; to make sure you can bring them back to the group. Chain stun the scorpions at the end and use defensive cooldowns. &lt;strong&gt;Tyrannical:&lt;/strong&gt; Nothing too hard here. Some groups like using heroism on Naraxas rather than the last boss.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-arcway&#34;&gt;The Arcway&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the first three globules, you can currently kill them then have everyone run outside and run back in. You get full % for the globules and the mini-globs disappear. It&amp;rsquo;s hard to write a pull suggestion for The Arcway, since which direction you go is based on what doors are open. If you go left first, make sure to jump down after Xakal to skip mobs. You generally want to also skip most of the mobs in the hallways closest to the central chamber, killing the mobs along the outside arc. Bring invisibility potions in case you are at full completion and need to get to the last boss. Skip the rats if possible. You can line-of-sight pull the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/npc=102351/mana-wyrm&#34;&gt;wyrms&lt;/a&gt; before &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/npc=98203/ivanyr&#34;&gt;Ivanyr&lt;/a&gt; to the hallway and behind the bridge. **Fortified: **The demon area to the left is hard without fortified and very hard with it. Use Sap to sneak by liberally. **Tyrannical: **This dungeon isn&amp;rsquo;t that bad on Tyrannical; the spider boss is probably the scariest (heroism helps) but it mostly just requires quick reaction speed to avoid deaths from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/spell=200227&#34;&gt;Tangled Web&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/spell=199811&#34;&gt;Blink Strikes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;vault-of-the-wardens&#34;&gt;Vault of the Wardens&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like Black Rock Hold, you want to take a normal-looking path in Vault, at least now that &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/item=109076/goblin-glider-kit&#34;&gt;Goblin Glider&lt;/a&gt; no longer is usable in Mythic+ dungeons. Pull all the mobs on one side in the start, up to and possibly including the miniboss. Pull all the mobs on one side, then all the mobs on the other side of the second staircase. Kill the mobs on your way to the first boss. Kill all the mobs in both hallways leading to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/npc=98533/foul-mother&#34;&gt;Foul Mother&lt;/a&gt;. Kill the mobs in front of Ash&amp;rsquo;Golm, kill him, run to Gazer, then run back out through Ash&amp;rsquo;Golm. Kill the mob towards the elevator. Run off the rock to the left to skip to some spiders. Run off again to more spiders. Kill mobs to get to 100% and beat up Cordana. Make sure to do both sides of the second staircase and foul mother in the beginning, or you will be short on mob count and need more spiders near the end. On easy affixes you can kill the mob in front of Gazer rather than running back out through Ash&amp;rsquo;Golm and skip some earlier mobs. &lt;strong&gt;Fortified:&lt;/strong&gt; You may want to use heroism on the first miniboss, depending on the other affixes and M+ level. &lt;strong&gt;Tyrannical:&lt;/strong&gt; You want heroism on the second boss and you want to get lucky and not get the Mogu. Pull the boss up to the ramp behind where he spawns and line-of-sight all the ads. Mogu you have to go down and kill, unfortunately. You might want to heroism right as the dungeon starts if it will take your group 10 minutes to get to the second boss.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;other-mythic-guides&#34;&gt;Other Mythic+ Guides&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following guides are other strong resources for Mythic+. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/wow/comments/56nedh/mythic_plus_tipsguide/&#34;&gt;https://www.reddit.com/r/wow/comments/56nedh/mythic_plus_tipsguide/&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/wow/comments/59328t/learning_pull_routes_in_mythic/d95d85r/&#34;&gt;https://www.reddit.com/r/wow/comments/59328t/learning_pull_routes_in_mythic/d95d85r/&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/mythic-keystones-and-dungeons-guide&#34;&gt;Wowhead guide&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://mythicpl.us/&#34;&gt;Mythicpl.us&lt;/a&gt; - shows weekly affixes, current rewards, and has a nifty calculator if you are shooting for 54 traits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;changelog&#34;&gt;Changelog&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2017-1-21: Comprehensive revision: Some route edits, reward changes with 7.1.5, class recommendation changes, new sections, other edits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope this guide was useful to you. If you have any suggestions or feedback, please let me know by commenting below or getting in touch with me. If you liked the guide, I would appreciate it if you shared it with your friends and guilds. Thank you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;comments&#34;&gt;Comments:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://coffeecakesandcrits.wordpress.com/&#34; title=&#34;wrathofkublakhan@yahoo.com&#34;&gt;wrathsome&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Nov 3, 2016&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Really nice guide, worth bookmarking for sure. What talents are you using for Druid healing and are they uniform for all runs? What are the expectations &amp;ndash; heavy tank healing, utility, speed &amp;hellip; Good article! Thank you.
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;heading-1&#34;&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;%22raphanwow@gmail.com%22&#34;&gt;Raphael&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Nov 4, 2016&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The talents section (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/restoration-druid-talent-guide&#34;&gt;http://www.wowhead.com/restoration-druid-talent-guide&lt;/a&gt;) of the Restoration Druid Guide (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/restoration-druid-guide&#34;&gt;http://www.wowhead.com/restoration-druid-guide&lt;/a&gt;) I link from the Class Guides Hub (&lt;a href=&#34;http://raidadvice.com/world-of-warcraft-legion-class-guides/&#34;&gt;http://raidadvice.com/world-of-warcraft-legion-class-guides/&lt;/a&gt;) is pretty solid. Generally, for hard Mythic+ content, I use 2/1/3/1/3/3/3 (Cenarion Ward, Renewal, Guardian Affinity, Mighty Bash, Cultivation, Germination, Flourish), but that varies depending on the dungeon, affix, and Mythic+ level. I usually Keep Cenarion Ward, Renewal, and Germination. I could write a whole post about Restoration Druid talents in Mythic+.
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;heading-2&#34;&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://coffeecakesandcrits.wordpress.com/&#34; title=&#34;wrathofkublakhan@yahoo.com&#34;&gt;wrathsome&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Nov 5, 2016&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I could write a whole post about Restoration Druid talents in Mythic+.&amp;rdquo; Please do.
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Use Wowprogress to Pick your Battles</title>
			<link>www.raidadvice.com/use-wowprogress-to-pick-your-battles/</link>
			<pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2016 06:10:55 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">www.raidadvice.com/use-wowprogress-to-pick-your-battles/</guid>
			<description>&lt;p&gt;My guild opted to spend tonight progressing on Mythic &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/npc=105393/ilgynoth&#34;&gt;Heart&lt;/a&gt; rather than entering Heroic &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/trial-of-valor&#34;&gt;Trial of Valor&lt;/a&gt;. I think this was a great decision. It was motivated in part by worth of mouth recounts, and in part by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowprogress.com/&#34;&gt;wowprogress&lt;/a&gt; results. Scroll to the bottom of the front page of wowprogress to see how many guilds have downed each boss in the current tier. On Tuesday, the first day Trials opened, less than 200 guilds had killed Heroic Odyn, the first boss of the instance. That&amp;rsquo;s less than half a percent of tracked guilds. Our average ilvl is around 875; spending a night wiping to a boss most guilds couldn&amp;rsquo;t kill in a night of raiding for gear with a base ilvl 10 below ours seemed like a poor investment. Yes, the new raid is exciting, and some of us will likely tackle normal on off nights. But with current tuning, getting in more attempts on Heart was a better idea than starting fresh on Odyn. Wowprogress helped guilds early in the tier too, and it can still help yours. For example, if deciding between Dragons and Heart, all else being equal you should choose Dragons first. Many more guilds have killed it. Check what more-progressed guilds have done and follow the path of least resistance. More often than not, it will be the best choice for your raid group.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Remember to Update Simulationcraft</title>
			<link>www.raidadvice.com/remember-to-update-simulationcraft/</link>
			<pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2016 05:57:59 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">www.raidadvice.com/remember-to-update-simulationcraft/</guid>
			<description>&lt;p&gt;Remember to keep &lt;a href=&#34;http://simulationcraft.org/download.html&#34;&gt;Simcraft updated&lt;/a&gt;! I got better gear and my simulated damage went down. I made sure to use the &lt;a href=&#34;https://mods.curse.com/addons/wow/simulationcraft&#34;&gt;Simulationcraft addon&lt;/a&gt; to import (apparently it can avoid glitches with importing from armory) and updated Simcraft. My simmed damage went up, which was as expected. Thanks to my Shammy buddy who suggested I try updating - it worked. Make sure to keep Simcraft up to date for accurate results.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>So Many Changes in Legion Patches 7.1, 7.1.5, and 7.2</title>
			<link>www.raidadvice.com/so-many-changes-in-legion-patches-7.1-7.1.5-and-7.2/</link>
			<pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2016 06:48:18 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">www.raidadvice.com/so-many-changes-in-legion-patches-7.1-7.1.5-and-7.2/</guid>
			<description>&lt;p&gt;There were a great deal of changes announced for 7.1.5 and 7.2 at Blizzcon this weekend. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/wow/comments/5b6juh/wow_legion_whats_next_summary/&#34;&gt;This Reddit post&lt;/a&gt; has a good summary. Blizzcon was great, but I am busy enjoying all the 7.1  changes! I haven&amp;rsquo;t been posting much because I haven&amp;rsquo;t wanted to take my free time away from playing to write guides in the detail that I have come to expect of myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;druid-changes&#34;&gt;Druid Changes&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;7.1 seemed in part to be a love letter to druids. Many of the changes I am really digging are druid specific:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Travel form travels almost as fast as mounts - it doesn&amp;rsquo;t benefit from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/achievement=11190/broken-isles-pathfinder-part-one&#34;&gt;Broken Isles Pathfinder&lt;/a&gt; but for short to medium distances it is nice to be able to use the class-fantasy-friendly method of traveling. Even for long travels, you can&amp;rsquo;t be dazed out of travel form, which is nice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Regrowth is baseline instead of Healing Touch - This makes Guardian Affinity a bit more appealing for raiding - you don&amp;rsquo;t need Restoration Affinity for access to a strong, fast heal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/spell=157228/owlkin-frenzy&#34;&gt;Owlkin Frenzy&lt;/a&gt; now empowers only Lunar Strike - it used to also work for Solar Wrath (or Stellar Flare). I made a weakaura to track the buff to make sure I only used it for Lunar Strike. While I was happy to optimize my play to get a minor edge over other Balance Druids, overall I enjoy not having to worry about that detail anymore.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Treant Form is always 5th stance &lt;strong&gt;after&lt;/strong&gt; Moonkin Form - it used to be 4th whenever you logged in or refreshed, and not having to switch specs and switch back to make it 4th form is a huge quality of life improvement - thanks Blizzard!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Manasaber and Manakitty form in Suramar - and you can be &amp;ldquo;disguised&amp;rdquo; as a bear too - you used to break stealth out of no stance or Balance form.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;other-changes&#34;&gt;Other Changes&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few of these were leading up to 7.1, most came in 7.1. And this isn&amp;rsquo;t even a full list. I have some gripes with the Legion design philosophy in general, but the changes for 7.1 were almost universally positive:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PvP is more rewarding now - See a &lt;a href=&#34;https://worldofwarcraft.com/en-us/news/20324477/pvp-rewards-in-patch-7-1&#34;&gt;full list here&lt;/a&gt;, the first skirmish win gives 100 base honor, for example. I&amp;rsquo;ve gotten back into arena for the first time since early Draenor. I&amp;rsquo;m much worse and more casual at it than raiding, but have enjoyed climbing past 1600 in 2s with a few different friends.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Karazhan is fun. I offspec heals (and do it pretty well; many of my M+10 clears are as a healer) and some guildies needed a healer, so I got luckily carried through a Nightbane run - and got &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/item=142552/smoldering-ember-wyrm&#34;&gt;the mount&lt;/a&gt; - and got a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/item=142166/ethereal-urn&#34;&gt;warforged 880 trinket&lt;/a&gt;. Good times. Kara was/seemed quite fun, I hope to go through it at a slightly slower pace soon.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I like the Falcosaurs. They look cool, the world quests are great for me as a skinner, and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/spell=230046/spiced-wildfowl-omelet&#34;&gt;the new Falcosaur dish&lt;/a&gt; is good for leveling cooking to 780. Now all I need is Nomi to give me a single rank-3 Delicacy recipe and I&amp;rsquo;m on my way to 800 (and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/guides/court-of-stars-dungeon-strategy-guide#class-profession-and-race-perks&#34;&gt;unlocking the Nightshare Refreshments in the Court of Stars&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The new &lt;a href=&#34;http://ptr.wowhead.com/spell=229217/potion-of-prolonged-power&#34;&gt;Potions of Prolonged Power&lt;/a&gt; are great. They are almost-but-not-quite as good as the more expensive potions for most specs. I bought several stacks of 100 to use freely in Mythic+ dungeons. I would buy them &lt;em&gt;en masse&lt;/em&gt; while you can before Alchemists run out of Blood of Sargeras.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Similarly, I am a fan of the Blood of Sargeras vendor in Dalaran - cheaper mats are great overall.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;World quest edits - the spawn rate or goals were slightly changed on a few world quests. Some were moved from a progress bar to objectives or vice versa. Every time I encountered this, it seemed like a good, well-reasoned decision. On a few, I had thought &amp;ldquo;the respawn timer on these mobs is a bit too slow&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;this should have/not have objectives&amp;rdquo; and Blizzard made that change - it was like they read my mind.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bumping the maximum baseline gear reward to 845 was appreciated as well - at 880 iLvL, it makes the chance that something will titanforge into something useful a tiny bit more realistic.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Slight dungeon edits, such as making the ground effect much more visible on the last boss of Halls of Valor or removing a few non-intuitive shortcuts. Bravo.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;coming-next&#34;&gt;Coming Next&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, what&amp;rsquo;s next for this site? The &lt;a href=&#34;http://raidadvice.com/withered-training-preparation-tips-and-tricks/&#34;&gt;Withered Training Guide&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://raidadvice.com/world-of-warcraft-legion-class-guides/&#34;&gt;Legion Class Guides Hub&lt;/a&gt; are getting tons of hits, and many of you check here every day or every few days hoping to see something new. I want to focus on three things:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A few more detailed guides;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;when I have an idea that isn&amp;rsquo;t a big, detailed guide, post it as a quick, short post while it&amp;rsquo;s relevant, and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;see if I can find a theme that organizes the content here a bit better than chronologically. In my head I imagine using something with a front page of resources and &amp;ldquo;top posts&amp;rdquo; as well as a list of recent posts. I like blogs that give the first few hundred words than you have to click for more detail - I think that right now the site is a bit hard to digest with long, full posts on the front page. I also think I can utilize categories better to make finding relevant old posts more manageable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a ton of ideas for possible posts; it&amp;rsquo;s just setting the time aside to write them. Here are a few of my ideas:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I have the bones of a detailed guide to log analysis post done, but I want to brush that up before releasing it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After that&amp;rsquo;s posted, maybe doing friend/reader log analysis (in some ways it&amp;rsquo;s much easier to analyze someone else&amp;rsquo;s play and be more objective).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sharing my weakauras,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Discussing the design philosophy of Myhic+&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Discussing the design philosophy of Legendary items in Legion and options going forward.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shoulder enchant options in Legion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why parsing doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter, except when it does&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mythic+ thoughts and guide compilation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Emerald Nightmare and Halls of Valor Guides compilation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to Track Hidden Appearance Progression&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Making a UI Revisited&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Where to focus: what is the best way to gear up outside of raiding.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are you enjoying in 7.1 or looking forward to in 7.2? Do any of the above ideas spark your interest, or is there something you want a guide for? Best of luck in Halls of Valor this week!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;comments&#34;&gt;Comments:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://coffeecakesandcrits.wordpress.com/&#34; title=&#34;wrathofkublakhan@yahoo.com&#34;&gt;wrathsome&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Nov 2, 2016&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since you asked, I think making the strong but older posts float up on the top page would be good. A lot of bloggers feel that &amp;ldquo;once written done&amp;rdquo; and hope that searches will find the post rather than the blog itself being the hub. Defining yourself as a blogger is like writing a mission statement which is kind of goofy because of what the mechanics of a blog are to use; meaning newest is top rather than strongest or topical. From your blog, I want Raid Advice; from solutions to tips to tricks to conceptual approach (your to-do list that you posted). Grats on Kara.
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>How to Find a New Guild - A Guide and Case Study</title>
			<link>www.raidadvice.com/how-to-find-a-new-guild-a-guide-and-case-study/</link>
			<pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2016 03:59:59 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">www.raidadvice.com/how-to-find-a-new-guild-a-guide-and-case-study/</guid>
			<description>&lt;p&gt;Regular readers may have noticed the dearth of posts the past few weeks. In that time, I searched for and found a new guild: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.seppukustormrage.shivtr.com/&#34;&gt;Seppuku&lt;/a&gt;, a 3/7 M 2-night guild on US-Stormrage. As of this posting, the guild is looking for a few more ranged DPS, hoping to round out the roster to 24-25 raiders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;why-find-a-new-guild&#34;&gt;Why find a new guild?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are happy in your current guild, you should strongly consider staying there. Changing guilds, especially if it involves paying real life money for a server transfer, brings with it some risk and uncertainty. Have a specific reason why you need to look for a new guild. I was very happy with my past guild (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dinosaurcowboys.net/&#34;&gt;Dinosaur Cowboys&lt;/a&gt;, a 4/7 M 2-night guild on US-Sargeras), except for one thing. It was located on &amp;ldquo;my&amp;rdquo; alliance server where I had over one million gold and 12 90+ alliance toons. It raided 2 weeknights, which is ideal for me right now. It had a great atmosphere, a long history, and a positive raiding environment. It was well organized, and I liked the people. The only problem was that the guild didn&amp;rsquo;t think it needed me. It had 36+ players step into the raid in the first three weeks of mythic, and outside of the dozen or so &amp;ldquo;core&amp;rdquo; members who were getting nearly 100% time, playing time was pretty sparse. I was only seeing about 25% of the mythic pulls. I am fine with sitting some, but 3/4 of the time was far too much. On the week before I left, I saw 0 of the guild&amp;rsquo;s 3 mythic farm kills and did not get in at all on the second raid night. I had raised the issue with the officers after the first week and hadn&amp;rsquo;t seen much improvement in play time. I was on the fence about leaving because the guild was otherwise a perfect fit, but sitting for the entire night as multiple players were rotated in made it clear to me that I had to leave. The guild is progressing well through The Emerald Nightmare with their current roster management system, so even though I was the only balance druid and performing well, there&amp;rsquo;s a sense in which they really &lt;em&gt;don&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/em&gt; need me. I think that my dedication and my performance (e.g., my &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.warcraftlogs.com/reports/mYBp6qRfvP4ZA81G#fight=15&amp;amp;type=damage-done&#34;&gt;most recent mythic Ursoc kill&lt;/a&gt;, on Raphkin, vs &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.warcraftlogs.com/reports/M7GV6XFbzNpZwQ8g#fight=13&amp;amp;type=damage-done&#34;&gt;theirs&lt;/a&gt;) indicated I could have helped push progression there, but ultimately I wasn&amp;rsquo;t getting the chance to prove it. I enjoyed leveling up and doing mythic+s with them, I made a few friends, and I got some good raid time and logs in on heroic (where I was never sat). I enjoyed my time there and left at the right time. I wish them well, and might consider playing with them again under the right circumstances. I wish I hadn&amp;rsquo;t had to leave, as I had seen the guild as a potentially permanent home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-to-select-a-new-guild---your-requirements-and-application&#34;&gt;How to Select a New Guild - Your Requirements and Application&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alright, so I had a clear reason for leaving and decided to leave. What was I looking for in a guild and what did I bring to the table? Put effort into figuring this out and creating the outline of your application! I&amp;rsquo;m going to copy/paste my guild &amp;ldquo;Looking for Guild&amp;rdquo; post below to show you what I went with. Ultimately, this part is up to you - what exactly are you looking for, and what can the guild expect from you? Even if you don&amp;rsquo;t post it publicly, spending some time thinking about what you want in a guild is important. A trap players sometimes fall into is always wanting a more progressed guild. Faster progression is great, but only if you have the skill and commitment to be a consistent player there. Also, if you are happy in a guild doing heroic, think hard about whether mythic is right for you. Mythic likely involves some bench time, and while I am fine with a bit of bench time, some players aren&amp;rsquo;t. My &lt;a href=&#34;http://us.battle.net/forums/en/wow/topic/20749806292?page=1&#34;&gt;post&lt;/a&gt;, which I used as an application template:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;General:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Btag: Raphael#1142.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Current WoW Character: (Character name and url of armory).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Raiding Spec: Balance Druid (27 AP, 871 ilvl).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Offspecs: Restoration Druid (16 AP), Guardian Druid (13 AP).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Emerald Nightmare Raiding Progress: 7/7H First week, 1 Mythic Nythendra kill, Multiple pulls on 4 mythic bosses.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;_UI: (&lt;a href=&#34;http://imgur.com/kpCBygw)._&#34;&gt;http://imgur.com/kpCBygw)._&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Heroic Kill Logs: Best are all 90+% (url of logs).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;On my one mythic Nythendra kill I died to slow ticking damage from Rot while receiving little healing, with Barkskin on cooldown from a previous Rot.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;I welcome you to examine my mythic progression logs (link to logs), I&amp;rsquo;ve done great on mechanics and DPS when in.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mythic+ Progression: Three weeks of M+10 completed, hope to continue that streak.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About me:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;I play WoW because I enjoy playing Mythic Progression. I simcraft my class, read and participate in Balance Druid theorycrafting (checkmywow.com Balance profile is based partly on my suggestions), make and use weakauras.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;I optimize my gear and consumables (best enchants, gems, crafted gear, pots, flasks, vantus runes and runes as applicable).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;I am dedicated: I do most AP and gear world quests, I have 100% attendance in Legion and historically 95+% attendance, I research and contribute to strategies on guild forums, I speak up and contribute to a positive atmosphere.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;I maintain a class guides compilation and blog about Warcraft/raiding with 20,000+ monthly views.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;_T18 on Holy Paladin (Anphar-Sargeras), US 167 M Archimonde, as healing officer and later GM of the no-longer-raiding 2-day guild &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowprogress.com/guild/us/sargeras/Cake+Plantation/rating.tier18)._&#34;&gt;http://www.wowprogress.com/guild/us/sargeras/Cake+Plantation/rating.tier18)._&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;_T17 on Balance Druid (Eenheid-Aerie Peak), in &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&#39;s 2-day raid team in Tier 17 (I finished tier 8/10 M; weekend team would have been around US 375 if apart from the US 90 weekday raid) (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowprogress.com/guild/us/aerie-peak/Alone/rating.tier17)._&#34;&gt;http://www.wowprogress.com/guild/us/aerie-peak/Alone/rating.tier17)._&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hard requirements of what I am looking for in a guild:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Reasonable playing time. I am fine with sitting occasionally as needed, but I am not interested in a bench/backup position. My ideal guild specifically needs ranged DPS.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;No racism/no slurs/no excessive vulgarity.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;A guild that raids 10.5 hours per week or less, 2 or 3 nights per week, between 6-12 pm EST and does not raid on Friday or Saturday. No &amp;ldquo;optional&amp;rdquo; heroic clear on a 4th day.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;9 hours per week or less is better, 2 nights per week is better, 7-11 pm EST is better.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Well-defined new member/&amp;ldquo;trial&amp;rdquo; period; feedback if you want players to make adjustments, especially when asked.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Actively progressing in mythic, not &amp;ldquo;we need just a few more to do mythic.&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Very-nice-to-haves:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Guild is (my Current Faction); on (my Current Server).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Active, friendly guild outside of raid times, people doing M+s and PvP.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Strong guild history prior to Legion.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;In the US 100-300 progression range currently and/or in past raids.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thanks for reading. Respond here and/or add me on BTAG if interested.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-to-finda-new-guild--the-search&#34;&gt;How to Find a New Guild - The Search&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alright, so you know what you want and are ready to apply? How do you find the guild that&amp;rsquo;s right for you? I asked a few friends, and got great advice from one in particular. Here&amp;rsquo;s what I recommend, in rough order.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you know friends in a guild that would be a good fit for you, reach out to them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make a post on the official LFG forums; if a guild posts something specific there &lt;strong&gt;and&lt;/strong&gt; contacts you, you know that you might be a good fit for them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scan wowprogress for guilds meeting your criteria.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scan the LFG forums for guilds meeting your criteria.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make posts on other sites and forums, or scan posts on other sites and forums.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make a text file or spreadhseet with your top choices and guilds that contact you. Record the URL of your application, BTAG of anyone that contacted you, and your application status. Especially early in an expansion, you may get a lot of interest, and it can be hard to keep track of unless you have a system for doing so. I ended up applying to about 10 guilds, some of which contacted me, some I found on wowprogress, and some I saw on the LFG forums. I was BTAG added by another 10-20 guilds that I did not end up applying to. Most of my wow friends were in guilds that would not be a good fit for me, unfortunately, failing to meet one or more of my hard requirements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-results&#34;&gt;The Results&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was only declined from one guild that told me that they did not like my performance. I was declined from a few more that said I had a strong app but were hesitant to add a third or fourth Balance Druid. I was also BTAG added by a few US top 100 guilds that wondered whether I might stretch my 10.5 hour maximum raid hours per week requirement, which was a nice ego boost. I was tempted, since raiding with stronger players is generally more fun for me, but ultimately I set my time requirements for a reason. In the end, I had several great choices to pick from. I first eliminated the 3-day guilds, since I would prefer not to commit three nights a week to raiding right now and I had some strong 2-day choices. I also eliminated a few horde guilds, since they were not obviously better choices than the remaining alliance guilds and, all things being equal, I would rather not pay for a faction change. The last few were very hard, all alliance guilds that raid during the times I want to and seeming to have great atmospheres. I ultimately decided to trial with Seppuku. I am only one week in, but I am optimistic about my future here. The core of the guild is very strong, and I enjoy raiding with the incredibly proficient other balance druid (who is also GM/raid leader!). Look out for a logs comparison post in the very near future. I have enjoyed doing M+s and chatting with the guild members outside of raid times as well. Changing guilds directly addressed the issue I had with my former guild: I went from being in on 25% of mythic pulls, 1 mythic kill, and 0 first kills over three weeks to being in on 100% of the pulls, 3 mythic kills, and 1 first kill in my first week there. And, I was promoted to Raider after one week. If you want to check out a few other resources on finding guilds, I list a few on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://raidadvice.com/general-raiding-guides/#Getting_in_a_Guild&#34;&gt;General Raiding Guides&lt;/a&gt; page. I hope that I do not find myself looking for another guild any time soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;comments&#34;&gt;Comments:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://coffeecakesandcrits.wordpress.com/&#34; title=&#34;wrathofkublakhan@yahoo.com&#34;&gt;wrathsome&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Oct 1, 2016&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is one helluva journey and grats on the arrival to a new place to play. Fresh personalities can be really great and I am sure you will fit in. In life, in game and even in animals; there is a &amp;ldquo;pecking order&amp;rdquo; for any group &amp;ndash; just assume that you are the bottom for now! The tendency to try to assert and prove yourself to move up in their eyes can be hard to manage. Good luck, I anticipate some fun progress posts in the coming months.
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Mount Macros Revisited</title>
			<link>www.raidadvice.com/mount-macros-revisited/</link>
			<pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2016 01:58:16 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">www.raidadvice.com/mount-macros-revisited/</guid>
			<description>&lt;p&gt;A &lt;a href=&#34;https://coffeecakesandcrits.wordpress.com/2016/10/01/mount-macros/&#34;&gt;post over at Coffee Cakes and Crits&lt;/a&gt; showed a creative way to incorporate toys and pets into your mount macro. Fun times. I also discovered recently that Blizzard has updated it&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Favorite Mount&amp;rdquo; logic, so you will cast a mount with a ground animation when in non-flying zones and a mount that can fly in flying zones. It seems like they did this on a pretty smart per mount basis - &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/item=33999/cenarion-war-hippogryph&#34;&gt;Cenarion War Hippogryph&lt;/a&gt; has a goofy run animation with its wings so it casts only in flying zones, but &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/item=89363/disc-of-the-red-flying-cloud&#34;&gt;Red Flying Cloud&lt;/a&gt; looks nifty on the ground and it casts in both. All ground-only mounts will cast in only nonflying areas. So, I have made a revision to my mount macro &lt;a href=&#34;http://raidadvice.com/mount-up-and-do-mythics/&#34;&gt;since I last shared it&lt;/a&gt;. Here it is: &lt;code&gt;/dismount /cast Archmage Vargoth&#39;s Spare Staff /rfp /castrandom [mod:alt]Azure Water Strider, Crimson Water Strider /cast [mod:shift]Grand Expedition Yak;[mod:ctrl]X-53 Touring Rocket /cancelform [stance:1/2] /run C_MountJournal.SummonByID(0)&lt;/code&gt; As noted by &lt;a href=&#34;https://coffeecakesandcrits.wordpress.com/author/wrathofkublakhan/&#34;&gt;wrathofkublakhan&lt;/a&gt;, /rfp summons a random favorite pet. Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Learn from Logs: Picking the Top Talents</title>
			<link>www.raidadvice.com/learn-from-logs-picking-the-top-talents/</link>
			<pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2016 00:54:50 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">www.raidadvice.com/learn-from-logs-picking-the-top-talents/</guid>
			<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://raidadvice.com/world-of-warcraft-legion-class-guides/&#34;&gt;Class Guides&lt;/a&gt; are great, but logs can be even better in some areas. Guides are a prediction of what will be best for each class, whereas logs tell you exactly what worked. I plan to write a few posts about using logs to improve your play. Today, we&amp;rsquo;ll look at selecting the right talents for your class and spec based on logs. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.warcraftlogs.com/&#34;&gt;Warcraftlogs&lt;/a&gt; has a great rankings feature that lets you examine at a glance what talents the highest ranking players in your class are using. Click on the menu button to the top left, and click on rankings next to the current raid. Select the boss, difficulty, and class you are interested in. As an example, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.warcraftlogs.com/rankings/10#boss=1853&amp;amp;difficulty=4&amp;amp;class=Druid&amp;amp;spec=Balance&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; are the top performances for Balance Druids on Heroic Nythendra. At the top, the site lists the top talents and trinkets for that boss. Along the side, you can see if any players near the top diverted from these talents or trinkets. For Balance druids, literally everyone in the top 100 uses &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/spell=202345/starlord&#34;&gt;Starlord&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/spell=102560/incarnation-chosen-of-elune&#34;&gt;Incarnation&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/spell=202360/blessing-of-the-ancients&#34;&gt;Blessing of the Ancients&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/spell=202430/natures-balance&#34;&gt;Nature&amp;rsquo;s Balance&lt;/a&gt;. Even, as an observer who knows nothing about the class, you can guess that those talents are the top DPS talents for Nythendra. If a Balance druid isn&amp;rsquo;t using those talents on the fight in your raid, you might wonder why. Another &amp;ldquo;top talent&amp;rdquo; is &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/spell=197491/guardian-affinity&#34;&gt;Guardian Affinity&lt;/a&gt;. Unlike the four mentioned above, however, many druids in the top 100 are using another choice - &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/spell=197492/restoration-affinity&#34;&gt;Restoration Affinity&lt;/a&gt;. This suggests that there isn&amp;rsquo;t a clear consensus between the two talents for top DPS or utility. Try looking at the top talents for each fight for your spec - hopefully you aren&amp;rsquo;t surprised by what you find.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;comments&#34;&gt;Comments:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://coffeecakesandcrits.wordpress.com/&#34; title=&#34;wrathofkublakhan@yahoo.com&#34;&gt;wrathsome&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Oct 2, 2016&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is cool. Yes, I was surprised that there is some consensus but not for all. I also see different results for different bosses and I wonder if that suggests that players are changing Talents for each fight. I&amp;rsquo;m not entirely clear on &amp;ldquo;top healer ranking&amp;rdquo; therein wondering if this is the highest overall healing-per-second. Kind of like when you look at DPS charts via Recount (or Details) in the LFR and see a super high number and realize that the player was spamming the boss and ignoring the adds &amp;ndash; naturally you&amp;rsquo;d not see this in a heroic raid fight. Healers can pad meters too but that is another topic, I think! Very cool, thanks for the explanation &amp;ndash; I spent quite some time mulling over those charts!
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Get Two Mythic&#43; Keystones Each Week</title>
			<link>www.raidadvice.com/get-two-mythic-keystones-each-week/</link>
			<pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2016 06:40:20 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">www.raidadvice.com/get-two-mythic-keystones-each-week/</guid>
			<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EDIT 2016-10-5: This has been patched out. If I had known for sure that it would be, I could have skipped writing this post.&lt;/strong&gt; Each week, if you completed a Mythic+ dungeon the previous week, you will get a chest in your order hall containing a piece of gear corresponding to the highest Mythic+ dungeon you beat as well as a Mythic+ keystone 2 levels lower than your previous week&amp;rsquo;s keystone. If you don&amp;rsquo;t have a Mythic+ keystone, you can get a +2 keystone by completing any Mythic or Mythic+ dungeon. A few sources have reported to me that, as of this week, you could combine these two options. If you waited to open your chest until you did a Mythic dungeon, getting the +2 keystone, you would get both that +2 keystone and the Mythic+ keystone 2 levels below your previous week&amp;rsquo;s keystone. It&amp;rsquo;s not clear whether this is an intentional feature or a bug that will be patched out. If you want to try your luck at getting a second keystone, this might be something you want to look into more. If it&amp;rsquo;s a bug rather than an intended feature, you probably want to avoid using it just to be safe.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Fishbrul Special</title>
			<link>www.raidadvice.com/fishbrul-special/</link>
			<pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2016 06:29:45 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">www.raidadvice.com/fishbrul-special/</guid>
			<description>&lt;p&gt;If you play a DPS class, before raid today, you might want to look into whether you are eating the right food. It could be &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/spell=201511/fishbrul-special&#34;&gt;Fishbrul Special&lt;/a&gt;. Back in Draenor, Blizzard introduced &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/item=127991/felmouth-frenzy&#34;&gt;Felmouth Frenzy&lt;/a&gt;. This food did direct damage to your target rather than improving a stat. This type of food is back in Legion with several varieties. From least to most potent: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/spell=201499/spiced-rib-roast&#34;&gt;Spiced Rib Roast&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/spell=201504/drogbar-style-salmon&#34;&gt;Drogbar Style Salmon&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/spell=201511/fishbrul-special&#34;&gt;Fishbrul Special&lt;/a&gt;. For many classes, for single target DPS fights, Fishbrul Special is going to be the winner. If you aren&amp;rsquo;t sure, ask friends or just Simcraft it yourself. For an introduction to Simcraft, see the link on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://raidadvice.com/general-raiding-guides/&#34;&gt;General Raiding Guides&lt;/a&gt; page. One you have your simulate profile set up and simmed with stat food, replace the food line and simulate again with Fishbrul Special. For Balance Druid, I simulated two profiles, one with the first line and one with the second: &lt;code&gt;actions.precombat+=/food,type=azshari_salad actions.precombat+=/food,type=fishbrul_special&lt;/code&gt; For me, Fishbrul Special comes out slightly ahead with current gear (it was about even last week!), giving about a 0.7% DPS increase over haste food. Don&amp;rsquo;t miss out on DPS before you even enter the instance - make sure to eat the right food!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Innervate, a Raid Cooldown</title>
			<link>www.raidadvice.com/innervate-a-raid-cooldown/</link>
			<pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2016 07:12:51 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">www.raidadvice.com/innervate-a-raid-cooldown/</guid>
			<description>&lt;p&gt;In Legion, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/spell=29166/innervate&#34;&gt;Innervate&lt;/a&gt; is back for Restoration and Balance Druids. Unlike previous versions, this one does not restore mana. It gives 10 seconds of no-mana-usage-casting to the healer it is cast upon. And yes, it is restricted to healers this time around. The Balance Druid version also gives increased haste to the healer it is cast on for the duration with the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/spell=202890/rapid-innervation&#34;&gt;Rapid Innervation&lt;/a&gt; artifact trait. As a Balance Druid, I picked up that trait as my 24th trait, and many Balance Druids should be getting access to it in the near future. Every healer should have some sort of weakaura for tracking Innervate. I made &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.weakauras.online/en/a/8mV9NVM9zk&#34;&gt;this very simple one&lt;/a&gt; that will allow healers to notice when Innervate is cast on them and react accordingly. If used properly in a coordinated group, Innervate can function as a significant raid healing cooldown, allowing certain classes to cast major burst heals that they otherwise could not possibly afford.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;who-should-innervate-be-cast-on&#34;&gt;Who Should Innervate be Cast on?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TL;DR: Disc &amp;raquo; Monk &amp;gt; Shaman &amp;gt;= Holy Priest &amp;raquo; Druid &amp;gt;= Paladin.&lt;/strong&gt; Discipline priests, if you have one in your raid, probably have the most to gain from Innervate, being able to spam otherwise prohibitively expensive spells or being able to spread Atonement to more players when it is usually mana prohibitive to do so. Discipline priests already have a high skill cap, however, and it can be easy for a Discipline Priest to waste Innervate if they do not prepare for it. If you want to cast Innervate on a Discipline priest, they should probably tell you when they are ready for it. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/CompetitiveWoW/comments/53e630/healers_and_innervate/&#34;&gt;This thread on Reddit&lt;/a&gt; a few weeks ago had some good discussion about the cooldown. Using the napkin math there, on a Monk, this has the potential to heal for 3.4 million damage in 10 seconds for no mana cost. Shamans and Holy Priests probably do not get quite the same benefit, but can also use it very effectively. Restoration Druids, though they have the spell in their spell book and may be tempted to cast it on themselves, do not have great mana dumps to benefit from it. Holy paladins similarly do not get great value out of the spell. For reference, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/spell=740/tranquility&#34;&gt;Tranquility&lt;/a&gt;, sometimes considered the best raid healing cooldown, might heal about 7.2 million over 6 seconds. But, unlike Innervate-powered healing, Tranquility is not targeted and thus will likely result in substantial overhealing in many situations. Innervate powered-healing often will allow the healer to target specific players or clusters of players to minimize the overhealing done, sometimes resulting in a raid cooldown more effective than Tranquility. Restoration Druids may object to &amp;ldquo;their cooldown&amp;rdquo; being used on other healers, but more likely than not that is best for the raid if used in a coordinated manner. Now, to be clear, in a PUG environment or an environment where the other healers do not track Innervate, keeping Innervate for yourself might be the right move as a Restoration Druid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-should-innervate-be-used&#34;&gt;How Should Innervate be used?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ideally Innervate should be pre-planned and/or called for just like a good tank calls for externals to be used on them. I advocate for a mix of both - plan out Innervate usage based on mechanics, and have the healer it is assigned to call for it exactly when they are ready. As alluded to above, it should be used in high damage situations, and the healer it is cast on should spam their highest healing per second spells during it, regardless of mana cost (since the cost is free during Innervate). Each healer should figured out for themselves what the rotation is - most classes have some discussion on what that should be in the Reddit thread above. Healers who want to call for Innervate and are new to tracking other players spells have many options for tracking when Innervate is available. One good one is using &lt;a href=&#34;https://mods.curse.com/addons/wow/exorsus-raid-tools&#34;&gt;Exorsus Raid Tools&lt;/a&gt;. Many guilds will already require their raiders to have this addon installed, and it has a raid cooldown module. Simply select Innervate as the only spell you want to track and position the module where you want it on your screen. When you might want Innervate, spot the player(s) who have it off cooldown and call for it to be used on you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-reward&#34;&gt;The Reward&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why go through all this effort? Because the benefit nets you an extra raid cooldown that can be similar in value to a major healing cooldown like &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/spell=740/tranquility&#34;&gt;Tranquility&lt;/a&gt;, whereas right now your raid might be getting the equivalent of an extra &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/item=127835/ancient-mana-potion&#34;&gt;Ancient Mana Potion&lt;/a&gt; for a Restoration Druid. Having Restoration Druids just cast Innervate on themselves or telling a Restoration/Balance Druid to just cast it on cooldown on a certain player is a big waste in healing potential, especially if the healer it is cast on does not track it and react accordingly. A small bit of effort can optimize Innervate usage in your raid for a great deal of benefit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;comments&#34;&gt;Comments:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;%22raphanwow@gmail.com%22&#34;&gt;Raphael&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Oct 1, 2016&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to Jeathebelle of &lt;a href=&#34;https://sacredshielding.wordpress.com/&#34;&gt;https://sacredshielding.wordpress.com/&lt;/a&gt; for discussing this concept, including the rough ranking of healers to use Innervate on, with me.
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;heading-1&#34;&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;%22raphanwow@gmail.com%22&#34;&gt;Raphael&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Feb 1, 2017&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More Reddit Innervate discussion: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/CompetitiveWoW/comments/5u3hyx/who&#34;&gt;https://www.reddit.com/r/CompetitiveWoW/comments/5u3hyx/who&lt;/a&gt;_should_take_innervate_and_wisdom_in_raids/
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>How to Target Specific Recipes from Nomi</title>
			<link>www.raidadvice.com/how-to-target-specific-recipes-from-nomi/</link>
			<pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2016 06:23:36 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">www.raidadvice.com/how-to-target-specific-recipes-from-nomi/</guid>
			<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mods.curse.com/addons/wow/nomicakes&#34;&gt;Nomicakes&lt;/a&gt;: This addon will show you what Cooking recipes can be gained from which materials you give to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/npc=64337/nomi&#34;&gt;Nomi&lt;/a&gt; in Dalaran. Simply give as many materials as you can for the recipe(s) you are targeting, and Nomi has a chance of teaching you those recipe(s). Aside from that, all we know is that it&amp;rsquo;s a grind and a low chance per batch of materials at this point. Best of luck to you, may Nomi&amp;rsquo;s odds be ever in your favor!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>RaidAdvice Roster System Tier 19</title>
			<link>www.raidadvice.com/raidadvice-roster-system-tier-19/</link>
			<pubDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2016 23:48:09 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">www.raidadvice.com/raidadvice-roster-system-tier-19/</guid>
			<description>&lt;p&gt;Are you an officer in your mythic raiding Warcraft guild? Do you have a hard time setting the 20-person roster for each encounter, figuring out who should come in if a replacement is needed, or making sure that each player gets their fair share of playing time? If so, you&amp;rsquo;ve come to the right place. In Tier 18, I designed a roster system based on &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/14ODJNjDg7kgc0PkKU1qt7AndAiXT1eaOedxH3RiOVXw&#34;&gt;this Google Sheet&lt;/a&gt;. It integrates with Discord and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.weakauras.online/en/a/kj6ZrDl928&#34;&gt;this Weakaura&lt;/a&gt; a friend made. It automatically generates a list of who you have scheduled for each boss, and which players to swap in and out. I have updated it for Legion for your use. [toc]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;getting-the-sheet&#34;&gt;Getting the Sheet&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/14ODJNjDg7kgc0PkKU1qt7AndAiXT1eaOedxH3RiOVXw&#34;&gt;the Google Sheet&lt;/a&gt;. Click on File, Make a Copy, so you have your own version to edit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;preparing-for-raid&#34;&gt;Preparing for Raid&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Sheet is easy and fairly self-explanatory. Fill in the player&amp;rsquo;s names, classes, Battle Tags, and Discord IDs if you use discord. Then, when you are ready for fill in names for your first week of raiding, click the triangle next to &amp;ldquo;Weekly Template&amp;rdquo; at the bottom, and click Duplicate. Double click on &amp;ldquo;Copy of Weekly Template&amp;rdquo; to rename it to the week of your raid, such as &amp;ldquo;2016-09-27.&amp;rdquo; Change the first line of the sheet to remind you that it is for a certain week. Each week, keep making copies of the weekly template, and save the lists from past weeks to have a record of who you wanted to bring. For each encounter, place a 1 next to players you want in, and 2-5 for backups in order of preference. For each mythic boss, you should have 20 players in. Then, if necessary, update the boss order at the bottom of the sheet. If you are skipping a boss, simply place the number at the end and adjust the other numbers accordingly. If you are completing the bosses in the order listed, no adjustment is necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;on-raid-night&#34;&gt;On Raid Night&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s where the magic comes in! Via a bit of creative Sheet functions, the lines at the bottom indicating which players are in and our update automatically. Now, before raid night, or before each encounter, you can copy the lines at the bottom listing which players will be in for the fight. You can paste them on your forums or into chat in Mumble or Discord. After each boss, you can copy/paste the IN/OUT list. If you use Discord, this will ping the players coming IN to get their attention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;integrated-weakaura&#34;&gt;Integrated Weakaura&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If that wasn&amp;rsquo;t exciting enough, my buddy (who wishes to remain anonymous) created &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.weakauras.online/en/a/kj6ZrDl928&#34;&gt;this Weakaura&lt;/a&gt; for officers who manage the sit list to use. Copy/paste the list of players you want in for a boss into officer chat that is generated by the spreadsheet (including the boss name and asterisks), and every officer with the Weakaura will be told which players to bring in and out. To clear the instructions, type /wa in chat to bring up your Weakaura menu or complete the roster swaps as instructed. A few notes about the Weakaura:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;While this sheet can be used with Normal/Heroic groups, the Weakaura is hard-coded for 20-person mythic, with groups 1-4 being &amp;ldquo;in&amp;rdquo; and 5-8 being &amp;ldquo;out.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If your raiders have above-average name lengths, you will not be able to copy in the name of every raider into a single chat line. Copy as many names as you can, and figure out the remaining raiders without using the Weakaura. If you have an idea of how to edit the Weakaura to fix this, do so and let me know about it! I have no custom LUA experience, and my buddy has moved on to another guild and may not have the time to come up with a fix. One solution would be to use the first 5 characters in each player&amp;rsquo;s name, but that could cause problems if a guild has two similarly named players.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As noted, my buddy may not have much time to work on the Weakaura, and I do not have experience with custom LUA Weakauras. If you see a problem, I would love to know about it, but I very well may not be able to get it fixed. I welcome you to make the fix and have me integrate your improvement into the Weakaura.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s it. I hope this system helps you as much as it helped me in managing a roster. Good luck with The Emerald Nightmare and The Nighthold!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Balance Druid Gear Spreadsheet for The Emerald Nightmare</title>
			<link>www.raidadvice.com/balance-druid-gear-spreadsheet-for-the-emerald-nightmare/</link>
			<pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2016 15:23:07 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">www.raidadvice.com/balance-druid-gear-spreadsheet-for-the-emerald-nightmare/</guid>
			<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EDIT 2017-1-18:&lt;/strong&gt; Check out the 7.1.5 &lt;a href=&#34;http://raidadvice.com/balance-druid-gear-spreadsheets-for-nighthold/&#34;&gt;Gear Spreadsheets for Nighthold&lt;/a&gt;. As I discussed in my prior post about &lt;a href=&#34;http://raidadvice.com/preparing-for-the-emerald-nightmare/&#34;&gt;Preparing for The Emerald Nightmare&lt;/a&gt;, it can be useful, &lt;em&gt;after you have done all your other prep&lt;/em&gt;, to figure out what gear you should be targeting in the instance. For reference, &lt;a href=&#34;http://imgur.com/a/J7s7r&#34;&gt;here is my gear as of last night&lt;/a&gt;. I created a spreadsheet, outlining the possible upgrades in the Emerald Nightmare for my class and spec. If you are a Balance Druid that wants to use this sheet, I urge you to make a copy and enter your own starting gear, as well as to continue to update stat weights using a source you trust. This sort of spreadsheet has limited usefulness, as there are many out-of-raid sources of gear in Legion and titanforging exists. This sheet serves the limited purpose of showing what upgrades exist &lt;em&gt;for me, from the raid&lt;/em&gt;. If you play any other class, this spreadsheet may serve as a model of something you want to create for yourself. &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1uTej7J-su3NF3Uvjtjo4ChlZiz4zBgVw0sbM97YoJ4A/&#34;&gt;Here is the spreadsheet&lt;/a&gt;. One insight demonstrated by spreadsheet that is applicable to Balance Druids and may be of use to other classes: the crafted ring and neck-piece are better than non-warforged/non-socketed rings and neck-pieces available from the &lt;strong&gt;mythic&lt;/strong&gt; raid. Balance Druids should look into getting these pieces if possible. Other classes should research them, especially if your class has a secondary stat that is valued much more highly than the other secondary stats.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Preparing for The Emerald Nightmare</title>
			<link>www.raidadvice.com/preparing-for-the-emerald-nightmare/</link>
			<pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2016 15:04:43 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">www.raidadvice.com/preparing-for-the-emerald-nightmare/</guid>
			<description>&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a basic overview of how I prepared for day one of heroic raiding in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/zone=8026/the-emerald-nightmare&#34;&gt;Emerald Nightmare&lt;/a&gt;. Many of these steps are repeatable tasks you can do yourself, even if you are starting the day before the raid opens up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;strategies&#34;&gt;Strategies&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Knowing what is heading your way from the seven bosses of The Emerald Nightmare is probably the most important step you can take at this point. Here are some resources I used:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/legion-dungeon-journal#ej-the-emerald-nightmare&#34;&gt;Dungeon Journal&lt;/a&gt; - Seriously, before anything else, open the in-game (or &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/legion-dungeon-journal#ej-the-emerald-nightmare&#34;&gt;wowhead copy&lt;/a&gt;) dungeon journal and read about the bosses to get a good idea of what each encounter will be like and what your role&amp;rsquo;s job is. Starting with it will give you a good frame of reference for more in-depth guides. You can also take a look at the loot from each boss to create a checklist of what loot you are hoping drops (especially relevant if your guild uses Master Looter and you need to figure out what loot you want to prioritize going for).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/guides/emerald-nightmare-raid-overview-and-rewards#tier19-druid&#34;&gt;Wowhead Encounter Guides&lt;/a&gt; - These guides are the best written guides I have seen for the Emerald Nightmare. They provide a good overview of what to look for and do in the fights, I recommend them as your next step.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLu3dsh6Bc2HUBq9hjJs_Vd9uuDJv-t-4A&#34;&gt;Fatboss Legion Beta Ecounter Videos&lt;/a&gt; - In this video playlist, Fatboss covers each of the seven encounters with a video. This is the best collection of encounter video guides that I have heard of. More may be available in the coming weeks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.twitch.tv/spartysmallwood/v/90109146&#34;&gt;SpartySmallwood&amp;rsquo;s Preparation Stream&lt;/a&gt; - I had this on in the background while playing today to reinforce the concepts outlined in the above guides. He did a solid job of covering the encounters and shared this link of useful &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1CIQbGT53EygCRa2SHmm5AVtseZRPRRyOLvV5iay8xNg/htmlview?pli=1&amp;amp;sle=true#gid=0&#34;&gt;Emerald Nightmare weakauras&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Discussion with other players - After all that, I spent a bit of time discussing the encounters with guild mates and friends. Finding someone who plays your spec and discussing it with them can be a great way to make sure you are fully prepared. If your guild deviates from public strategies, make sure to pay attention to that.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;user-interface&#34;&gt;User Interface&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right before a new raid is not a great time to make drastic changes to your user interface - hopefully you did that weeks ago, so you are now comfortable with your UI setup. However, before your enter raid, you want to make sure your addons are up to date and look at the boss-specific settings of whichever boss mod (such as Deadly Boss Mods or BigWigs) you use. The mod may be set to alert you to more or less than you want to know, and you can change this to suit your needs. If you are using boss specific addons or weakauras, you also want to make sure that they are set to display when and where you want them. Customize your UI - don&amp;rsquo;t just accept the defaults!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;spec-talents-and-rotation&#34;&gt;Spec: Talents and Rotation&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hopefully you have been mastering your rotation for the past several weeks. But now is a good time to take one last look at the public theory-crafting available for your class. As a Balance Druid, I am thankful to the folks that put together &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ellicottsj/BoomkinFAQ/wiki/Boomkin-FAQ&#34;&gt;this FAQ&lt;/a&gt;. It links to a bunch of superb resources including two great guides. &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/document/d/1c6-_akHl_Cja-uwg20Gt8R0f12pcw4_qtVcT7LyZW4A/edit&#34;&gt;This one&lt;/a&gt; outlines the Boomkin opener and covers talent choices for each fight. I hope that finding a great resource like this is as easy as you as the Balance Druid community made finding this for me - it was as simple as checking the pinned comments in the Balance Druid discord (see &lt;a href=&#34;http://raidadvice.com/world-of-warcraft-legion-useful-discord-channels/&#34;&gt;my list of class Discords&lt;/a&gt;). The night before raid is a good time to run a few dungeons or practice on a target dummy to make sure that you are very comfortable with the mechanics of your class, so you can focus on the mechanics of the raid encounters in raid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;gear&#34;&gt;Gear&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You have gotten most of what you can from world quests, heroics, and mythics at this point. However, it&amp;rsquo;s worth checking out whether you can improve your gear with crafted or world drop BoEs if you have the gold to do so. I decided to get five crafted/BoE pieces, all of which are just about as good as I can get outside of mythic, and a few of which will last me well into mythic despite the lower item level. Crafted gear, BoE rings, and BoE trinkets can come with perfect stats for your class. I recommend prioritizing a neck piece and rings. Secondary stats seem to scale at a lower rate in Legion than in prior expansions. The first piece I bought was my &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/item=130231/dawnlight-band&#34;&gt;Dawnlight Band&lt;/a&gt; (of the Fireflash). I upgraded it to 850, and my stat weights showed that it was better than all but one mythic ring that drops in the Emerald Nightmare because of how much better haste is for balance druids than the other stats. The &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/item=130239/sylvan-maelstrom-amulet&#34;&gt;Sylvan Maelstrom Amulet&lt;/a&gt; for Druids is especially great, as it gives not only (potentially) perfect stats, it gives a free bonus of versatility for outdoor encounters, which may include &amp;ldquo;outdoor&amp;rdquo; fights in raids! &lt;a href=&#34;http://imgur.com/a/J7s7r&#34;&gt;Here is an album&lt;/a&gt; showing my overall gear, crafted pieces, and artifact weapon progression. The other four pieces are an &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/item=127034/imbued-silkweave-flourish&#34;&gt;Imbued Silkweave Flourish&lt;/a&gt;, a set of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/item=128891/dreadleather-bindings&#34;&gt;Dreadleather Bindings&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/item=141582/frans-intractable-loop&#34;&gt;Fran&amp;rsquo;s Intractable Loop&lt;/a&gt;, and my artifact, the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/item=132474/scythe-of-elune&#34;&gt;Scythe of Elune&lt;/a&gt; (I had some good luck with warforged relics before raids!). The good news here is that you can decide to purchase crafted gear after a week or two of raids to fill in if you want to save gold, and the gear is only going to get cheaper. If you think you might be interested in crafted gear, I recommend scanning your realm&amp;rsquo;s auction house for upgrades. The biggest cost of crafted gear is &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/item=124125/obliterum&#34;&gt;Obliterum&lt;/a&gt; to upgrade the gear to item level 850, and it may take a while to find crafted gear with perfect (or close enough to perfect for your liking) stats. The necklace, cloak, and rings I had I all intend to keep for a long while, and I enchanted them with the best enchantments available: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/item=128550/enchant-cloak-binding-of-intellect&#34;&gt;Enchant Cloak - Binding of Intellect&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/item=128553/enchant-neck-mark-of-the-hidden-satyr&#34;&gt;Enchant Neck - Mark of the Hidden Satyr&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/item=128542/enchant-ring-binding-of-haste&#34;&gt;Enchant Ring - Binding of Haste&lt;/a&gt;. I used a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/spell=195880/sabers-eye-of-intellect&#34;&gt;Saber&amp;rsquo;s Eye of Intellect&lt;/a&gt; on my ring and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/spell=195853/quick-dawnlight&#34;&gt;Quick Dawnlight&lt;/a&gt; on my necklace. Interestingly, before the lowering of gems from +250 of a secondary to +150 of a secondary, Quick Dawnlight would have been better than the Saber&amp;rsquo;s Eye. I had used a cheaper &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/item=130216/quick-azsunite&#34;&gt;Quick Azsunite&lt;/a&gt; on my belt as I hoped to replace it before raiding. I have since upgraded it to a Dawnlight. While a few thousand gold for a piece I want to replace soon is a bit expensive, it&amp;rsquo;s really just a few potions worth of gold&amp;hellip; Too see what enchantments and gems you might want to use, check out the wowhead World of Warcraft: Legion &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/guides/legion-enchanting&#34;&gt;Enchanting&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/guides/legion-jewelcrafting&#34;&gt;Jewelcrafting&lt;/a&gt; guides. Don&amp;rsquo;t forget the shoulder and glove enchantments for use outside of raids.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;consumables&#34;&gt;Consumables&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before you enter raid, you want to make sure you have all the consumables you need to succeed. For each class, that can include potions, flasks, health potions, food, and possibly even &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/item=140587/defiled-augment-rune&#34;&gt;Defiled Augment Rune&lt;/a&gt;s. For balance druids, the best available are &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/item=127843/potion-of-deadly-grace&#34;&gt;Potion of Deadly Grace&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/item=127834/ancient-healing-potion&#34;&gt;Ancient Healing Potion&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/item=127847/flask-of-the-whispered-pact&#34;&gt;Flask of the Whispered Pact&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/spell=201506/azshari-salad&#34;&gt;Azshari Salad&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/wow/comments/53gqwg/the_current_state_of_alchemy_and_raid_supplies/&#34;&gt;Potions are very expensive&lt;/a&gt; this expansion, so good luck with those. Check the wowhead guides to World of Warcraft: Legion &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/guides/legion-alchemy&#34;&gt;Alchemy&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/guides/legion-cooking&#34;&gt;Cooking&lt;/a&gt; to see what consumables are best for you. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/spells/professions/inscription/legion-inscription/vantus-runes&#34;&gt;Vantus runes&lt;/a&gt; will be an important consumable you want to coordinate with your guild. You may also want to grab a few &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/item=141446/tome-of-the-tranquil-mind&#34;&gt;Tome of the Tranquil Mind&lt;/a&gt; for changing talents on the fly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s most of what I did to prepare over the past few days. What are you doing to be &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/achievement=10458/ready-for-raiding-v&#34;&gt;Ready for Raiding&lt;/a&gt;? Best luck in the Nightmare!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>World of Warcraft: Legion Useful Discord Channels</title>
			<link>www.raidadvice.com/world-of-warcraft-legion-useful-discord-channels/</link>
			<pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2016 06:18:23 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">www.raidadvice.com/world-of-warcraft-legion-useful-discord-channels/</guid>
			<description>&lt;p&gt;As I&amp;rsquo;ve &lt;a href=&#34;http://raidadvice.com/useful-websites-for-legion-prepatch/&#34;&gt;noted before&lt;/a&gt;, the Discord channel for your class is a great place to get information about how to play your class and spec well. I recently checked the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/competitivewow&#34;&gt;https://www.reddit.com/r/competitivewow&lt;/a&gt; Discord channel list, and wanted to post a list of class channels here as well for your reference. If you want to make sure that guide you read in prepatch is still up-to-date and search for more resources, the Discord channel for your spec is a great first stop. I will be going through and cultivating the class guides, hopefully in time for the release of mythic raiding. In the meantime, your class Discord is a good first place to check for up-to-date information, and can be all you need in some cases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://discord.gg/0ez1cFfUH3ingV96&#34;&gt;Death Knight&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Demon Hunter: &lt;a href=&#34;https://discord.gg/0enuZ4FBFlwM8Kr3&#34;&gt;Mardum&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/bgpcLZfa87&#34;&gt;Fel Hammer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://discord.gg/0dWu0WkuetF87H9H&#34;&gt;Druid&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://discord.gg/yqer4BX&#34;&gt;Hunter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://discord.gg/0gLMHikX2aZ23VdA&#34;&gt;Mage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://discord.gg/0dkfBMAxzTmggsPH&#34;&gt;Monk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://discord.gg/0dvRDgpa5xZHFfnD&#34;&gt;Paladin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://discord.gg/0f1Ta8lT8xXXEAIY&#34;&gt;Priest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://discord.gg/0h08tydxoNhfDVZf&#34;&gt;Rogue&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://discord.gg/0VcupJEQX0HuE5HH&#34;&gt;Shaman&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://discord.gg/0onXDymd9Wpc2CEu&#34;&gt;Warlock&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://discord.gg/0pYY7932lTH4FHW6&#34;&gt;Warrior&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://discord.gg/0kfOaeT2AxMqPiAo&#34;&gt;CompetitiveWoW Discord&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For even more Discord channels, check out this list on Reddit: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/wow/comments/4yfgms/wowclass_discord_info/&#34;&gt;https://www.reddit.com/r/wow/comments/4yfgms/wowclass_discord_info/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Withered Training Preparation, Tips, and Tricks</title>
			<link>www.raidadvice.com/withered-training-preparation-tips-and-tricks/</link>
			<pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2016 15:32:58 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">www.raidadvice.com/withered-training-preparation-tips-and-tricks/</guid>
			<description>&lt;p&gt;(Last updated 2017-1-12) This guide will outline some items to focus on in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/zone=7637/suramar&#34;&gt;Suramar&lt;/a&gt; to maximize &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/faction=1859&#34;&gt;the Nightfallen&lt;/a&gt; reputation gains and overall success you have at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/quest=43943/withered-army-training&#34;&gt;Withered Army Training&lt;/a&gt;. This is &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; an all-inclusive guide, and will reference other resources on Withered Training that you should check out before starting the training. I wrote this guide because while there are a few great guides on how to clear the scenario, it was harder to find detailed information on how to prepare for the scenario or what to do your first few times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;withered-training-faq&#34;&gt;Withered Training FAQ&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;What is Withered Army Training?&lt;/em&gt; Withered Army Training is an every-three-days world quest that grants reputation with the Nightfallen, Artifact Power, and other goodies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;When can I do it?&lt;/em&gt; You must complete about 40 quests in the Suramar storyline, ending with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/quest=44636/building-an-army&#34;&gt;Building an Army!&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;I heard I have to pay Ancient Mana to do the scenario?&lt;/em&gt; The first time is free, after that you purchase troops with Ancient Mana. You can enter the scenario the second time right after you do it the first time, by the way. After that, you have to wait about three days in between attempts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;How am I graded on Withered Training?&lt;/em&gt; The more mobs you kill, the higher your score.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;What score do I need for maximum reward?&lt;/em&gt; If you get 375 score, you maximize your +425 reputation reward, with other breakpoints at lower scores.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;A Withered soldier is running away - what do I do?&lt;/em&gt; Run to it and right click on it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;I want to be a hero and kill all the bosses I can and defeat the training. Will I be rewarded for this?&lt;/em&gt; The further you get in the scenario, the more access you have to rewards.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Wait, I thought rewards were based on score?&lt;/em&gt; You get certain rewards for getting 375 score or above. For others, you have to give up your Withered to carry back chests of rewards, so only complete them after you have gone as far as you want to on that attempt! These rewards cost either 5 or 10 Withered, and are either external to the training or upgrade your army for the next time you do the training. Most rewards that do not upgrade your army are cosmetic.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;How else can I maximize my reputation with the Nightfallen?&lt;/em&gt; Hey! This is a Withered Training guide, stay on topic. But, to answer, do every world quest in Suramar you see, do the three daily turn-ins to your Shal&amp;rsquo;Aran Withered, and complete all the story-line quests in Suramar.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;getting-around-suramar&#34;&gt;Getting Around Suramar&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to prepare for Withered Training, it may be useful to travel quickly around Suramar by unlocking portals. Unlocking all the portals will get the achievement &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/achievement=11125/now-youre-thinking-with-portals&#34;&gt;Now You&amp;rsquo;re Thinking With Portals&lt;/a&gt;. See the comments there for some suggestions on unlocking the portals. I recommend the &lt;a href=&#34;https://mods.curse.com/addons/wow/handynotes&#34;&gt;Handynotes&lt;/a&gt; addon and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://mods.curse.com/addons/wow/handynotes_suramartelemancy&#34;&gt;Suramar Telemancy&lt;/a&gt; module that shows these portals on your map.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;maximizing-your-ancient-mana-pool&#34;&gt;Maximizing your Ancient Mana Pool&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The higher cap to your &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/currency=1155/ancient-mana&#34;&gt;Ancient Mana&lt;/a&gt; pool you have, the more Withered you can start out with in Withered Training. Starting out with more makes the training easier, so you want to get as high a cap as you can. I recommend at least 1300 for 15 Withered, and the maximum cap of 2000 is ideal. Reaching that cap will give the achievement &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/achievement=11133/why-cant-i-hold-all-this-mana&#34;&gt;Why Can&amp;rsquo;t I Hold All This Mana?&lt;/a&gt; The top comment thread on Wowhead provides the following macro to help you identify which of the 10 upgrades to your Ancient Mana pool you have already acquired: &lt;code&gt;/run local a={41138,42230,42488,42833,42792,42842,43988,43989,43986,43987}for i,q in ipairs(a)do print(i,IsQuestFlaggedCompleted(q))end&lt;/code&gt; The first 5 ways to upgrade your mana pool are from the basic story-line. Ways 6-10 are from items you can pick up in the world. For those items, use these &lt;a href=&#34;https://mods.curse.com/addons/wow/tomtom&#34;&gt;TomTom&lt;/a&gt; coordinates (also provided in the Wowhead comments): &lt;code&gt;/way Suramar 21.4 54.5 Kel&#39;danath&#39;s Manaflask /way Suramar 22.9 35.8 Volatile Leyline Crystal (ent.) /way Suramar 35.6 12.1 Infinite Stone /way Suramar 44.8 31.0 Enchanted Burial Urn /way Suramar 26.9 70.7 Kyrtos&#39;s Research Notes&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;filling-your-ancient-mana-pool&#34;&gt;Filling your Ancient Mana Pool&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you have a high enough cap (ideally at least 1300), you need to fill it. If you are having problems I recommend three areas to farm for Ancient Mana items. They are at the Vineyard and the Market in Suramar, and the underground Falanar ruins (which Withered Army Training scenario uses the same map as). The Vineyard is probably the most abundant source of Ancient Mana if you face no competition from other players there. If you have limitless gold and no time, you can search on the auction house and pay gold for an &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/item=139890/ancient-mana-gem&#34;&gt;Ancient Mana Gem&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/item=139786/ancient-mana-crystal&#34;&gt;Ancient Mana Crystal&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;withered-army-training-tips&#34;&gt;Withered Army Training Tips&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before you start the scenario, I recommend looking at three resources. First, the top comment on wowhead here: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/quest=43943/withered-army-training#comments&#34;&gt;http://www.wowhead.com/quest=43943/withered-army-training#comments&lt;/a&gt; which links to this &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://imgur.com/a/14DpM&#34;&gt;Wowhead map&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;rdquo; This resource goes into detail about how to fight each mob in the scenario, so I will not be covering that here. Second, this Reddit thread &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/wow/comments/51dcoj/i_have_made_a_map_for_the_wither_training/&#34;&gt;https://www.reddit.com/r/wow/comments/51dcoj/i_have_made_a_map_for_the_wither_training/&lt;/a&gt; provides the &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://imgur.com/a/zEwRK&#34;&gt;Reddit map&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;rdquo; A third resource, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mmo-champion.com/threads/2064610-Withered-Army-Training?p=42226469&amp;amp;viewfull=1#post42226469&#34;&gt;this comment&lt;/a&gt; on MMO-Champion, includes the &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://i.imgur.com/u8R5Lpq.png&#34;&gt;MMO-Champion map part 1&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://i.imgur.com/4QKUv6B.png&#34;&gt;MMO-Champion map part 2&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;rdquo; This guide is warrior specific, and had many of the same thoughts I did. You have all expansion to revisit Withered Training and complete it. With that in mind, I suggest you focus on getting 375 score each time until you build up your army a bit. Maximize the reward chests you grab before starting any hard bosses. Kill as many easy enemies as you can, then grab all the upgrades you can from the easy areas. If you complete the easy areas I outline, have 375 score, and have some chests you can grab, grab them, and do the harder bosses next time. If you have 1-4 Withered left over, there is no harm trying a boss to see what the encounter is like; just get the rewards first! Focus on upgrading your army and getting 375 score the first few times you enter the training, not on completing the scenario. Only go into the harder bosses if you have 375 score and there are no chests you can grab. This is not a sprint. There is no reward for going fast, and you can only do the scenario once every few days. Take your time and do not lose Withered to silly mistakes. Use a tank if possible. If not, use a DPS spec with good creature control, prioritizing short cooldown stuns and interrupts. You can hit your extra action button to enrage your Withered. They will aggro everything in sight and do more damage. I recommend using this only when a room is clear and you are engaging a boss. Other than that, it is too easy for things to get out of control with enraged Withered. Get the three daily buffs from your Shal&amp;rsquo;Aran Withered before starting if you have the Ancient Mana to do so - they will be active in the scenario!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;suggested-beginners-route&#34;&gt;Suggested Beginner&amp;rsquo;s Route&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can get 375 score with the following route on the Wowhead map above. I suggest clearing this route and grabbing the Withered army upgrade rewards from it before trying any more difficult rooms. After 2-4 successful clears of this route, you can do this route and continue on to harder bosses with your Withered army. &lt;strong&gt;Then&lt;/strong&gt;, if you wipe, at least you won&amp;rsquo;t have missed getting rewards or upgrades, and you can try again at full strength next time. For each room, pull as few mobs as you can at a time and clear them before engaging more mobs. Be careful and hug the walls, as your Withered will accidentally aggro enemies if they get too close. Clear room 1. Head to room 4 and clear it. Clear the area between 4 and the intersection between 5 and 6. A very hard boss, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/npc=110954/leystalker-dro&#34;&gt;Leystalker Dro&lt;/a&gt;, will likely pop out at one of these mobs (he can be avoided with very precise play - see below). Be alert, and good luck! Your very first time, when you start with only 8 Withered, you may want to grab the Health Increase chest (unless you think you can skip Dro - see below), since if you do not have good stuns you can easily wipe to him without getting any chest reward. Be on alert until you have killed Dro, as he can spawn at any mob in room 5. Clear the area between 5 and 8, and clear room 8. Clear the hallway towards 9, and get the one Withered just within 9 if it will bring you to a multiple of 5 for chests. You should be over 375 score, and can turn in your Withered for chests rewards along this path. Make sure to kill every single mob to improve your score. Especially make sure to free the mobs trapped in webs, as some of those hide Withered you can recruit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;withered-pickups-on-suggested-route&#34;&gt;Withered Pickups on Suggested Route&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Along the above suggested route, you can pick up about 16 Withered reinforcements. A good goal is ending with 15 or 20 Withered toal so you can grab two reward chests. Even if almost all your original Withered die at Leystalker Dro, you can recover along the rest of the route. There are a few more Withered inside boss rooms that you can grab if you are very careful about not pulling the boss. These Withered are generally not necessary to maximize reputation gains or chest rewards, so I recommend skipping them your first few times if you are unsure whether you can avoid pulling the bosses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Room&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Withered&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Room 1:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Room1 to Room 4:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Room 4:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Room 4 to Room 5:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Room 5:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Room 8:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From Room 8 to Room 9:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Front of Room 9:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;monitor-your-withered&#34;&gt;Monitor your Withered&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://wago.io/4kcrS2ei-&#34;&gt;This nifty weakaura&lt;/a&gt; by alcaras will display how many Withered are in your army and their average health. It&amp;rsquo;s a nice way to see whether you are at a multiple of 5 for chest rewards. Especially once you have all the &amp;ldquo;easy&amp;rdquo; chest rewards and are progressing further into the instance, the indicator is a good way to help decide whether you can push a bit more or should stop and get the rewards available now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;advanced-tactics-and-dro-avoidance&#34;&gt;Advanced Tactics and Dro Avoidance&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MqwdzaGUwZs&#34;&gt;This video&lt;/a&gt; covers several advanced tips I was not aware of when drafting the guide. A few points I want to emphasize: Demon hunters can scan for Dro and avoid him; other classes can avoid him if they memorize his stationary spawn locations (shown in the video) and play extremely precisely. As a tank with several upgrade chests under my belt, I will probably not alter my play now, but for someone new to the scenario, you may wish to try avoiding Dro. Apparently, your Withered will &lt;strong&gt;never&lt;/strong&gt; attack until you do, you can use this to very carefully face pull and fight mobs in safer locations. If you are sure you will not accidentally face pull too many mobs, you can open boss doors and grab a few mobs and/or Withered near the entrance of the room this way. Some players, and the video creator, use the tactic of enraging their Withered in an empty area, then moving ahead and face pulling, then un-enraging their Withered. This is a hack to get the Withered to stop following you for a bit. Be warned, if you stray too far, the Withered will wander off and/or start following you. I had tried this tactic and found it to be fairly difficult for not a lot of reward, but some folks love it and get great results with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;changelog&#34;&gt;Changelog&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2017-1-12: Removed references to unlocking dungeons, as The Arcway and Court of Stars are unlocked by default as of patch 7.1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you follow the above advice, hopefully you will clear the Withered Army training with 375+ score several times. Get three upgraded Withered and upgrade your whole army to have more health and be resistant to fear. Once that is completed, you can clear this route and take on the harder bosses for more upgrades and fun. Good luck!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;comments&#34;&gt;Comments:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;%22raphanwow@gmail.com%22&#34;&gt;Raphael&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Sep 1, 2016&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reddit comments: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/wow/comments/52f1j1/withered&#34;&gt;https://www.reddit.com/r/wow/comments/52f1j1/withered&lt;/a&gt;_training_strategy_and_faq/.
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;heading-1&#34;&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;%22mikymod@gmail.com%22&#34;&gt;mikymod&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Sep 2, 2016&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;just what i&amp;rsquo;m looking for :D ty and keep going!
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;heading-2&#34;&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://coffeecakesandcrits.wordpress.com/&#34; title=&#34;wrathofkublakhan@yahoo.com&#34;&gt;wrathsome&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Sep 4, 2016&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brilliant and you have my thanks. I&amp;rsquo;m not there yet, however instead of bookmarking your piece; I decided to bookmark your blog. Good stuff, well received.
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;heading-3&#34;&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;%22jeanniet13@gmail.com%22&#34;&gt;Batcat&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Sep 4, 2016&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for putting this together in one place! I&amp;rsquo;ve been having trouble with the training, and I also haven&amp;rsquo;t capped out my Ancient Mana pool yet, either.
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Mount Up and Do Mythics</title>
			<link>www.raidadvice.com/mount-up-and-do-mythics/</link>
			<pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2016 16:40:49 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">www.raidadvice.com/mount-up-and-do-mythics/</guid>
			<description>&lt;p&gt;These are two World of Warcraft tidbits I wanted to share. They will help you mount up and clear mythic dungeons each week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;mount-up&#34;&gt;Mount Up&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EDIT 2016-10-11: Follow up post &lt;a href=&#34;http://raidadvice.com/mount-macros-revisited/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt; The following is my Mount Up macro. I assign the &amp;ldquo;favorite mounts&amp;rdquo; icon to it, and enjoy using it to get around in Legion. &lt;code&gt;/dismount /castrandom [mod:alt]Azure Water Strider, Crimson Water Strider /cast [mod:shift]Grand Expedition Yak;[mod:ctrl]Mekgineer&#39;s Chopper /cast [flyable]X-53 Touring Rocket /cancelform [stance:1/2] /run C_MountJournal.SummonByID(0)&lt;/code&gt; Here&amp;rsquo;s what it does: If mounted, I dismount. If I am holding alt, cast either Azure Water Stider or Crimson Water Strider. If I am holding shift, cast my Yak for repairs and transmog. If I am holding control, cast MekGineer&amp;rsquo;s Chopper for a two-person ground mount. If none of the above, make sure I am not in bear or cat form (if you skip this step, the next doesn&amp;rsquo;t work), and summon a random favorite mount. This allows me to set both ground and flying mounts as my favorite mounts for use in the Broken Isles, cast a water-walker/shop/transmog mount/2-seater if I need it, and cast a 2-seater flying mount if I happen to be in a flyable zone. Consider this alternative: &lt;code&gt;/dismount /cast [mod:alt]Crimson Water Strider;[mod:shift]Traveler&#39;s Tundra Mammoth;[mod:ctrl]Sandstone Drake /castrandom [flyable]Red Flying Cloud, Black Drake /run C_MountJournal.SummonByID(0)&lt;/code&gt; This macro would work for a non-druid. It would cast Crimson Water Strider with alt, Traveler&amp;rsquo;s Tundra Mammoth with shift, and Sandstone Drake with control for a two-person flying or ground mount. If none of the above, and in a flying zone, cast either Red Flying Cloud or Black Drake. If not in a flying zone, cast a favorite mount. You can obviously change the mount names if you have different mounts or preferences. Happy trails!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;do-mythics&#34;&gt;Do Mythics&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://wago.io/Ek906edj-&#34;&gt;This weakaura&lt;/a&gt;, by Spinalcrack, the first of his name, Co-GM of &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; on US-Sargeras, Assistant Administrator at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.howtopriest.com&#34;&gt;www.howtopriest.com&lt;/a&gt;, and Protector of the Realm, displays which mythic dungeons you have yet to complete each week when you open up the dungeon journal. There&amp;rsquo;s a picture of exactly how it looks at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://wago.io/Ek906edj-&#34;&gt;wago.io page&lt;/a&gt;. This is deceptively useful! I had thought checking my calendar, figuring out which ones I &lt;em&gt;had&lt;/em&gt; done, and subtracting would be just as easy. It&amp;rsquo;s not even close. Just opening the journal and seeing which mythics I have not finished yet is amazing. Hopefully this helps you wrap up the last few you need to do this weekend. I resisted installing this weakaura for a week even though Spinal is the co-GM of my guild and suggested it to us. Once you install it, it feels like it should have always been there and you never want to go back. That&amp;rsquo;s pretty much the universal opinion of everyone I&amp;rsquo;ve gotten to try it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Gearing up for The Emerald Nightmare with PvP World Quests</title>
			<link>www.raidadvice.com/gearing-up-for-the-emerald-nightmare-with-pvp-world-quests/</link>
			<pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2016 15:55:33 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">www.raidadvice.com/gearing-up-for-the-emerald-nightmare-with-pvp-world-quests/</guid>
			<description>&lt;p&gt;There is &lt;a href=&#34;http://us.battle.net/forums/en/wow/topic/18300628854&#34;&gt;no more PvP gear in Legion&lt;/a&gt;. Players can get gear from PvE and they can get gear from PvP, and PvP gear can be used in PvE and vice versa. &lt;a href=&#34;https://worldofwarcraft.com/en-us/news/19994381/legion-pvp-preview&#34;&gt;According to Blizzard&lt;/a&gt;, &amp;ldquo;in Legion, gear is gear, regardless of where you earned it, with no PvP-specific stats or fluctuating item levels, and the best players in both PvP and PvE content will be able to earn the best gear.&amp;rdquo; Now, if a player had to be extremely talented at PvP to get good gear, a mythic raider who was not excellent at PvP might be fine ignoring PvP in Legion. However, this appears not to be the case: you can basically acquire PvP gear from world quests much like how you get other gear from world quests. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/quests/type:113?filter=35;7;0&#34;&gt;Here is a list of PvP world quests in Legion&lt;/a&gt;. Three Warden Tower Assault quests spawn every three hours, one in each of Val&amp;rsquo;sharah, Highmountain, and Stormheim. These quests are very straightforward, players must kill several opposing faction NPCs then kill a boss NPC at the top of a tower. The mobs are a bit punishing, so pull a few at a time, bring a tank, wait for other members of your faction to show up, or all three. Doing these quests rewards honor. They also reward either gold, artifact knowledge, or iLvL 805 gear. Here&amp;rsquo;s the important part for gearing up: These quests, under certain conditions, start rewarding 840 gear instead of 805 gear, the same iLvL gear that drops from mythic dungeons! And just like mythic dungeons, that gear can roll warforged. It&amp;rsquo;s not clear exactly what breakpoints cause the quests to start spawning 840 gear or stop spawning 805 gear (840 gear starts showing up as a reward at around honor level 14), but as &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/holinka/status/771917972784812032&#34;&gt;noted by World of Warcraft&amp;rsquo;s Lead PvP Designer&lt;/a&gt; the &amp;ldquo;gear reward ilvl from PvP world quest increase based on Honor level.&amp;rdquo; How can you increase your honor level if you don&amp;rsquo;t want to fight other players in PvP? That&amp;rsquo;s right, you guessed it, by doing these world quests every few hours. Two notes: First, for the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/quest=41421/warden-tower-assault-nightwatchers-perch&#34;&gt;Val&amp;rsquo;sharah quest&lt;/a&gt;, the world map icon currently always directs you to the southern tower. If you get there, and the tower is guarded by your faction, you need to go to the northern tower. It&amp;rsquo;s located northwest of Blackrock Hold at around (33, 44). Second, for avid PvPers, &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/holinka/status/771920998027268096&#34;&gt;you need not worry&lt;/a&gt;: &amp;ldquo;When you Prestige, the world quest system will consider you Honor level 50 when calculating your reward.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;comments&#34;&gt;Comments:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;%22themoonbunnie@gmail.com%22&#34;&gt;MoonBunnie&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Sep 2, 2016&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regarding the Warden Tower Assault quest in Val&amp;rsquo;Sharah, you can distinguish if the current world quest marker is in the correct location by looking at the name of the quest. If the name of the quest is &amp;ldquo;Warden Tower Assault: Darkfollow&amp;rsquo;s Spire&amp;rdquo;, then the world quest marker is in the correct location. If however the name of the quest is &amp;ldquo;Warden Tower Assault: Starstalker&amp;rsquo;s Point&amp;rdquo;, then the marker is in the wrong location, and you will need to travel to west of Black Rook Hold as you indicated!
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;heading-1&#34;&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;%22raphanwow@gmail.com%22&#34;&gt;Raphael&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Sep 3, 2016&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for the tip MoonBunnie. To remember this, I recall the phrase &amp;ldquo;Northern Star&amp;rdquo; - the *northern* quest is at *Star*stalker&amp;rsquo;s point.
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Invasions are Great for Leveling before Legion</title>
			<link>www.raidadvice.com/invasions-are-great-for-leveling-before-legion/</link>
			<pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2016 23:12:15 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">www.raidadvice.com/invasions-are-great-for-leveling-before-legion/</guid>
			<description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been very busy with invasions &amp;amp; World of Warcraft refer-a-friend leveling. Check &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/wow/comments/4zilwq/on_saturday_i_created_24_new_characters_on_the/&#34;&gt;this post on Reddit&lt;/a&gt; for a how-to guide and tips. You can do this by yourself - run two windows of Warcraft on your own computer for two different Warcraft subscriptions. Even if you start Friday evening, you can likely get a full server of characters on your main account to 90 over the weekend before invasions end when Legion launches. You can save time over the fellow who wrote that guide by using the grant-levels feature of refer a friend. One way of approaching it is leveling two pairs of characters to 90, one pair to 60, one pair to 45, and one pair to 28. Then, use level granting, to bring your main account to two 45 characters, then three 60 characters, then five level 90 characters. Over the next few weeks, stay tuned for a re-polished class guides compilation for Legion, a roster management tools system for guild leaders, a third user interface post, and more. If there&amp;rsquo;s any content you are particularly interested in reading about or any questions you have for Legion, leave a comment and let me know. Best of luck with the invasions!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;comments&#34;&gt;Comments:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;%22raphanwow@gmail.com%22&#34;&gt;Raphael&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Aug 0, 2016&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I now have 12 90+ characters on my Alliance server, and am on the way towards 12 90+ on my Horde server. I don&amp;rsquo;t even need to micromanage two windows - just join group, do stages 1-2, log out, and repeat. One character tags the mobs, and the other character stays in the in at Crossroads/Kharanos, still in experience range and getting credit for the other character&amp;rsquo;s tags.
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Remember to Buy Legion</title>
			<link>www.raidadvice.com/remember-to-buy-legion/</link>
			<pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2016 21:24:19 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">www.raidadvice.com/remember-to-buy-legion/</guid>
			<description>&lt;p&gt;Legion launches in just a few weeks. You may have pre-ordered the game digitally from Blizzard. If you have, you&amp;rsquo;re all set. If not, now is a great time to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/World-Warcraft-Legion-Standard-PC-Mac/dp/B017MRX6CM//ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;linkCode=ll1&amp;amp;tag=raida-20&amp;amp;linkId=907ba57e142f9fce0b9fd68e8365cea4&#34;&gt;order the game (Amazon US store link)&lt;/a&gt;. If you&amp;rsquo;re like me, and you want a physical copy, ordering from Amazon is an excellent choice. Shipping should be free, you should receive the game on launch day, and, if you have Amazon Prime, they currently offer a 20% discount on pre-orders and recently released games! Here&amp;rsquo;s that link again to order: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/World-Warcraft-Legion-Standard-PC-Mac/dp/B017MRX6CM//ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;linkCode=ll1&amp;amp;tag=raida-20&amp;amp;linkId=907ba57e142f9fce0b9fd68e8365cea4&#34;&gt;World of Warcraft: Legion Standard Edition PC/Mac (Amazon US store link)&lt;/a&gt;. I ordered &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Overwatch-Origins-PC/dp/B017L187YG/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;linkCode=ll1&amp;amp;tag=raida-20&amp;amp;linkId=3cb486d2ba2f4ed278f104b4e1a386e0&#34;&gt;Overwatch: Origins Edition (Amazon US store link)&lt;/a&gt; from Amazon and couldn&amp;rsquo;t have been happier with my shopping experience. The Legion is ready - are you? &lt;em&gt;Amazon and Amazon Prime are trademarks of Amazon.com, Inc. or its affiliates.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Seven Tips for Legion that Gul&#39;dan Never Saw Coming</title>
			<link>www.raidadvice.com/seven-tips-for-legion-that-guldan-never-saw-coming/</link>
			<pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2016 16:37:53 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">www.raidadvice.com/seven-tips-for-legion-that-guldan-never-saw-coming/</guid>
			<description>&lt;p&gt;Here are some useful tips that will help you prepare for the launch of World of Warcraft: Legion. For even more resources you may not have encountered, check out the &lt;a href=&#34;http://raidadvice.com/class-guides-legion-prepatch/&#34;&gt;class guides&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;http://raidadvice.com/general-raiding-guides/&#34;&gt;general raiding guides&lt;/a&gt; (both are also linked in the navigation bar). It has always been a dream of mine to write a useful &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.paulgraham.com/nthings.html&#34;&gt;List of N Things&lt;/a&gt; blog post with a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wired.com/2015/12/psychology-of-clickbait/&#34;&gt;catchy title&lt;/a&gt;. Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;swag-your-spellbook&#34;&gt;Swag Your Spellbook&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Blizzard &lt;a href=&#34;https://worldofwarcraft.com/en-us/news/20151961/legion-pre-expansion-patch-notes&#34;&gt;reworked the Glyph system with the 7.0 Legion prepatch&lt;/a&gt;, several classes lost cosmetic effects. Some will be available again from Inscription Glyphs when Legion launches. Others are available for you now! Are you a Druid missing your stag appearance? A Shaman that misses making it rain (of frogs)? Check out &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/wow/comments/4tr061/there_are_vendors_throughout_the_world_who_sell/&#34;&gt;this Reddit post with a list of vendors that sell cosmetic enhancements&lt;/a&gt;. Some like &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/npc=11536/quartermaster-miranda-breechlock&#34;&gt;Quartermaster Miranda Breechlock&lt;/a&gt; in Eastern Plaguelands sell only a few items (she sells a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/item=136801/divine-tome-contemplation&#34;&gt;Contemplation Tome&lt;/a&gt; for Paladins and a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/item=136928/thaumaturgists-orb&#34;&gt;nifty toy&lt;/a&gt; for Priests). Others like &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/npc=12022/lorelae-wintersong&#34;&gt;Lorelae Wintersong&lt;/a&gt; in Moonglade sell many Tomes - any Druids looking for &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/item=136794/tome-of-the-wilds-flap&#34;&gt;Flap&lt;/a&gt; or cosmetic effects should check her out. Speaking of Flap, if you are a Balance Druid, check out the &lt;a href=&#34;https://wago.io/4k38vaEub&#34;&gt;FlappyBirb weakaura&lt;/a&gt; which creates some mini-games based on Flapping!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;enhance-your-exploring&#34;&gt;Enhance Your Exploring&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Preach made a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gWdybMztTss&#34;&gt;great video guide&lt;/a&gt; with some Legion leveling tips. Some folks on Reddit &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/wow/comments/4ww5fg/preachgaming_legion_levelling_hints_and_tips/&#34;&gt;summarized and discussed his recommendations&lt;/a&gt; - definitely worth a read-through. A few other tips and tricks threads have popped up on Reddit: here&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/wow/comments/4xns8f/helpful_tips_from_my_beta_experience_so_far/&#34;&gt;another one&lt;/a&gt; I found useful. Make sure to plan your attack so you hit the ground running once the expansion drops.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;analyze-your-artifact-weapons&#34;&gt;Analyze Your Artifact Weapons&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Poneria wrote a &lt;a href=&#34;https://felconcentration.wordpress.com/2016/07/12/multispeccing-artifacts/&#34;&gt;lengthy article&lt;/a&gt; on the math behind leveling up multiple artifact weapons. Check it out to get a better understanding of where you should be spending your artifact power. My executive summary? Two fully-filled artifact weapons (a main spec and one offspec) is doable. But once you get to the hidden &amp;ldquo;percentage improvement&amp;rdquo; traits, you want to focus on one main spec early on in Legion. The artifact power costs of each additional percentage will get prohibitively high for multiple specs. If you are interested in looking at more artifact weapon numbers, check out &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/11xQCzhiVM9gTZkUsu1UNs7z4dpwHpRQSUUZySY7xLv0/&#34;&gt;this spreadsheet&lt;/a&gt; by Kibo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;automate-backing-up-your-addons&#34;&gt;Automate Backing Up Your Addons&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://us.battle.net/forums/en/wow/topic/18300739344&#34;&gt;This guide on the official Blizzard Battle.net forums&lt;/a&gt; explains how you can automate backing up your addons (and their settings) to your favorite cloud storage provider - at no additional cost! Once everything is set up, you can also sync addons between different computers. The process is a bit involved and requires some tech savvy, so proceed with caution. For a paid alternative, consider &lt;a href=&#34;https://mods.curse.com/premium&#34;&gt;Curse Premium&lt;/a&gt;, which includes an &lt;a href=&#34;https://support.curse.com/hc/en-us/articles/204269785-AddOn-Sync-Settings-Backup&#34;&gt;addons backup and sync feature&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;calculate-your-cooldowns&#34;&gt;Calculate Your Cooldowns&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I noted in my &lt;a href=&#34;http://raidadvice.com/updating-my-addons-and-user-interface-for-the-legion-prepatch/&#34;&gt;recent post on User Interface&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://mods.curse.com/addons/wow/weakauras-2&#34;&gt;Weakauras&lt;/a&gt; can be a great way to manage your cooldowns. I also noted that it can often be a good start - and sometimes finish - to borrow Weakauras from someone else. Several Weakauras repository websites are popping up for Legion. They include &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.weakauras.online&#34;&gt;weakauras.online&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://wago.io&#34;&gt;wago.io&lt;/a&gt;. As someone who is very likely going to main Balance Druid, I love &lt;a href=&#34;https://wago.io/p/Cyous&#34;&gt;Cyrous&amp;rsquo;s Weakauras on wago.io&lt;/a&gt;. Restoration is my favorite offspec, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.weakauras.online/en/user/show/ablution&#34;&gt;Ablution&amp;rsquo;s Weakauras&lt;/a&gt; on weakauras.online are a great resource for Restoration Druids as well as Holy and Discipline Priests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;optimize-your-offspec&#34;&gt;Optimize Your Offspec&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are you still considering what class to pick or what offspec you should prioritize? Are you wondering what specs have secondary stat priorities that mesh well, so you don&amp;rsquo;t have to maintain two separate sets of gear? If so, look no further! &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1eQ3kdYBuMG-xsXcJ6jY-PJSNS5zv0cHmdxX6S6dL1_w/pubhtml&#34;&gt;This spreadsheet&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/wow/comments/4wfan7/to_all_those_worried_about_which_class_to_play/&#34;&gt;linked on Reddit&lt;/a&gt;, lays out which specs have synergistic stat priorities. For me, Balance Druid with Restoration Druid offspec has never looked better, with both specs prioritizing Haste then Critical Strike.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;perfect-your-performance&#34;&gt;Perfect Your Performance&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I may have saved the best for last. &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1TiiI4huz4NXKfx7PGvvVTyP6xu8VaDNZ4-FEn69mOhc/pubhtml#&#34;&gt;This spreadsheet&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/wow/comments/4wq208/legion_raiders_lexicon/&#34;&gt;with discussion on Reddit&lt;/a&gt;, is a comprehensive guide to the start of Legion. It covers, leveling, professions, gearing, your artifact, and more. It is focused on players who want to immediately gear up a main and an alt for &lt;a href=&#34;http://us.battle.net/forums/en/wow/topic/19740454318&#34;&gt;heroic split runs&lt;/a&gt;. A word of caution: &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1apphJ2vlZL4eQFZMKeUrYC34PsNt7JFeTZiqNtb0NyE/htmlview?usp=sharing&amp;amp;sle=true&#34;&gt;the original spreadsheet&lt;/a&gt; was written in Russian, and is being constantly updated by the creator. The translated English version may become outdated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;comments&#34;&gt;Comments:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;%22raphanwow@gmail.com%22&#34;&gt;Raphael&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Aug 2, 2016&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reddit&amp;rsquo;s comments at: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/wow/comments/4y8hma/tips&#34;&gt;https://www.reddit.com/r/wow/comments/4y8hma/tips&lt;/a&gt;_for_legion_leveling_artifact_weapons_addons/ &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/wow/comments/4zhwn5/legion&#34;&gt;https://www.reddit.com/r/wow/comments/4zhwn5/legion&lt;/a&gt;_launch_survival_guide/
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Useful Websites for Legion Prepatch</title>
			<link>www.raidadvice.com/useful-websites-for-legion-prepatch/</link>
			<pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2016 04:06:38 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">www.raidadvice.com/useful-websites-for-legion-prepatch/</guid>
			<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://discordapp.com/&#34;&gt;Discord&lt;/a&gt; is the new voice program taking over many gaming communities with its crisp, free voice-chat and very useful text channels (EDIT: see &lt;a href=&#34;http://raidadvice.com/world-of-warcraft-legion-useful-discord-channels/&#34;&gt;this list of Discord channels for Legion&lt;/a&gt;). There are several community-run wow-related discord servers, including &lt;a href=&#34;https://discord.gg/wow&#34;&gt;this one&lt;/a&gt; for WoW in general and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.icy-veins.com/forums/topic/16114-class-discord-channels/&#34;&gt;these&lt;/a&gt; for each class. Check these channels if you want to stay tuned for the very latest theory-crafting. You can also make a free server for your guild. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/&#34;&gt;http://www.wowhead.com/&lt;/a&gt;: Wowhead, already very useful in general, seems to be stepping up its class guides game for Legion (navigate from &lt;a href=&#34;http://legion.wowhead.com/guides/classes&#34;&gt;http://legion.wowhead.com/guides/classes&lt;/a&gt;). &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.icy-veins.com/wow/class-guides&#34;&gt;http://www.icy-veins.com/wow/class-guides&lt;/a&gt; - A very reasonable starting off point for class guides, with the best guide available for some specs. The Icy-Veins forums also have bits of useful discussion. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mmo-champion.com/&#34;&gt;http://www.mmo-champion.com/&lt;/a&gt;: This site, like wowhead, has periodic updates about wow, as well has having very well-trafficked &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mmo-champion.com/forums/247-Class-Discussions&#34;&gt;forums&lt;/a&gt;, which have the best theorycrafting available for some classes. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/wow/&#34;&gt;http://www.reddit.com/r/wow/&lt;/a&gt;: This reddit subreddit is an official wow community site and has good, active discussion about wow. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/r/CompetitiveWoW/&#34;&gt;http://www.reddit.com/r/CompetitiveWoW/&lt;/a&gt;: This reddit subreddit is narrowly focused on high-level wow raiding. There are detailed guides, log analysis posts, and more. &lt;a href=&#34;http://simplearmory.com/&#34;&gt;http://simplearmory.com/&lt;/a&gt;: This website allows an alternative view of the wow armory. The collectibles, mounts section links to a good guide for mount farming and tells what you missed at a glance. &lt;a href=&#34;http://bossblueprint.com/wow&#34;&gt;http://bossblueprint.com/wow&lt;/a&gt;: This website is a great way to quickly outline raid positioning strategies for HFC.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Legion Prepatch Looms</title>
			<link>www.raidadvice.com/legion-prepatch-looms/</link>
			<pubDate>Sun, 17 Jul 2016 23:36:51 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">www.raidadvice.com/legion-prepatch-looms/</guid>
			<description>&lt;p&gt;Hello and welcome back to RaidAdvice. Who&amp;rsquo;s excited for the Legion prepatch (&lt;a href=&#34;http://us.battle.net/wow/en/blog/20176410/the-legion-pre-expansion-patch-arrives-july-19-7-15-2016&#34;&gt;coming in a few days on July 19, 2016&lt;/a&gt;)? Guide availability for the prepatch is spotty right now, and several writers are waiting to release guides until the patch drops. Check back in a week or two for my first-draft list of prepatch class guides. Before Legion hits, there&amp;rsquo;s a few raid-oriented posts I intend to release, so be on the lookout for those as well! For now, there&amp;rsquo;s a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/CompetitiveWoW/comments/4t1wqx/class_guides_for_patch_70/&#34;&gt;reddit thread&lt;/a&gt; with information on several guides, and some class websites (links available from the &lt;a href=&#34;http://raidadvice.com/class-guides-tier-18/&#34;&gt;Class Guides Tier 18 page&lt;/a&gt;) have forums where folks are starting to theorycraft. Class discord channels and IRC have some good guides forming/promised as well. If you know of a good guide, feel free to leave a comment here, or contact me directly (my contact information is available in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://raidadvice.com/about/&#34;&gt;about page&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Generally Useful Websites Tier 18</title>
			<link>www.raidadvice.com/generally-useful-websites-tier-18/</link>
			<pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2016 23:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">www.raidadvice.com/generally-useful-websites-tier-18/</guid>
			<description>&lt;p&gt;This is a quick post on useful websites that do not easily fit into the &amp;ldquo;guides&amp;rdquo; pages. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/&#34;&gt;http://www.wowhead.com/&lt;/a&gt;: Wowhead maintains news, guides, and a searchable database of every item in the game. If you have a question about something in wow, this is a great first place to look. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mmo-champion.com/&#34;&gt;http://www.mmo-champion.com/&lt;/a&gt;: This site has periodic updates about wow, as well has having very well-trafficked forums. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/wow/&#34;&gt;http://www.reddit.com/r/wow/&lt;/a&gt;: This reddit subreddit is an official wow community site and has good, active discussion about wow. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/r/CompetitiveWoW/&#34;&gt;http://www.reddit.com/r/CompetitiveWoW/&lt;/a&gt;: This reddit subreddit is narrowly focused on high-level wow raiding. There are detailed guides, log analysis posts, and more. &lt;a href=&#34;http://simplearmory.com/&#34;&gt;http://simplearmory.com/&lt;/a&gt;: This website allows an alternative view of the wow armory. The collectibles, mounts section links to a good guide for mount farming and tells what you missed at a glance.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Other Class Guide Compilations for Tier 18</title>
			<link>www.raidadvice.com/other-class-guide-compilations-for-tier-18/</link>
			<pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2016 02:48:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">www.raidadvice.com/other-class-guide-compilations-for-tier-18/</guid>
			<description>&lt;p&gt;This site was started due to dissatisfaction with other guide compilations, which generally seek to host proprietary guides for all classes on one site. Some of these websites are good jumping off points, but, in general, they suffer from being out of date or inaccurate for at least some of the guides. That being said, the best are listed below. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.icy-veins.com/wow/class-guides&#34;&gt;http://www.icy-veins.com/wow/class-guides&lt;/a&gt; - A very reasonable starting off point for people new to raiding. The Icy-Veins forums also have bits of useful discussion. &lt;a href=&#34;http://onuraslan.github.io/SummonStoneMirror/summonstone.com/&#34;&gt;http://onuraslan.github.io/SummonStoneMirror/summonstone.com/&lt;/a&gt; - A mirror of the now defunct SummonStone website. This project had promise, but was closed by its creator, Skullflower, a notable Death Knight theorycrafter and raider, when he took a job working for Blizzard. Nice guide format, a better jumping off point for some classes than Icy-Veins. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mmo-champion.com/forums/247-Class-Discussions&#34;&gt;http://www.mmo-champion.com/forums/247-Class-Discussions&lt;/a&gt; - The MMO-Champion class forums have the best theorycrafting available for some classes. Other class forums may be inactive or, worse, have inaccurate information.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
